[
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's mercy on israel"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Paul stressed what and why?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:13]\tI am saying all this especially for you Gentiles. God has appointed me as the apostle to the Gentiles. I stress this,\n\t[R 11:14]\tfor I want somehow to make the people of Israel jealous of what you Gentiles have, so I might save some of them.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of the section titled, \"God's Mercy on Israel\". \nPaul stressed what and why?\n\t[R 11:13]\tI am saying all this especially for you Gentiles. God has appointed me as the apostle to the Gentiles. I stress this,\n\t[R 11:14]\tfor I want somehow to make the people of Israel jealous of what you Gentiles have, so I might save some of them.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            8
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Which parenthetical statements are contained?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:9]\t(And remember that those who do not have the Spirit of Christ living in them do not belong to him at all.)\n\t[R 8:24-25]\t(If we already have something, we don't need to hope for it. But if we look forward to something we don't yet have, we must wait patiently and confidently.)\n\t[R 8:36]\t(As the Scriptures say, \"For your sake we are killed every day; we are being slaughtered like sheep.\")\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 30 points. 3-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 8. \nWhich parenthetical statements are contained?\n\t[R 8:9]\t(And remember that those who do not have the Spirit of Christ living in them do not belong to him at all.)\n\t[R 8:24-25]\t(If we already have something, we don't need to hope for it. But if we look forward to something we don't yet have, we must wait patiently and confidently.)\n\t[R 8:36]\t(As the Scriptures say, \"For your sake we are killed every day; we are being slaughtered like sheep.\")\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "love fulfills god's requirements"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What does no wrong to whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 13:10]\tLove does no wrong to others, so love fulfills the requirements of God's law.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 10 points. 2-Part question. From the section titled, \"Love Fulfills God's Requirements\". \nWhat does no wrong to whom?\n\t[R 13:10]\tLove does no wrong to others, so love fulfills the requirements of God's law.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 7
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "drawing close to god"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Let there be what instead of what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 4:9]\tLet there be tears for what you have done. Let there be sorrow and deep grief. Let there be sadness instead of laughter, and gloom instead of joy.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 20 points. 2-Part question. 7-Part answer. From the section titled, \"Drawing Close to God\". \nLet there be what instead of what?\n\t[J 4:9]\tLet there be tears for what you have done. Let there be sorrow and deep grief. Let there be sadness instead of laughter, and gloom instead of joy.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "warning against judging others"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Your job is to obey what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 4:11]\tDon't speak evil against each other, dear brothers and sisters. If you criticize and judge each other, then you are criticizing and judging God's law. But your job is to obey the law, not to judge whether it applies to you.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 10 points. From the section titled, \"Warning against Judging Others\". \nYour job is to obey what?\n\t[J 4:11]\tDon't speak evil against each other, dear brothers and sisters. If you criticize and judge each other, then you are criticizing and judging God's law. But your job is to obey the law, not to judge whether it applies to you.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            8
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of God...?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:9]\tSpirit\n\t[R 8:14]\tchildren\n\t[R 8:39]\tlove\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 20 points. Scripture text question. 3-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 8. \nHow does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of God...?\"\n\t[R 8:9]\tSpirit\n\t[R 8:14]\tchildren\n\t[R 8:39]\tlove\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            16
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The 8th verse names which individual?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:8]\tAmpliatus\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 10 points. Chapter analysis answer. From Romans chapter 16. \nThe 8th verse names which individual?\n\t[R 16:8]\tAmpliatus\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            1,
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Loyalty is mentioned in three verses. Give in essence these verses.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 1:6]\tBut when you ask him, be sure that your faith is in God alone. Do not waver, for a person with divided loyalty is as unsettled as a wave of the sea that is blown and tossed by the wind.\n\t[J 1:8]\tTheir loyalty is divided between God and the world, and they are unstable in everything they do.\n\t[J 4:8]\tCome close to God, and God will come close to you. Wash your hands, you sinners; purify your hearts, for your loyalty is divided between God and the world.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 30 points. Statement and essence question. 3-Part answer. From separate verses of James chapters 1 and 4. \nLoyalty is mentioned in three verses. Give in essence these verses.\n\t[J 1:6]\tBut when you ask him, be sure that your faith is in God alone. Do not waver, for a person with divided loyalty is as unsettled as a wave of the sea that is blown and tossed by the wind.\n\t[J 1:8]\tTheir loyalty is divided between God and the world, and they are unstable in everything they do.\n\t[J 4:8]\tCome close to God, and God will come close to you. Wash your hands, you sinners; purify your hearts, for your loyalty is divided between God and the world.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            13
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The possessive word God's is used to describe what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 13:4]\tservants\n\t[R 13:8]\tlaw\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 20 points. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 13. \nThe possessive word God's is used to describe what?\n\t[R 13:4]\tservants\n\t[R 13:8]\tlaw\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            11
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What were hardened?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:7]\tSo this is the situation: Most of the people of Israel have not found the favor of God they are looking for so earnestly. A few have- the ones God has chosen- but the hearts of the rest were hardened.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 11. \nWhat were hardened?\n\t[R 11:7]\tSo this is the situation: Most of the people of Israel have not found the favor of God they are looking for so earnestly. A few have- the ones God has chosen- but the hearts of the rest were hardened.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            1,
            13
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Night is mentioned in two verses. Give in essence these verses.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:9]\tGod knows how often I pray for you. Day and night I bring you and your needs in prayer to God, whom I serve with all my heart by spreading the Good News about his Son.\n\t[R 13:12]\tThe night is almost gone; the day of salvation will soon be here. So remove your dark deeds like dirty clothes, and put on the shining armor of right living.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. Statement and essence question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 1 and 13. \nNight is mentioned in two verses. Give in essence these verses.\n\t[R 1:9]\tGod knows how often I pray for you. Day and night I bring you and your needs in prayer to God, whom I serve with all my heart by spreading the Good News about his Son.\n\t[R 13:12]\tThe night is almost gone; the day of salvation will soon be here. So remove your dark deeds like dirty clothes, and put on the shining armor of right living.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            8
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Despite what is overwhelming victory ours?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:37]\tNo, despite all these things, overwhelming victory is ours through Christ, who loved us.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 8.\nDespite what is overwhelming victory ours?\n\t[R 8:37]\tNo, despite all these things, overwhelming victory is ours through Christ, who loved us.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 7
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's selection of israel"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Which questions are contained?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:6]\tWell then, has God failed to fulfill his promise to Israel?\n\t[R 9:14]\tAre we saying, then, that God was unfair?\n\t[R 9:19]\t\"Why does God blame people for not responding?\n\t[R 9:19]\tHaven't they simply done what he makes them do?\"\n\t[R 9:20]\tWho are you, a mere human being, to argue with God?\n\t[R 9:20]\tShould the thing that was created say to the one who created it, \"Why have you made me like this?\"\n\t[R 9:21]\tWhen a potter makes jars out of clay, doesn't he have a right to use the same lump of clay to make one jar for decoration and another to throw garbage into?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 30 points. 7-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of the section titled, \"God's Selection of Israel\". \nWhich questions are contained?\n\t[R 9:6]\tWell then, has God failed to fulfill his promise to Israel?\n\t[R 9:14]\tAre we saying, then, that God was unfair?\n\t[R 9:19]\t\"Why does God blame people for not responding?\n\t[R 9:19]\tHaven't they simply done what he makes them do?\"\n\t[R 9:20]\tWho are you, a mere human being, to argue with God?\n\t[R 9:20]\tShould the thing that was created say to the one who created it, \"Why have you made me like this?\"\n\t[R 9:21]\tWhen a potter makes jars out of clay, doesn't he have a right to use the same lump of clay to make one jar for decoration and another to throw garbage into?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote the closing two verses.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:25]\tRahab the prostitute is another example. She was shown to be right with God by her actions when she hid those messengers and sent them safely away by a different road.\n\t[J 2:26]\tJust as the body is dead without breath, so also faith is dead without good works.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 20 points. Quotation question. From 2 consecutive verses of James chapter 2. \nQuote the closing two verses.\n\t[J 2:25]\tRahab the prostitute is another example. She was shown to be right with God by her actions when she hid those messengers and sent them safely away by a different road.\n\t[J 2:26]\tJust as the body is dead without breath, so also faith is dead without good works.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "paul greets his friends"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who was a co-worker in whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:9]\tGreet Urbanus, our co-worker in Christ, and my dear friend Stachys.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 10 points. 2-Part question. From the section titled, \"Paul Greets His Friends\". \nWho was a co-worker in whom?\n\t[R 16:9]\tGreet Urbanus, our co-worker in Christ, and my dear friend Stachys.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "paul's travel plans"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who eagerly did what and why?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:26]\tFor you see, the believers in Macedonia and Achaia have eagerly taken up an offering for the poor among the believers in Jerusalem.\n\t[R 15:27]\tThey were glad to do this because they feel they owe a real debt to them. Since the Gentiles received the spiritual blessings of the Good News from the believers in Jerusalem, they feel the least they can do in return is to help them financially.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 20 points. 3-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of the section titled, \"Paul's Travel Plans\". \nWho eagerly did what and why?\n\t[R 15:26]\tFor you see, the believers in Macedonia and Achaia have eagerly taken up an offering for the poor among the believers in Jerusalem.\n\t[R 15:27]\tThey were glad to do this because they feel they owe a real debt to them. Since the Gentiles received the spiritual blessings of the Good News from the believers in Jerusalem, they feel the least they can do in return is to help them financially.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's selection of israel"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "God will show mercy to whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:15]\tFor God said to Moses, \"I will show mercy to anyone I choose, and I will show compassion to anyone I choose.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"God's Selection of Israel\". \nGod will show mercy to whom?\n\t[R 9:15]\tFor God said to Moses, \"I will show mercy to anyone I choose, and I will show compassion to anyone I choose.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 6
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "Romans chapter 11 names which individuals?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:1]\tAbraham\n\t[R 11:1]\tBenjamin\n\t[R 11:2]\tElijah\n\t[R 11:9]\tDavid\n\t[R 11:28]\tIsaac\n\t[R 11:28]\tJacob\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 20 points. 6-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses. \nRomans chapter 11 names which individuals?\n\t[R 11:1]\tAbraham\n\t[R 11:1]\tBenjamin\n\t[R 11:2]\tElijah\n\t[R 11:9]\tDavid\n\t[R 11:28]\tIsaac\n\t[R 11:28]\tJacob\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence verse 29 from the 11th chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:29]\tFor God's gifts and his call can never be withdrawn.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 10 points. Essence question. From Romans. \nGive in essence verse 29 from the 11th chapter.\n\t[R 11:29]\tFor God's gifts and his call can never be withdrawn.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's good news"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The Good News tells us what, how?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:17]\tThis Good News tells us how God makes us right in his sight. This is accomplished from start to finish by faith. As the Scriptures say, \"It is through faith that a righteous person has life.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"God's Good News\". \nThe Good News tells us what, how?\n\t[R 1:17]\tThis Good News tells us how God makes us right in his sight. This is accomplished from start to finish by faith. As the Scriptures say, \"It is through faith that a righteous person has life.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            15
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The 24th verse names which geographical locations?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:24]\tSpain\n\t[R 15:24]\tRome\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. 2-part Chapter analysis answer. From Romans chapter 15. \nThe 24th verse names which geographical locations?\n\t[R 15:24]\tSpain\n\t[R 15:24]\tRome\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            10
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Three Old testament questions are contained. Give them.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 10:6]\t'Who will go up to heaven?'\n\t[R 10:7]\t'Who will go down to the place of the dead?'\n\t[R 10:16]\t\"LORD, who has believed our message?\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. Statement and question. 3-Part chapter analysis answer. From Romans chapter 10. \nThree Old testament questions are contained. Give them.\n\t[R 10:6]\t'Who will go up to heaven?'\n\t[R 10:7]\t'Who will go down to the place of the dead?'\n\t[R 10:16]\t\"LORD, who has believed our message?\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give the exclamations that say God is, quote, \"worthy of eternal praise?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:25]\tSo they worshiped and served the things God created instead of the Creator himself, who is worthy of eternal praise!\n\t[R 9:5]\tAnd he is God, the one who rules over everything and is worthy of eternal praise!\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. Scripture text question. 2-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of Romans. \nGive the exclamations that say God is, quote, \"worthy of eternal praise?\"\n\t[R 1:25]\tSo they worshiped and served the things God created instead of the Creator himself, who is worthy of eternal praise!\n\t[R 9:5]\tAnd he is God, the one who rules over everything and is worthy of eternal praise!\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "a warning against prejudice"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Under what condition will God, quote, \"be merciful when he judges you?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:13]\tThere will be no mercy for those who have not shown mercy to others. But if you have been merciful, God will be merciful when he judges you.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"A Warning against Prejudice\". \nUnder what condition will God, quote, \"be merciful when he judges you?\"\n\t[J 2:13]\tThere will be no mercy for those who have not shown mercy to others. But if you have been merciful, God will be merciful when he judges you.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            1,
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Parents are mentioned in two verses. Give in essence these verses.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:30]\tThey are backstabbers, haters of God, insolent, proud, and boastful. They invent new ways of sinning, and they disobey their parents.\n\t[R 2:28]\tFor you are not a true Jew just because you were born of Jewish parents or because you have gone through the ceremony of circumcision.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 20 points. Statement and essence question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 1 and 2. \nParents are mentioned in two verses. Give in essence these verses.\n\t[R 1:30]\tThey are backstabbers, haters of God, insolent, proud, and boastful. They invent new ways of sinning, and they disobey their parents.\n\t[R 2:28]\tFor you are not a true Jew just because you were born of Jewish parents or because you have gone through the ceremony of circumcision.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            15
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What say, quote, \"The insults of those who insult you, O God, have fallen on me.\"?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:3]\tFor even Christ didn't live to please himself. As the Scriptures say, \"The insults of those who insult you, O God, have fallen on me.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 10 points. Scripture text question. From Romans chapter 15. \nWhat say, quote, \"The insults of those who insult you, O God, have fallen on me.\"?\n\t[R 15:3]\tFor even Christ didn't live to please himself. As the Scriptures say, \"The insults of those who insult you, O God, have fallen on me.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "faith without good deeds is dead"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "According to the closing verse, what is dead?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:26]\tJust as the body is dead without breath, so also faith is dead without good works.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 20 points. Give 2 complete answers. From the section titled, \"Faith without Good Deeds Is Dead\". \nAccording to the closing verse, what is dead?\n\t[J 2:26]\tJust as the body is dead without breath, so also faith is dead without good works.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "drawing close to god"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Humble yourselves before whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 4:7]\tSo humble yourselves before God. Resist the devil, and he will flee from you.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 10 points. From the section titled, \"Drawing Close to God\". \nHumble yourselves before whom?\n\t[J 4:7]\tSo humble yourselves before God. Resist the devil, and he will flee from you.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "QuotationCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            8
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish this verse and the two that follow, quote, \"Against its will,... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:20]\tAgainst its will, all creation was subjected to God's curse. But with eager hope,\n\t[R 8:21]\tthe creation looks forward to the day when it will join God's children in glorious freedom from death and decay.\n\t[R 8:22]\tFor we know that all creation has been groaning as in the pains of childbirth right up to the present time.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 30 points. Quotation completion question. From Romans chapter 8. \nFinish this verse and the two that follow, quote, \"Against its will,... \"\n\t[R 8:20]\tAgainst its will, all creation was subjected to God's curse. But with eager hope,\n\t[R 8:21]\tthe creation looks forward to the day when it will join God's children in glorious freedom from death and decay.\n\t[R 8:22]\tFor we know that all creation has been groaning as in the pains of childbirth right up to the present time.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            7
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The possessive word God's is used to describe what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 7:13]\tgood commands\n\t[R 7:22]\tlaw\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 20 points. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 7. \nThe possessive word God's is used to describe what?\n\t[R 7:13]\tgood commands\n\t[R 7:22]\tlaw\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "living to please others"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Scriptures give us what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:4]\tSuch things were written in the Scriptures long ago to teach us. And the Scriptures give us hope and encouragement as we wait patiently for God's promises to be fulfilled.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 10 points. 2-Part answer. From the section titled, \"Living to Please Others\". \nScriptures give us what?\n\t[R 15:4]\tSuch things were written in the Scriptures long ago to teach us. And the Scriptures give us hope and encouragement as we wait patiently for God's promises to be fulfilled.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            13
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "About days, what did Paul say?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 13:12]\tThe night is almost gone; the day of salvation will soon be here. So remove your dark deeds like dirty clothes, and put on the shining armor of right living.\n\t[R 13:13]\tBecause we belong to the day, we must live decent lives for all to see. Don't participate in the darkness of wild parties and drunkenness, or in sexual promiscuity and immoral living, or in quarreling and jealousy.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 20 points. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 13. \nAbout days, what did Paul say?\n\t[R 13:12]\tThe night is almost gone; the day of salvation will soon be here. So remove your dark deeds like dirty clothes, and put on the shining armor of right living.\n\t[R 13:13]\tBecause we belong to the day, we must live decent lives for all to see. Don't participate in the darkness of wild parties and drunkenness, or in sexual promiscuity and immoral living, or in quarreling and jealousy.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            14
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Don't tear apart what over what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:20]\tDon't tear apart the work of God over what you eat. Remember, all foods are acceptable, but it is wrong to eat something if it makes another person stumble.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 10 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 14. \nDon't tear apart what over what?\n\t[R 14:20]\tDon't tear apart the work of God over what you eat. Remember, all foods are acceptable, but it is wrong to eat something if it makes another person stumble.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "The unique word snake is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:13]\t\"Their talk is foul, like the stench from an open grave. Their tongues are filled with lies.\" \"Snake venom drips from their lips.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. Statement and 2-Part essence question. \nThe unique word snake is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n\t[R 3:13]\t\"Their talk is foul, like the stench from an open grave. Their tongues are filled with lies.\" \"Snake venom drips from their lips.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "adam and christ contrasted"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "About God's wonderful grace, what did Paul say?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 5:20]\tGod's law was given so that all people could see how sinful they were. But as people sinned more and more, God's wonderful grace became more abundant.\n\t[R 5:21]\tSo just as sin ruled over all people and brought them to death, now God's wonderful grace rules instead, giving us right standing with God and resulting in eternal life through Jesus Christ our Lord.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 20 points. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of the section titled, \"Adam and Christ Contrasted\". \nAbout God's wonderful grace, what did Paul say?\n\t[R 5:20]\tGod's law was given so that all people could see how sinful they were. But as people sinned more and more, God's wonderful grace became more abundant.\n\t[R 5:21]\tSo just as sin ruled over all people and brought them to death, now God's wonderful grace rules instead, giving us right standing with God and resulting in eternal life through Jesus Christ our Lord.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 4
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Four Old Testament Scriptures are contained. Give them.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:3]\t\"Abraham believed God, and God counted him as righteous because of his faith.\"\n\t[R 4:7-8]\t\"Oh, what joy for those whose disobedience is forgiven, whose sins are put out of sight. Yes, what joy for those whose record the LORD has cleared of sin.\"\n\t[R 4:17]\t\"I have made you the father of many nations.\"\n\t[R 4:18]\t\"That's how many descendants you will have!\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 30 points. Statement and question. 4-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 4. \nFour Old Testament Scriptures are contained. Give them.\n\t[R 4:3]\t\"Abraham believed God, and God counted him as righteous because of his faith.\"\n\t[R 4:7-8]\t\"Oh, what joy for those whose disobedience is forgiven, whose sins are put out of sight. Yes, what joy for those whose record the LORD has cleared of sin.\"\n\t[R 4:17]\t\"I have made you the father of many nations.\"\n\t[R 4:18]\t\"That's how many descendants you will have!\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            12
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "God's will is what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 12:2]\tDon't copy the behavior and customs of this world, but let God transform you into a new person by changing the way you think. Then you will learn to know God's will for you, which is good and pleasing and perfect.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 10 points. 3-Part answer. From Romans chapter 12. \nGod's will is what?\n\t[R 12:2]\tDon't copy the behavior and customs of this world, but let God transform you into a new person by changing the way you think. Then you will learn to know God's will for you, which is good and pleasing and perfect.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "EssenceCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish in essence this verse and the one that follows, quote, \"Humble yourselves before the Lord... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 4:10]\tHumble yourselves before the Lord, and he will lift you up in honor.\n\t[J 4:11]\tDon't speak evil against each other, dear brothers and sisters. If you criticize and judge each other, then you are criticizing and judging God's law. But your job is to obey the law, not to judge whether it applies to you.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 20 points. Essence completion question. From James chapter 4. \nFinish in essence this verse and the one that follows, quote, \"Humble yourselves before the Lord... \"\n\t[J 4:10]\tHumble yourselves before the Lord, and he will lift you up in honor.\n\t[J 4:11]\tDon't speak evil against each other, dear brothers and sisters. If you criticize and judge each other, then you are criticizing and judging God's law. But your job is to obey the law, not to judge whether it applies to you.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "In the 9th verse, how does James address his readers?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:9]\tbrothers and sisters\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From James chapter 5. \nIn the 9th verse, how does James address his readers?\n\t[J 5:9]\tbrothers and sisters\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        },
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            1
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence the verse in which Paul speaks of wavering and the verse in which James speaks of wavering.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:20]\tAbraham never wavered in believing God's promise. In fact, his faith grew stronger, and in this he brought glory to God.\n\t[J 1:6]\tBut when you ask him, be sure that your faith is in God alone. Do not waver, for a person with divided loyalty is as unsettled as a wave of the sea that is blown and tossed by the wind.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 20 points. 2-Part essence question. From separate verses of Romans chapter 4 and James chapter 1. \nGive in essence the verse in which Paul speaks of wavering and the verse in which James speaks of wavering.\n\t[R 4:20]\tAbraham never wavered in believing God's promise. In fact, his faith grew stronger, and in this he brought glory to God.\n\t[J 1:6]\tBut when you ask him, be sure that your faith is in God alone. Do not waver, for a person with divided loyalty is as unsettled as a wave of the sea that is blown and tossed by the wind.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 4
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How did James answer his question, quote, \" Do you think the Scriptures have no meaning?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 4:5]\tDo you think the Scriptures have no meaning? They say that God is passionate that the spirit he has placed within us should be faithful to him.\n\t[J 4:6]\tAnd he gives grace generously. As the Scriptures say, \"God opposes the proud but gives grace to the humble.\"\n\t[J 4:7]\tSo humble yourselves before God. Resist the devil, and he will flee from you.\n\t[J 4:8]\tCome close to God, and God will come close to you. Wash your hands, you sinners; purify your hearts, for your loyalty is divided between God and the world.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 30 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From 4 consecutive verses of James chapter 4. \nHow did James answer his question, quote, \" Do you think the Scriptures have no meaning?\"\n\t[J 4:5]\tDo you think the Scriptures have no meaning? They say that God is passionate that the spirit he has placed within us should be faithful to him.\n\t[J 4:6]\tAnd he gives grace generously. As the Scriptures say, \"God opposes the proud but gives grace to the humble.\"\n\t[J 4:7]\tSo humble yourselves before God. Resist the devil, and he will flee from you.\n\t[J 4:8]\tCome close to God, and God will come close to you. Wash your hands, you sinners; purify your hearts, for your loyalty is divided between God and the world.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "salvation is for everyone"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What happened in the, quote, \"time of Moses\"?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 10:19]\tBut I ask, did the people of Israel really understand? Yes, they did, for even in the time of Moses, God said, \"I will rouse your jealousy through people who are not even a nation. I will provoke your anger through the foolish Gentiles.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 20 points. Scripture Text Question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Salvation Is for Everyone\". \nWhat happened in the, quote, \"time of Moses\"?\n\t[R 10:19]\tBut I ask, did the people of Israel really understand? Yes, they did, for even in the time of Moses, God said, \"I will rouse your jealousy through people who are not even a nation. I will provoke your anger through the foolish Gentiles.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            16
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Whose sister is mentioned?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:15]\tNereus\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 10 points. Chapter analysis answer. From Romans chapter 16. \nWhose sister is mentioned?\n\t[R 16:15]\tNereus\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "In the 19th verse, how does James address his readers?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:19]\tMy dear brothers and sisters\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. Give a complete answer. From James chapter 5. \nIn the 19th verse, how does James address his readers?\n\t[J 5:19]\tMy dear brothers and sisters\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            13
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who is rebelling against what God has instituted?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 13:2]\tSo anyone who rebels against authority is rebelling against what God has instituted, and they will be punished.\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 13. \nWho is rebelling against what God has instituted?\n\t[R 13:2]\tSo anyone who rebels against authority is rebelling against what God has instituted, and they will be punished.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 5
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "Disobedience is mentioned in which chapters?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t\tRomans 1, 4, 5, 10, and 11\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. 5-Part answer. \nDisobedience is mentioned in which chapters?\n\t\tRomans 1, 4, 5, 10, and 11\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "life in the spirit"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Letting the Spirit control your mind leads to what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:6]\tSo letting your sinful nature control your mind leads to death. But letting the Spirit control your mind leads to life and peace.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 10 points. 2-Part answer. From the section titled, \"Life in the Spirit\". \nLetting the Spirit control your mind leads to what?\n\t[R 8:6]\tSo letting your sinful nature control your mind leads to death. But letting the Spirit control your mind leads to life and peace.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            7,
            10
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The possessive word \"law's\" is used to describe what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 7:10]\tcommands\n\t[R 10:5]\tway of making a person right with God\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 20 points. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 7 and 10. \nThe possessive word \"law's\" is used to describe what?\n\t[R 7:10]\tcommands\n\t[R 10:5]\tway of making a person right with God\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's judgment of sin"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What did Paul say there will be for the, quote, \"Jew first and also for the Gentile\"?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 2:9]\tThere will be trouble and calamity for everyone who keeps on doing what is evil- for the Jew first and also for the Gentile.\n\t[R 2:10]\tBut there will be glory and honor and peace from God for all who do good- for the Jew first and also for the Gentile.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 20 points. Scripture text question. Give 2 complete answers. From 2 consecutive verses of the section titled, \"God's Judgment of Sin\". \nWhat did Paul say there will be for the, quote, \"Jew first and also for the Gentile\"?\n\t[R 2:9]\tThere will be trouble and calamity for everyone who keeps on doing what is evil- for the Jew first and also for the Gentile.\n\t[R 2:10]\tBut there will be glory and honor and peace from God for all who do good- for the Jew first and also for the Gentile.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "israel's unbelief"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Gentiles were not trying to follow what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:30]\tWhat does all this mean? Even though the Gentiles were not trying to follow God's standards, they were made right with God. And it was by faith that this took place.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Israel's Unbelief\". \nGentiles were not trying to follow what?\n\t[R 9:30]\tWhat does all this mean? Even though the Gentiles were not trying to follow God's standards, they were made right with God. And it was by faith that this took place.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 4
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote verses 15, 16, 17, and 18 from the 12th chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 12:15]\tBe happy with those who are happy, and weep with those who weep.\n\t[R 12:16]\tLive in harmony with each other. Don't be too proud to enjoy the company of ordinary people. And don't think you know it all!\n\t[R 12:17]\tNever pay back evil with more evil. Do things in such a way that everyone can see you are honorable.\n\t[R 12:18]\tDo all that you can to live in peace with everyone.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 30 points. Quotation question. From 4 consecutive verses of Romans. \nQuote verses 15, 16, 17, and 18 from the 12th chapter.\n\t[R 12:15]\tBe happy with those who are happy, and weep with those who weep.\n\t[R 12:16]\tLive in harmony with each other. Don't be too proud to enjoy the company of ordinary people. And don't think you know it all!\n\t[R 12:17]\tNever pay back evil with more evil. Do things in such a way that everyone can see you are honorable.\n\t[R 12:18]\tDo all that you can to live in peace with everyone.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What makes a, quote, \"huge ship turn?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:4]\tAnd a small rudder makes a huge ship turn wherever the pilot chooses to go, even though the winds are strong.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From James chapter 3. \nWhat makes a, quote, \"huge ship turn?\"\n\t[J 3:4]\tAnd a small rudder makes a huge ship turn wherever the pilot chooses to go, even though the winds are strong.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Rome is named in which chapters?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t\tRomans 1 and 15\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 20 points. 2-Part answer. From Romans. \nRome is named in which chapters?\n\t\tRomans 1 and 15\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            11
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Let their backs be bent for how long?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:10]\tLet their eyes go blind so they cannot see, and let their backs be bent forever.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 10 points. From Romans chapter 11. \nLet their backs be bent for how long?\n\t[R 11:10]\tLet their eyes go blind so they cannot see, and let their backs be bent forever.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "The unique word silver is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:3]\tYour gold and silver are corroded. The very wealth you were counting on will eat away your flesh like fire. This corroded treasure you have hoarded will testify against you on the day of judgment.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 20 points. Statement and 2-Part essence question. \nThe unique word silver is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n\t[J 5:3]\tYour gold and silver are corroded. The very wealth you were counting on will eat away your flesh like fire. This corroded treasure you have hoarded will testify against you on the day of judgment.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            11
          ],
          "Section": null
        },
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence the verse that mentions earnest looking and the verses that mention earnest prayer.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:7]\tSo this is the situation: Most of the people of Israel have not found the favor of God they are looking for so earnestly. A few have- the ones God has chosen- but the hearts of the rest were hardened.\n\t[J 5:16]\tConfess your sins to each other and pray for each other so that you may be healed. The earnest prayer of a righteous person has great power and produces wonderful results.\n\t[J 5:17]\tElijah was as human as we are, and yet when he prayed earnestly that no rain would fall, none fell for three and a half years!\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 30 points. 2-Part essence question. 3-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 11 and James chapter 5. \nGive in essence the verse that mentions earnest looking and the verses that mention earnest prayer.\n\t[R 11:7]\tSo this is the situation: Most of the people of Israel have not found the favor of God they are looking for so earnestly. A few have- the ones God has chosen- but the hearts of the rest were hardened.\n\t[J 5:16]\tConfess your sins to each other and pray for each other so that you may be healed. The earnest prayer of a righteous person has great power and produces wonderful results.\n\t[J 5:17]\tElijah was as human as we are, and yet when he prayed earnestly that no rain would fall, none fell for three and a half years!\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "When God counted Abraham as righteous, what wasn't it for and what was it for?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:23]\tAnd when God counted him as righteous, it wasn't just for Abraham's benefit. It was recorded\n\t[R 4:24]\tfor our benefit, too, assuring us that God will also count us as righteous if we believe in him, the one who raised Jesus our Lord from the dead.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 4. \nWhen God counted Abraham as righteous, what wasn't it for and what was it for?\n\t[R 4:23]\tAnd when God counted him as righteous, it wasn't just for Abraham's benefit. It was recorded\n\t[R 4:24]\tfor our benefit, too, assuring us that God will also count us as righteous if we believe in him, the one who raised Jesus our Lord from the dead.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            1
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Humbly do what and why?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 1:21]\tSo get rid of all the filth and evil in your lives, and humbly accept the word God has planted in your hearts, for it has the power to save your souls.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From James chapter 1. \nHumbly do what and why?\n\t[J 1:21]\tSo get rid of all the filth and evil in your lives, and humbly accept the word God has planted in your hearts, for it has the power to save your souls.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's mercy on israel"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Which patriarch is named?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:16]\tAbraham\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 10 points. Chapter analysis answer. From the section titled, \"God's Mercy on Israel\". \nWhich patriarch is named?\n\t[R 11:16]\tAbraham\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "the danger of criticism"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Don't let what ruin whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:15]\tAnd if another believer is distressed by what you eat, you are not acting in love if you eat it. Don't let your eating ruin someone for whom Christ died.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 10 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"The Danger of Criticism\". \nDon't let what ruin whom?\n\t[R 14:15]\tAnd if another believer is distressed by what you eat, you are not acting in love if you eat it. Don't let your eating ruin someone for whom Christ died.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 4
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Four questions are contained. Give them.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:1]\tWhat did he discover about being made right with God?\n\t[R 4:9]\tNow, is this blessing only for the Jews, or is it also for uncircumcised Gentiles?\n\t[R 4:10]\tBut how did this happen?\n\t[R 4:10]\tWas he counted as righteous only after he was circumcised, or was it before he was circumcised?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 30 points. Statement and question. 4-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 4. \nFour questions are contained. Give them.\n\t[R 4:1]\tWhat did he discover about being made right with God?\n\t[R 4:9]\tNow, is this blessing only for the Jews, or is it also for uncircumcised Gentiles?\n\t[R 4:10]\tBut how did this happen?\n\t[R 4:10]\tWas he counted as righteous only after he was circumcised, or was it before he was circumcised?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            14
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "With the Lord's help, what will servants do?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:4]\tWho are you to condemn someone else's servants? Their own master will judge whether they stand or fall. And with the Lord's help, they will stand and receive his approval.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 10 points. 2-Part answer. From Romans chapter 14. \nWith the Lord's help, what will servants do?\n\t[R 14:4]\tWho are you to condemn someone else's servants? Their own master will judge whether they stand or fall. And with the Lord's help, they will stand and receive his approval.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote the verses in which Abraham is named.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:21]\tDon't you remember that our ancestor Abraham was shown to be right with God by his actions when he offered his son Isaac on the altar?\n\t[J 2:23]\tAnd so it happened just as the Scriptures say: \"Abraham believed God, and God counted him as righteous because of his faith.\" He was even called the friend of God.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 20 points. Quotation question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of James chapter 2. \nQuote the verses in which Abraham is named.\n\t[J 2:21]\tDon't you remember that our ancestor Abraham was shown to be right with God by his actions when he offered his son Isaac on the altar?\n\t[J 2:23]\tAnd so it happened just as the Scriptures say: \"Abraham believed God, and God counted him as righteous because of his faith.\" He was even called the friend of God.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "faith and endurance"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Like what will the rich, quote, \"fade away?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 1:10]\tAnd those who are rich should boast that God has humbled them. They will fade away like a little flower in the field.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Faith and Endurance\". \nLike what will the rich, quote, \"fade away?\"\n\t[J 1:10]\tAnd those who are rich should boast that God has humbled them. They will fade away like a little flower in the field.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            7
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "To which questions did Paul exclaim, quote, \"Of course not!\"?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 7:7]\tWell then, am I suggesting that the law of God is sinful?\n\t[R 7:13]\tDid the law, which is good, cause my death?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 20 points. Scripture text question. 2-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 7. \nTo which questions did Paul exclaim, quote, \"Of course not!\"?\n\t[R 7:7]\tWell then, am I suggesting that the law of God is sinful?\n\t[R 7:13]\tDid the law, which is good, cause my death?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence the verse that names Job and the verse that names Elijah.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:11]\tWe give great honor to those who endure under suffering. For instance, you know about Job, a man of great endurance. You can see how the Lord was kind to him at the end, for the Lord is full of tenderness and mercy.\n\t[J 5:17]\tElijah was as human as we are, and yet when he prayed earnestly that no rain would fall, none fell for three and a half years!\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 20 points. 2-Part essence question. From separate verses of James chapter 5. \nGive in essence the verse that names Job and the verse that names Elijah.\n\t[J 5:11]\tWe give great honor to those who endure under suffering. For instance, you know about Job, a man of great endurance. You can see how the Lord was kind to him at the end, for the Lord is full of tenderness and mercy.\n\t[J 5:17]\tElijah was as human as we are, and yet when he prayed earnestly that no rain would fall, none fell for three and a half years!\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who oppress you?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:6]\tBut you dishonor the poor! Isn't it the rich who oppress you and drag you into court?\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. From James chapter 2. \nWho oppress you?\n\t[J 2:6]\tBut you dishonor the poor! Isn't it the rich who oppress you and drag you into court?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "Romans chapter 2 contains which exclamation and which Old Testament Scriptures?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 2:1]\tYou may think you can condemn such people, but you are just as bad, and you have no excuse!\n\t[R 2:6]\tHe will judge everyone according to what they have done.\n\t[R 2:24]\t\"The Gentiles blaspheme the name of God because of you.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. 2-Part question. 3-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses. \nRomans chapter 2 contains which exclamation and which Old Testament Scriptures?\n\t[R 2:1]\tYou may think you can condemn such people, but you are just as bad, and you have no excuse!\n\t[R 2:6]\tHe will judge everyone according to what they have done.\n\t[R 2:24]\t\"The Gentiles blaspheme the name of God because of you.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote verses 11, 12, and 13.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 2:11]\tFor God does not show favoritism.\n\t[R 2:12]\tWhen the Gentiles sin, they will be destroyed, even though they never had God's written law. And the Jews, who do have God's law, will be judged by that law when they fail to obey it.\n\t[R 2:13]\tFor merely listening to the law doesn't make us right with God. It is obeying the law that makes us right in his sight.\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. Quotation question. From 3 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 2. \nQuote verses 11, 12, and 13.\n\t[R 2:11]\tFor God does not show favoritism.\n\t[R 2:12]\tWhen the Gentiles sin, they will be destroyed, even though they never had God's written law. And the Jews, who do have God's law, will be judged by that law when they fail to obey it.\n\t[R 2:13]\tFor merely listening to the law doesn't make us right with God. It is obeying the law that makes us right in his sight.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "life in the spirit"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "God adopted you as what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:15]\tSo you have not received a spirit that makes you fearful slaves. Instead, you received God's Spirit when he adopted you as his own children. Now we call him, \"Abba, Father.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Life in the Spirit\". \nGod adopted you as what?\n\t[R 8:15]\tSo you have not received a spirit that makes you fearful slaves. Instead, you received God's Spirit when he adopted you as his own children. Now we call him, \"Abba, Father.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            12
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The possessive word God's is used to describe what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 12:2]\twill\n\t[R 12:13]\tpeople\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 20 points. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 12. \nThe possessive word God's is used to describe what?\n\t[R 12:2]\twill\n\t[R 12:13]\tpeople\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "In the 11th verse, how does James address his readers?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 4:11]\tdear brothers and sisters\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From James chapter 4. \nIn the 11th verse, how does James address his readers?\n\t[J 4:11]\tdear brothers and sisters\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 7
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "Romans chapter 15 names which geographical locations?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:19]\tJerusalem\n\t[R 15:19]\tIllyricum\n\t[R 15:24]\tSpain\n\t[R 15:24]\tRome\n\t[R 15:26]\tMacedonia\n\t[R 15:26]\tAchaia\n\t[R 15:31]\tJudea\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 20 points. 7-part Chapter analysis answer. From separate verses. \nRomans chapter 15 names which geographical locations?\n\t[R 15:19]\tJerusalem\n\t[R 15:19]\tIllyricum\n\t[R 15:24]\tSpain\n\t[R 15:24]\tRome\n\t[R 15:26]\tMacedonia\n\t[R 15:26]\tAchaia\n\t[R 15:31]\tJudea\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What is emphasized?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:31]\tWell then, if we emphasize faith, does this mean that we can forget about the law? Of course not! \n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 10 points. From Romans chapter 3. \nWhat is emphasized?\n\t[R 3:31]\tWell then, if we emphasize faith, does this mean that we can forget about the law? Of course not! \n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            2,
            3,
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Three questions mention Gentiles. Give these questions.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 2:26]\tAnd if the Gentiles obey God's law, won't God declare them to be his own people?\n\t[R 3:29]\tIsn't he also the God of the Gentiles?\n\t[R 4:9]\tNow, is this blessing only for the Jews, or is it also for uncircumcised Gentiles?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 30 points. Statement and question. 3-Part Chapter Analysis answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 2, 3, and 4. \nThree questions mention Gentiles. Give these questions.\n\t[R 2:26]\tAnd if the Gentiles obey God's law, won't God declare them to be his own people?\n\t[R 3:29]\tIsn't he also the God of the Gentiles?\n\t[R 4:9]\tNow, is this blessing only for the Jews, or is it also for uncircumcised Gentiles?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "God demonstrated what and why?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:26]\tfor he was looking ahead and including them in what he would do in this present time. God did this to demonstrate his righteousness, for he himself is fair and just, and he makes sinners right in his sight when they believe in Jesus.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 3. \nGod demonstrated what and why?\n\t[R 3:26]\tfor he was looking ahead and including them in what he would do in this present time. God did this to demonstrate his righteousness, for he himself is fair and just, and he makes sinners right in his sight when they believe in Jesus.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "sin's power is broken"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Since we died with Christ, what do we know?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 6:8]\tAnd since we died with Christ, we know we will also live with him.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Sin's Power Is Broken\". \nSince we died with Christ, what do we know?\n\t[R 6:8]\tAnd since we died with Christ, we know we will also live with him.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Part",
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            14
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "A low-carb diet may consist of mostly vegetables and meat. Quote the verse that mentions vegetables and the verse that mentions meat.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:2]\tFor instance, one person believes it's all right to eat anything. But another believer with a sensitive conscience will eat only vegetables.\n\t[R 14:21]\tIt is better not to eat meat or drink wine or do anything else if it might cause another believer to stumble.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 20 points. Statement and 2-Part quotation question. From separate verses of Romans chapter 14. \nA low-carb diet may consist of mostly vegetables and meat. Quote the verse that mentions vegetables and the verse that mentions meat.\n\t[R 14:2]\tFor instance, one person believes it's all right to eat anything. But another believer with a sensitive conscience will eat only vegetables.\n\t[R 14:21]\tIt is better not to eat meat or drink wine or do anything else if it might cause another believer to stumble.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            11
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who complained?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:2]\tElijah\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 10 points. Chapter analysis answer. From Romans chapter 11. \nWho complained?\n\t[R 11:2]\tElijah\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        },
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence the two verses that refer to God with the four-word title, quote,  \"LORD of Heaven's Armies.\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:29]\tAnd Isaiah said the same thing in another place: \"If the LORD of Heaven's Armies had not spared a few of our children, we would have been wiped out like Sodom, destroyed like Gomorrah.\"\n\t[J 5:4]\tFor listen! Hear the cries of the field workers whom you have cheated of their pay. The cries of those who harvest your fields have reached the ears of the LORD of Heaven's Armies.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. Scripture text essence question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 9 and James chapter 5. \nGive in essence the two verses that refer to God with the four-word title, quote,  \"LORD of Heaven's Armies.\"\n\t[R 9:29]\tAnd Isaiah said the same thing in another place: \"If the LORD of Heaven's Armies had not spared a few of our children, we would have been wiped out like Sodom, destroyed like Gomorrah.\"\n\t[J 5:4]\tFor listen! Hear the cries of the field workers whom you have cheated of their pay. The cries of those who harvest your fields have reached the ears of the LORD of Heaven's Armies.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "QuotationCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish this verse and the two that follow, quote, \"Come close to God... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 4:8]\tCome close to God, and God will come close to you. Wash your hands, you sinners; purify your hearts, for your loyalty is divided between God and the world.\n\t[J 4:9]\tLet there be tears for what you have done. Let there be sorrow and deep grief. Let there be sadness instead of laughter, and gloom instead of joy.\n\t[J 4:10]\tHumble yourselves before the Lord, and he will lift you up in honor.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 30 points. Quotation completion question. From James. \nFinish this verse and the two that follow, quote, \"Come close to God... \"\n\t[J 4:8]\tCome close to God, and God will come close to you. Wash your hands, you sinners; purify your hearts, for your loyalty is divided between God and the world.\n\t[J 4:9]\tLet there be tears for what you have done. Let there be sorrow and deep grief. Let there be sadness instead of laughter, and gloom instead of joy.\n\t[J 4:10]\tHumble yourselves before the Lord, and he will lift you up in honor.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "The unique word stubborn is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 2:5]\tBut because you are stubborn and refuse to turn from your sin, you are storing up terrible punishment for yourself. For a day of anger is coming, when God's righteous judgment will be revealed.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 20 points. Statement and 2-Part essence question. \nThe unique word stubborn is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n\t[R 2:5]\tBut because you are stubborn and refuse to turn from your sin, you are storing up terrible punishment for yourself. For a day of anger is coming, when God's righteous judgment will be revealed.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "the danger of criticism"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What will each of us have to give, quote, \"to God?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:12]\tYes, each of us will give a personal account to God.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"The Danger of Criticism\". \nWhat will each of us have to give, quote, \"to God?\n\t[R 14:12]\tYes, each of us will give a personal account to God.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "a living sacrifice to god"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Be ready to do what and eager to do what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 12:13]\tWhen God's people are in need, be ready to help them. Always be eager to practice hospitality.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"A Living Sacrifice to God\". \nBe ready to do what and eager to do what?\n\t[R 12:13]\tWhen God's people are in need, be ready to help them. Always be eager to practice hospitality.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "Which province is named?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:5]\tAsia\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 10 points. Chapter analysis answer. \nWhich province is named?\n\t[R 16:5]\tAsia\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "Romans chapter 4 contains which exclamations?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:10]\tClearly, God accepted Abraham before he was circumcised!\n\t[R 4:15]\tThe only way to avoid breaking the law is to have no law to break!\n\t[R 4:18]\t\"That's how many descendants you will have!\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 20 points. 3-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses. \nRomans chapter 4 contains which exclamations?\n\t[R 4:10]\tClearly, God accepted Abraham before he was circumcised!\n\t[R 4:15]\tThe only way to avoid breaking the law is to have no law to break!\n\t[R 4:18]\t\"That's how many descendants you will have!\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            11
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How do verses 21, 22, and 23 describe God?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:21]\tFor if God did not spare the original branches, he won't spare you either.\n\t[R 11:22]\tNotice how God is both kind and severe. He is severe toward those who disobeyed, but kind to you if you continue to trust in his kindness. But if you stop trusting, you also will be cut off.\n\t[R 11:23]\tAnd if the people of Israel turn from their unbelief, they will be grafted in again, for God has the power to graft them back into the tree.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 30 points. 3-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 3 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 11. \nHow do verses 21, 22, and 23 describe God?\n\t[R 11:21]\tFor if God did not spare the original branches, he won't spare you either.\n\t[R 11:22]\tNotice how God is both kind and severe. He is severe toward those who disobeyed, but kind to you if you continue to trust in his kindness. But if you stop trusting, you also will be cut off.\n\t[R 11:23]\tAnd if the people of Israel turn from their unbelief, they will be grafted in again, for God has the power to graft them back into the tree.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence the closing section.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:19]\tMy dear brothers and sisters, if someone among you wanders away from the truth and is brought back,\n\t[J 5:20]\tyou can be sure that whoever brings the sinner back from wandering will save that person from death and bring about the forgiveness of many sins.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 20 points. Essence question. From 2 consecutive verses of James. \nGive in essence the closing section.\n\t[J 5:19]\tMy dear brothers and sisters, if someone among you wanders away from the truth and is brought back,\n\t[J 5:20]\tyou can be sure that whoever brings the sinner back from wandering will save that person from death and bring about the forgiveness of many sins.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            13
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Concerning neighbors, which Old Testament Scripture is contained?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 13:9]\t \"Love your neighbor as yourself.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 10 points. Chapter analysis answer. From Romans chapter 13. \nConcerning neighbors, which Old Testament Scripture is contained?\n\t[R 13:9]\t \"Love your neighbor as yourself.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "In the 12th verse, how does James address his readers?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:12]\tmy brothers and sisters\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. Give a complete answer. From James chapter 5. \nIn the 12th verse, how does James address his readers?\n\t[J 5:12]\tmy brothers and sisters\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            13
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The possessive word God's is used to describe what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 13:4]\tservants\n\t[R 13:8]\tlaw\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 13. \nThe possessive word God's is used to describe what?\n\t[R 13:4]\tservants\n\t[R 13:8]\tlaw\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            7,
            13
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The word \"covet\" is found in three verses. Give in essence these verses.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 7:7]\tWell then, am I suggesting that the law of God is sinful? Of course not! In fact, it was the law that showed me my sin. I would never have known that coveting is wrong if the law had not said, \"You must not covet.\"\n\t[R 7:9]\tAt one time I lived without understanding the law. But when I learned the command not to covet, for instance, the power of sin came to life,\n\t[R 13:9]\tFor the commandments say, \"You must not commit adultery. You must not murder. You must not steal. You must not covet.\" These- and other such commandments- are summed up in this one commandment: \"Love your neighbor as yourself.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. Statement and essence question. 3-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 7 and 13. \nThe word \"covet\" is found in three verses. Give in essence these verses.\n\t[R 7:7]\tWell then, am I suggesting that the law of God is sinful? Of course not! In fact, it was the law that showed me my sin. I would never have known that coveting is wrong if the law had not said, \"You must not covet.\"\n\t[R 7:9]\tAt one time I lived without understanding the law. But when I learned the command not to covet, for instance, the power of sin came to life,\n\t[R 13:9]\tFor the commandments say, \"You must not commit adultery. You must not murder. You must not steal. You must not covet.\" These- and other such commandments- are summed up in this one commandment: \"Love your neighbor as yourself.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "You have fattened yourselves for what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:5]\tYou have spent your years on earth in luxury, satisfying your every desire. You have fattened yourselves for the day of slaughter.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From James chapter 5. \nYou have fattened yourselves for what?\n\t[J 5:5]\tYou have spent your years on earth in luxury, satisfying your every desire. You have fattened yourselves for the day of slaughter.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Paul's heart was filled with what for whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:2]\tMy heart is filled with bitter sorrow and unending grief\n\t[R 9:3]\tfor my people, my Jewish brothers and sisters. I would be willing to be forever cursed- cut off from Christ!- if that would save them.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give 3 complete answers. From 2 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 9. \nPaul's heart was filled with what for whom?\n\t[R 9:2]\tMy heart is filled with bitter sorrow and unending grief\n\t[R 9:3]\tfor my people, my Jewish brothers and sisters. I would be willing to be forever cursed- cut off from Christ!- if that would save them.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            16
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Watch out for whom, why?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:17]\tAnd now I make one more appeal, my dear brothers and sisters. Watch out for people who cause divisions and upset people's faith by teaching things contrary to what you have been taught. Stay away from them.\n\t[R 16:18]\tSuch people are not serving Christ our Lord; they are serving their own personal interests. By smooth talk and glowing words they deceive innocent people.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 20 points. 2-part Question. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 16. \nWatch out for whom, why?\n\t[R 16:17]\tAnd now I make one more appeal, my dear brothers and sisters. Watch out for people who cause divisions and upset people's faith by teaching things contrary to what you have been taught. Stay away from them.\n\t[R 16:18]\tSuch people are not serving Christ our Lord; they are serving their own personal interests. By smooth talk and glowing words they deceive innocent people.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            8
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The word life-giving is used to describe whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:2]\tSpirit\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 10 points. From Romans chapter 8. \nThe word life-giving is used to describe whom?\n\t[R 8:2]\tSpirit\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "love fulfills god's requirements"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "About love, what did Paul say?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 13:8]\tOwe nothing to anyone- except for your obligation to love one another. If you love your neighbor, you will fulfill the requirements of God's law.\n\t[R 13:9]\tFor the commandments say, \"You must not commit adultery. You must not murder. You must not steal. You must not covet.\" These- and other such commandments- are summed up in this one commandment: \"Love your neighbor as yourself.\"\n\t[R 13:10]\tLove does no wrong to others, so love fulfills the requirements of God's law.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 30 points. Give a complete answer. From 3 consecutive verses of the section titled, \"Love Fulfills God's Requirements\". \nAbout love, what did Paul say?\n\t[R 13:8]\tOwe nothing to anyone- except for your obligation to love one another. If you love your neighbor, you will fulfill the requirements of God's law.\n\t[R 13:9]\tFor the commandments say, \"You must not commit adultery. You must not murder. You must not steal. You must not covet.\" These- and other such commandments- are summed up in this one commandment: \"Love your neighbor as yourself.\"\n\t[R 13:10]\tLove does no wrong to others, so love fulfills the requirements of God's law.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "living to please others"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who will rule over whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:12]\tAnd in another place Isaiah said, \"The heir to David's throne will come, and he will rule over the Gentiles. They will place their hope on him.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 10 points. 2-Part question. From the section titled, \"Living to Please Others\". \nWho will rule over whom?\n\t[R 15:12]\tAnd in another place Isaiah said, \"The heir to David's throne will come, and he will rule over the Gentiles. They will place their hope on him.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part",
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote the verse that mentions taming animals and the verse that mentions taming the tongue.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:7]\tPeople can tame all kinds of animals, birds, reptiles, and fish,\n\t[J 3:8]\tbut no one can tame the tongue. It is restless and evil, full of deadly poison.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 20 points. 2-Part quotation question. From 2 consecutive verses of James chapter 3. \nQuote the verse that mentions taming animals and the verse that mentions taming the tongue.\n\t[J 3:7]\tPeople can tame all kinds of animals, birds, reptiles, and fish,\n\t[J 3:8]\tbut no one can tame the tongue. It is restless and evil, full of deadly poison.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "the future glory"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The Holy Spirit helps us in what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:26]\tAnd the Holy Spirit helps us in our weakness. For example, we don't know what God wants us to pray for. But the Holy Spirit prays for us with groanings that cannot be expressed in words.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"The Future Glory\". \nThe Holy Spirit helps us in what?\n\t[R 8:26]\tAnd the Holy Spirit helps us in our weakness. For example, we don't know what God wants us to pray for. But the Holy Spirit prays for us with groanings that cannot be expressed in words.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "living to please others"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "May whom help you to do what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:5]\tMay God, who gives this patience and encouragement, help you live in complete harmony with each other, as is fitting for followers of Christ Jesus.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Living to Please Others\". \nMay whom help you to do what?\n\t[R 15:5]\tMay God, who gives this patience and encouragement, help you live in complete harmony with each other, as is fitting for followers of Christ Jesus.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            1
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Three verses say that God abandoned sinful men. Give in essence these verses.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:24]\tSo God abandoned them to do whatever shameful things their hearts desired. As a result, they did vile and degrading things with each other's bodies.\n\t[R 1:26]\tThat is why God abandoned them to their shameful desires. Even the wom en turned against the natural way to have sex and instead indulged in sex with each other.\n\t[R 1:28]\tSince they thought it foolish to acknowledge God, he abandoned them to their foolish thinking and let them do things that should never be done.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 30 points. Statement and essence question. 3-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 1. \nThree verses say that God abandoned sinful men. Give in essence these verses.\n\t[R 1:24]\tSo God abandoned them to do whatever shameful things their hearts desired. As a result, they did vile and degrading things with each other's bodies.\n\t[R 1:26]\tThat is why God abandoned them to their shameful desires. Even the wom en turned against the natural way to have sex and instead indulged in sex with each other.\n\t[R 1:28]\tSince they thought it foolish to acknowledge God, he abandoned them to their foolish thinking and let them do things that should never be done.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence verses 22, 23, and 24 from the 4th chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:22]\tAnd because of Abraham's faith, God counted him as righteous.\n\t[R 4:23]\tAnd when God counted him as righteous, it wasn't just for Abraham's benefit. It was recorded\n\t[R 4:24]\tfor our benefit, too, assuring us that God will also count us as righteous if we believe in him, the one who raised Jesus our Lord from the dead.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. Essence question. From 3 consecutive verses of Romans. \nGive in essence verses 22, 23, and 24 from the 4th chapter.\n\t[R 4:22]\tAnd because of Abraham's faith, God counted him as righteous.\n\t[R 4:23]\tAnd when God counted him as righteous, it wasn't just for Abraham's benefit. It was recorded\n\t[R 4:24]\tfor our benefit, too, assuring us that God will also count us as righteous if we believe in him, the one who raised Jesus our Lord from the dead.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "life in the spirit"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Why did God send his own Son in a, quote, \"body like the bodies we sinners have?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:3]\tThe law of Moses was unable to save us because of the weakness of our sinful nature. So God did what the law could not do. He sent his own Son in a body like the bodies we sinners have. And in that body God declared an end to sin's control over us by giving his Son as a sacrifice for our sins.\n\t[R 8:4]\tHe did this so that the just requirement of the law would be fully satisfied for us, who no longer follow our sinful nature but instead follow the Spirit.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 20 points. Scripture text question. Give 3 complete answers. From 2 consecutive verses of the section titled, \"Life in the Spirit\". \nWhy did God send his own Son in a, quote, \"body like the bodies we sinners have?\"\n\t[R 8:3]\tThe law of Moses was unable to save us because of the weakness of our sinful nature. So God did what the law could not do. He sent his own Son in a body like the bodies we sinners have. And in that body God declared an end to sin's control over us by giving his Son as a sacrifice for our sins.\n\t[R 8:4]\tHe did this so that the just requirement of the law would be fully satisfied for us, who no longer follow our sinful nature but instead follow the Spirit.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "paul's final instructions"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who will soon crush Satan, quote, \"under your feet?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:20]\tThe God of peace will soon crush Satan under your feet. \n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Paul's Final Instructions\". \nWho will soon crush Satan, quote, \"under your feet?\"\n\t[R 16:20]\tThe God of peace will soon crush Satan under your feet. \n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "sin's power is broken"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give yourselves completely to whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 6:13]\tDo not let any part of your body become an instrument of evil to serve sin. Instead, give yourselves completely to God, for you were dead, but now you have new life. \n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 10 points. From the section titled, \"Sin's Power Is Broken\". \nGive yourselves completely to whom?\n\t[R 6:13]\tDo not let any part of your body become an instrument of evil to serve sin. Instead, give yourselves completely to God, for you were dead, but now you have new life. \n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 6
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god remains faithful"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Which questions are contained?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:1]\tThen what's the advantage of being a Jew?\n\t[R 3:1]\tIs there any value in the ceremony of circumcision?\n\t[R 3:3]\tTrue, some of them were unfaithful; but just because they were unfaithful, does that mean God will be unfaithful?\n\t[R 3:5]\tIsn't it unfair, then, for him to punish us?\"\n\t[R 3:6]\tIf God were not entirely fair, how would he be qualified to judge the world?\n\t[R 3:7]\t\"But how can God condemn me as a sinner if my dishonesty highlights his truthfulness and brings him more glory?\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 30 points. 6-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of the section titled, \"God Remains Faithful\". \nWhich questions are contained?\n\t[R 3:1]\tThen what's the advantage of being a Jew?\n\t[R 3:1]\tIs there any value in the ceremony of circumcision?\n\t[R 3:3]\tTrue, some of them were unfaithful; but just because they were unfaithful, does that mean God will be unfaithful?\n\t[R 3:5]\tIsn't it unfair, then, for him to punish us?\"\n\t[R 3:6]\tIf God were not entirely fair, how would he be qualified to judge the world?\n\t[R 3:7]\t\"But how can God condemn me as a sinner if my dishonesty highlights his truthfulness and brings him more glory?\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's selection of israel"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Concerning whom did Isaiah cry out?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:27]\tIsrael\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 10 points. From the section titled, \"God's Selection of Israel\". \nConcerning whom did Isaiah cry out?\n\t[R 9:27]\tIsrael\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "James teaches about the tongue's duality by giving a two-verse illustration about fresh water. Give this illustration.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:11]\tDoes a spring of water bubble out with both fresh water and bitter water?\n\t[J 3:12]\tDoes a fig tree produce olives, or a grapevine produce figs? No, and you can't draw fresh water from a salty spring \n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 20 points. Statement and question. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of James chapter 3. \nJames teaches about the tongue's duality by giving a two-verse illustration about fresh water. Give this illustration.\n\t[J 3:11]\tDoes a spring of water bubble out with both fresh water and bitter water?\n\t[J 3:12]\tDoes a fig tree produce olives, or a grapevine produce figs? No, and you can't draw fresh water from a salty spring \n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Which ancestor is named?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:21]\tAbraham\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 10 points. Chapter analysis answer. From James chapter 2. \nWhich ancestor is named?\n\t[J 2:21]\tAbraham\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            8,
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "In advance, what happened?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:29]\tFor God knew his people in advance, and he chose them to become like his Son, so that his Son would be the firstborn among many brothers and sisters.\n\t[R 9:23]\tHe does this to make the riches of his glory shine even brighter on those to whom he shows mercy, who were prepared in advance for glory.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 20 points. Give 2 complete answers. From 2 separate verses of Romans chapters 8 and 9. \nIn advance, what happened?\n\t[R 8:29]\tFor God knew his people in advance, and he chose them to become like his Son, so that his Son would be the firstborn among many brothers and sisters.\n\t[R 9:23]\tHe does this to make the riches of his glory shine even brighter on those to whom he shows mercy, who were prepared in advance for glory.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What was restored by what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 5:10]\tFor since our friendship with God was restored by the death of his Son while we were still his enemies, we will certainly be saved through the life of his Son.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 5. \nWhat was restored by what?\n\t[R 5:10]\tFor since our friendship with God was restored by the death of his Son while we were still his enemies, we will certainly be saved through the life of his Son.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "faith without good deeds is dead"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Without what did James say the, quote, \"body is dead?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:26]\tJust as the body is dead without breath, so also faith is dead without good works.\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. Scripture text question. From the section titled, \"Faith without Good Deeds Is Dead\". \nWithout what did James say the, quote, \"body is dead?\"\n\t[J 2:26]\tJust as the body is dead without breath, so also faith is dead without good works.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "The unique word bubble is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:11]\tDoes a spring of water bubble out with both fresh water and bitter water?\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. Statement and 2-Part essence question. \nThe unique word bubble is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n\t[J 3:11]\tDoes a spring of water bubble out with both fresh water and bitter water?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        },
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Which exclamation names Abraham and which exclamation names Elijah?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:10]\tClearly, God accepted Abraham before he was circumcised!\n\t[J 5:17]\tElijah was as human as we are, and yet when he prayed earnestly that no rain would fall, none fell for three and a half years!\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. 2-Part question. Chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of Romans and James. \nWhich exclamation names Abraham and which exclamation names Elijah?\n\t[R 4:10]\tClearly, God accepted Abraham before he was circumcised!\n\t[J 5:17]\tElijah was as human as we are, and yet when he prayed earnestly that no rain would fall, none fell for three and a half years!\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            7
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The 24th verse contains which exclamation?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 7:24]\tOh, what a miserable person I am!\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 10 points. Chapter analysis answer. From Romans chapter 7. \nThe 24th verse contains which exclamation?\n\t[R 7:24]\tOh, what a miserable person I am!\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "The unique word urgent is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 13:11]\tThis is all the more urgent, for you know how late it is; time is running out. Wake up, for our salvation is nearer now than when we first believed.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 20 points. Statement and 2-Part essence question. \nThe unique word urgent is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n\t[R 13:11]\tThis is all the more urgent, for you know how late it is; time is running out. Wake up, for our salvation is nearer now than when we first believed.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How do verses 22, 23, and 24 describe God?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:22]\tIn the same way, even though God has the right to show his anger and his power, he is very patient with those on whom his anger falls, who are destined for destruction.\n\t[R 9:23]\tHe does this to make the riches of his glory shine even brighter on those to whom he shows mercy, who were prepared in advance for glory.\n\t[R 9:24]\tAnd we are among those whom he selected, both from the Jews and from the Gentiles.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 30 points. 3-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 3 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 9. \nHow do verses 22, 23, and 24 describe God?\n\t[R 9:22]\tIn the same way, even though God has the right to show his anger and his power, he is very patient with those on whom his anger falls, who are destined for destruction.\n\t[R 9:23]\tHe does this to make the riches of his glory shine even brighter on those to whom he shows mercy, who were prepared in advance for glory.\n\t[R 9:24]\tAnd we are among those whom he selected, both from the Jews and from the Gentiles.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            1
          ],
          "Section": null
        },
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            1
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What opportunity did Paul speak of and what opportunity did James speak of?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:10]\tOne of the things I always pray for is the opportunity, God willing, to come at last to see you.\n\t[J 1:2]\tDear brothers and sisters, when troubles of any kind come your way, consider it an opportunity for great joy.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 2 separate verses of Romans chapter 1 and James chapter 1. \nWhat opportunity did Paul speak of and what opportunity did James speak of?\n\t[R 1:10]\tOne of the things I always pray for is the opportunity, God willing, to come at last to see you.\n\t[J 1:2]\tDear brothers and sisters, when troubles of any kind come your way, consider it an opportunity for great joy.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "the danger of criticism"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Before eating, give thanks to whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:6]\tThose who worship the Lord on a special day do it to honor him. Those who eat any kind of food do so to honor the Lord, since they give thanks to God before eating. And those who refuse to eat certain foods also want to please the Lord and give thanks to God.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 10 points. From the section titled, \"The Danger of Criticism\". \nBefore eating, give thanks to whom?\n\t[R 14:6]\tThose who worship the Lord on a special day do it to honor him. Those who eat any kind of food do so to honor the Lord, since they give thanks to God before eating. And those who refuse to eat certain foods also want to please the Lord and give thanks to God.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 7
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "a living sacrifice to god"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "If your gift is prophesy, do what, if your gift is serving others, do what, if your gift is teaching, do what, if your gift is encouraging others, do what, if your gift is giving, do what, if your gift is leadership, do what and if your gift is showing kindness, do what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 12:6]\tIn his grace, God has given us different gifts for doing certain things well. So if God has given you the ability to prophesy, speak out with as much faith as God has given you.\n\t[R 12:7]\tIf your gift is serving others, serve them well. If you are a teacher, teach well.\n\t[R 12:8]\tIf your gift is to encourage others, be encouraging. If it is giving, give generously. If God has given you leadership ability, take the responsibility seriously. And if you have a gift for showing kindness to others, do it gladly.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 30 points. 7-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 3 consecutive verses of the section titled, \"A Living Sacrifice to God\". \nIf your gift is prophesy, do what, if your gift is serving others, do what, if your gift is teaching, do what, if your gift is encouraging others, do what, if your gift is giving, do what, if your gift is leadership, do what and if your gift is showing kindness, do what?\n\t[R 12:6]\tIn his grace, God has given us different gifts for doing certain things well. So if God has given you the ability to prophesy, speak out with as much faith as God has given you.\n\t[R 12:7]\tIf your gift is serving others, serve them well. If you are a teacher, teach well.\n\t[R 12:8]\tIf your gift is to encourage others, be encouraging. If it is giving, give generously. If God has given you leadership ability, take the responsibility seriously. And if you have a gift for showing kindness to others, do it gladly.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            4,
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Two verses name Sarah. Give in essence these verses.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:19]\tAnd Abraham's faith did not weaken, even though, at about 100 years of age, he figured his body was as good as dead- and so was Sarah's womb.\n\t[R 9:9]\tFor God had promised, \"I will return about this time next year, and Sarah will have a son.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 20 points. Statement and essence question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 4 and 9. \nTwo verses name Sarah. Give in essence these verses.\n\t[R 4:19]\tAnd Abraham's faith did not weaken, even though, at about 100 years of age, he figured his body was as good as dead- and so was Sarah's womb.\n\t[R 9:9]\tFor God had promised, \"I will return about this time next year, and Sarah will have a son.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who was about 100 years of age?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:19]\tAbraham\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 10 points. Chapter analysis answer. From Romans chapter 4. \nWho was about 100 years of age?\n\t[R 4:19]\tAbraham\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part",
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "paul's travel plans"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Referring to the Romans, when and how did Paul want to be able to, quote, \"come to you?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:31]\tPray that I will be rescued from those in Judea who refuse to obey God. Pray also that the believers there will be willing to accept the donation I am taking to Jerusalem.\n\t[R 15:32]\tThen, by the will of God, I will be able to come to you with a joyful heart, and we will be an encouragement to each other.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 20 points. 2-Part scripture text question. Give 3 complete answers. From 2 consecutive verses of the section titled, \"Paul's Travel Plans\". \nReferring to the Romans, when and how did Paul want to be able to, quote, \"come to you?\"\n\t[R 15:31]\tPray that I will be rescued from those in Judea who refuse to obey God. Pray also that the believers there will be willing to accept the donation I am taking to Jerusalem.\n\t[R 15:32]\tThen, by the will of God, I will be able to come to you with a joyful heart, and we will be an encouragement to each other.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            14
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What harmony is mentioned?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:19]\tSo then, let us aim for harmony in the church and try to build each other up.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 14. \nWhat harmony is mentioned?\n\t[R 14:19]\tSo then, let us aim for harmony in the church and try to build each other up.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's selection of israel"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "To some, what does God choose to do, to others, what does he choose to do, and why?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:18]\tSo you see, God chooses to show mercy to some, and he chooses to harden the hearts of others so they refuse to listen.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. 3-Part question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"God's Selection of Israel\". \nTo some, what does God choose to do, to others, what does he choose to do, and why?\n\t[R 9:18]\tSo you see, God chooses to show mercy to some, and he chooses to harden the hearts of others so they refuse to listen.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 7
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "nothing can separate us from god's love"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Which questions are contained?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:31]\tWhat shall we say about such wonderful things as these?\n\t[R 8:31]\tIf God is for us, who can ever be against us?\n\t[R 8:32]\tSince he did not spare even his own Son but gave him up for us all, won't he also give us everything else?\n\t[R 8:33]\tWho dares accuse us whom God has chosen for his own?\n\t[R 8:34]\tWho then will condemn us?\n\t[R 8:35]\tCan anything ever separate us from Christ's love?\n\t[R 8:35]\tDoes it mean he no longer loves us if we have trouble or calamity, or are persecuted, or hungry, or destitute, or in danger, or threatened with death?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 30 points. 7-Part chapter analysis answer. From consecutive verses of the section titled, \"Nothing Can Separate Us from God's Love\". \nWhich questions are contained?\n\t[R 8:31]\tWhat shall we say about such wonderful things as these?\n\t[R 8:31]\tIf God is for us, who can ever be against us?\n\t[R 8:32]\tSince he did not spare even his own Son but gave him up for us all, won't he also give us everything else?\n\t[R 8:33]\tWho dares accuse us whom God has chosen for his own?\n\t[R 8:34]\tWho then will condemn us?\n\t[R 8:35]\tCan anything ever separate us from Christ's love?\n\t[R 8:35]\tDoes it mean he no longer loves us if we have trouble or calamity, or are persecuted, or hungry, or destitute, or in danger, or threatened with death?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's selection of israel"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who are not necessarily children of God?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:8]\tThis means that Abraham's physical descendants are not necessarily children of God. Only the children of the promise are considered to be Abraham's children.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"God's Selection of Israel\". \nWho are not necessarily children of God?\n\t[R 9:8]\tThis means that Abraham's physical descendants are not necessarily children of God. Only the children of the promise are considered to be Abraham's children.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "James exclaimed what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:6]\tBut you dishonor the poor!\n\t[J 2:19]\tGood for you!\n\t[J 2:20]\tHow foolish!\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 20 points. 3-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of James chapter 2. \nJames exclaimed what?\n\t[J 2:6]\tBut you dishonor the poor!\n\t[J 2:19]\tGood for you!\n\t[J 2:20]\tHow foolish!\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's mercy on israel"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who did not spare the, quote, \"original branches?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:21]\tFor if God did not spare the original branches, he won't spare you either.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 10 points. Scripture text question. From the section titled, \"God's Mercy on Israel\". \nWho did not spare the, quote, \"original branches?\"\n\t[R 11:21]\tFor if God did not spare the original branches, he won't spare you either.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "controlling the tongue"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who should not become what, and why?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:1]\tDear brothers and sisters, not many of you should become teachers in the church, for we who teach will be judged more strictly.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 20 points. 3-Part question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Controlling the Tongue\". \nWho should not become what, and why?\n\t[J 3:1]\tDear brothers and sisters, not many of you should become teachers in the church, for we who teach will be judged more strictly.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "warning against judging others"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "God alone has the power to do what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 4:12]\tGod alone, who gave the law, is the Judge. He alone has the power to save or to destroy. So what right do you have to judge your neighbor?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 10 points. 2-Part answer. From the section titled, \"Warning against Judging Others\". \nGod alone has the power to do what?\n\t[J 4:12]\tGod alone, who gave the law, is the Judge. He alone has the power to save or to destroy. So what right do you have to judge your neighbor?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What might be argued and what might be claimed?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:7]\t\"But how can God condemn me as a sinner if my dishonesty highlights his truthfulness and brings him more glory?\"\n\t[R 3:8]\t\"The more we sin, the better it is!\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Chapter analysis answer. From consecutive verses of Romans chapter 3. \nWhat might be argued and what might be claimed?\n\t[R 3:7]\t\"But how can God condemn me as a sinner if my dishonesty highlights his truthfulness and brings him more glory?\"\n\t[R 3:8]\t\"The more we sin, the better it is!\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "respect for authority"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who need to be paid?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 13:6]\tPay your taxes, too, for these same reasons. For government workers need to be paid. They are serving God in what they do.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Respect for Authority\". \nWho need to be paid?\n\t[R 13:6]\tPay your taxes, too, for these same reasons. For government workers need to be paid. They are serving God in what they do.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            11
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How did Paul answer his question, quote, \"I ask, then, has God rejected his own people, the nation of Israel?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:1]\tI ask, then, has God rejected his own people, the nation of Israel? Of course not! I myself am an Israelite, a descendant of Abraham and a member of the tribe of Benjamin.\n\t[R 11:2]\tNo, God has not rejected his own people, whom he chose from the very beginning. Do you realize what the Scriptures say about this? Elijah the prophet complained to God about the people of Israel and said,\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 20 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 11. \nHow did Paul answer his question, quote, \"I ask, then, has God rejected his own people, the nation of Israel?\"\n\t[R 11:1]\tI ask, then, has God rejected his own people, the nation of Israel? Of course not! I myself am an Israelite, a descendant of Abraham and a member of the tribe of Benjamin.\n\t[R 11:2]\tNo, God has not rejected his own people, whom he chose from the very beginning. Do you realize what the Scriptures say about this? Elijah the prophet complained to God about the people of Israel and said,\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "controlling the tongue"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who can tame the tongue?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:8]\tbut no one can tame the tongue. It is restless and evil, full of deadly poison.\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Controlling the Tongue\". \nWho can tame the tongue?\n\t[J 3:8]\tbut no one can tame the tongue. It is restless and evil, full of deadly poison.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            1
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of God...?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:4]\tSon\n\t[R 1:16]\tpower\n\t[R 1:30]\thaters\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. Scripture text question. 3-Part answer. From Romans chapter 1. \nHow does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of God...?\"\n\t[R 1:4]\tSon\n\t[R 1:16]\tpower\n\t[R 1:30]\thaters\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote the opening three verses.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:1]\tWith Christ as my witness, I speak with utter truthfulness. My conscience and the Holy Spirit confirm it.\n\t[R 9:2]\tMy heart is filled with bitter sorrow and unending grief\n\t[R 9:3]\tfor my people, my Jewish brothers and sisters. I would be willing to be forever cursed- cut off from Christ!- if that would save them.\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. Quotation question. 3-Part answer. From 3 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 9. \nQuote the opening three verses.\n\t[R 9:1]\tWith Christ as my witness, I speak with utter truthfulness. My conscience and the Holy Spirit confirm it.\n\t[R 9:2]\tMy heart is filled with bitter sorrow and unending grief\n\t[R 9:3]\tfor my people, my Jewish brothers and sisters. I would be willing to be forever cursed- cut off from Christ!- if that would save them.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            8
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Where is the sky and where is the earth?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:39]\tNo power in the sky above or in the earth below- indeed, nothing in all creation will ever be able to separate us from the love of God that is revealed in Christ Jesus our Lord.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 10 points. 2-Part question. From Romans chapter 8. \nWhere is the sky and where is the earth?\n\t[R 8:39]\tNo power in the sky above or in the earth below- indeed, nothing in all creation will ever be able to separate us from the love of God that is revealed in Christ Jesus our Lord.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote verses 1 and 2 from the closing chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:1]\tI commend to you our sister Phoebe, who is a deacon in the church in Cenchrea.\n\t[R 16:2]\tWelcome her in the Lord as one who is worthy of honor among God's people. Help her in whatever she needs, for she has been helpful to many, and especially to me.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 20 points. Quotation question. From 2 consecutive verses of Romans. \nQuote verses 1 and 2 from the closing chapter.\n\t[R 16:1]\tI commend to you our sister Phoebe, who is a deacon in the church in Cenchrea.\n\t[R 16:2]\tWelcome her in the Lord as one who is worthy of honor among God's people. Help her in whatever she needs, for she has been helpful to many, and especially to me.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "living to please others"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "We should help others do what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:2]\tWe should help others do what is right and build them up in the Lord.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Living to Please Others\". \nWe should help others do what?\n\t[R 15:2]\tWe should help others do what is right and build them up in the Lord.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "James lists two responsibilities of a church elder. What are they?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:14]\tAre any of you sick? You should call for the elders of the church to come and pray over you, anointing you with oil in the name of the Lord.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 20 points. Statement and question. Give 2 complete answers. From James chapter 5. \nJames lists two responsibilities of a church elder. What are they?\n\t[J 5:14]\tAre any of you sick? You should call for the elders of the church to come and pray over you, anointing you with oil in the name of the Lord.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "faith and endurance"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who is generous?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 1:5]\tIf you need wisdom, ask our generous God, and he will give it to you. He will not rebuke you for asking.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 10 points. From the section titled, \"Faith and Endurance\". \nWho is generous?\n\t[J 1:5]\tIf you need wisdom, ask our generous God, and he will give it to you. He will not rebuke you for asking.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "QuotationCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            13
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish this verse and the two that follow, quote, \"Love does no wrong to others,... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 13:10]\tLove does no wrong to others, so love fulfills the requirements of God's law.\n\t[R 13:11]\tThis is all the more urgent, for you know how late it is; time is running out. Wake up, for our salvation is nearer now than when we first believed.\n\t[R 13:12]\tThe night is almost gone; the day of salvation will soon be here. So remove your dark deeds like dirty clothes, and put on the shining armor of right living.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 30 points. Quotation completion question. From Romans chapter 13. \nFinish this verse and the two that follow, quote, \"Love does no wrong to others,... \"\n\t[R 13:10]\tLove does no wrong to others, so love fulfills the requirements of God's law.\n\t[R 13:11]\tThis is all the more urgent, for you know how late it is; time is running out. Wake up, for our salvation is nearer now than when we first believed.\n\t[R 13:12]\tThe night is almost gone; the day of salvation will soon be here. So remove your dark deeds like dirty clothes, and put on the shining armor of right living.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part",
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            9,
            11
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote the verse that mentions members of God's people and the verse that mentions members of the tribe of Benjamin.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:6]\tWell then, has God failed to fulfill his promise to Israel? No, for not all who are born into the nation of Israel are truly members of God's people!\n\t[R 11:1]\tI ask, then, has God rejected his own people, the nation of Israel? Of course not! I myself am an Israelite, a descendant of Abraham and a member of the tribe of Benjamin.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 20 points. 2-Part quotation question. From separate verses of Romans chapters 9 and 11. \nQuote the verse that mentions members of God's people and the verse that mentions members of the tribe of Benjamin.\n\t[R 9:6]\tWell then, has God failed to fulfill his promise to Israel? No, for not all who are born into the nation of Israel are truly members of God's people!\n\t[R 11:1]\tI ask, then, has God rejected his own people, the nation of Israel? Of course not! I myself am an Israelite, a descendant of Abraham and a member of the tribe of Benjamin.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The 4th verse contains which exclamation?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:4]\tOf course not!\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 10 points. Chapter analysis answer. From Romans chapter 3. \nThe 4th verse contains which exclamation?\n\t[R 3:4]\tOf course not!\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "EssenceCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            12
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish in essence this verse and the one that follows, quote, \"Dear friends, never take revenge... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 12:19]\tDear friends, never take revenge. Leave that to the righteous anger of God. For the Scriptures say, \"I will take revenge; I will pay them back,\" says the LORD.\n\t[R 12:20]\tInstead, \"If your enemies are hungry, feed them. If they are thirsty, give them something to drink. In doing this, you will heap burning coals of shame on their heads.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 20 points. Essence completion question. From Romans chapter 12. \nFinish in essence this verse and the one that follows, quote, \"Dear friends, never take revenge... \"\n\t[R 12:19]\tDear friends, never take revenge. Leave that to the righteous anger of God. For the Scriptures say, \"I will take revenge; I will pay them back,\" says the LORD.\n\t[R 12:20]\tInstead, \"If your enemies are hungry, feed them. If they are thirsty, give them something to drink. In doing this, you will heap burning coals of shame on their heads.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "the faith of abraham"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Whose promise is mentioned?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:14]\tIf God's promise is only for those who obey the law, then faith is not necessary and the promise is pointless.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 10 points. From the section titled, \"The Faith of Abraham\". \nWhose promise is mentioned?\n\t[R 4:14]\tIf God's promise is only for those who obey the law, then faith is not necessary and the promise is pointless.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The possessive word God's is used to describe what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:13]\tways\n\t[J 3:15]\tkind of wisdom\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. 2-Part answer. From James chapter 3. \nThe possessive word God's is used to describe what?\n\t[J 3:13]\tways\n\t[J 3:15]\tkind of wisdom\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 4
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 4
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How do verses 5, 6, 8, and 9 describe the tongue?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:5]\tIn the same way, the tongue is a small thing that makes grand speeches. But a tiny spark can set a great forest on fire.\n\t[J 3:6]\tAnd among all the parts of the body, the tongue is a flame of fire. It is a whole world of wickedness, corrupting your entire body. It can set your whole life on fire, for it is set on fire by hell itself.\n\t[J 3:8]\tbut no one can tame the tongue. It is restless and evil, full of deadly poison.\n\t[J 3:9]\tSometimes it praises our Lord and Father, and sometimes it curses those who have been made in the image of God.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 30 points. 4-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 4 separate verses of James chapter 3. \nHow do verses 5, 6, 8, and 9 describe the tongue?\n\t[J 3:5]\tIn the same way, the tongue is a small thing that makes grand speeches. But a tiny spark can set a great forest on fire.\n\t[J 3:6]\tAnd among all the parts of the body, the tongue is a flame of fire. It is a whole world of wickedness, corrupting your entire body. It can set your whole life on fire, for it is set on fire by hell itself.\n\t[J 3:8]\tbut no one can tame the tongue. It is restless and evil, full of deadly poison.\n\t[J 3:9]\tSometimes it praises our Lord and Father, and sometimes it curses those who have been made in the image of God.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "One chapter contains seven geographical locations. Identify this chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:1]\tRomans 15\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 20 points. Statement and question. From Romans. \nOne chapter contains seven geographical locations. Identify this chapter.\n\t[R 15:1]\tRomans 15\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            11
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who were holy and who also will be holy?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:16]\tAnd since Abraham and the other patriarchs were holy, their descendants will also be holy- just as the entire batch of dough is holy because the portion given as an offering is holy. For if the roots of the tree are holy, the branches will be, too.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 10 points. 2-Part question. 3-part answer. From Romans chapter 11. \nWho were holy and who also will be holy?\n\t[R 11:16]\tAnd since Abraham and the other patriarchs were holy, their descendants will also be holy- just as the entire batch of dough is holy because the portion given as an offering is holy. For if the roots of the tree are holy, the branches will be, too.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "EssenceCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish in essence this verse and the one that follows, quote, \"Therefore, since we have been made right... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 5:1]\tTherefore, since we have been made right in God's sight by faith, we have peace with God because of what Jesus Christ our Lord has done for us.\n\t[R 5:2]\tBecause of our faith, Christ has brought us into this place of undeserved privilege where we now stand, and we confidently and joyfully look forward to sharing God's glory.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 20 points. Essence completion question. From 2 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 5. \nFinish in essence this verse and the one that follows, quote, \"Therefore, since we have been made right... \"\n\t[R 5:1]\tTherefore, since we have been made right in God's sight by faith, we have peace with God because of what Jesus Christ our Lord has done for us.\n\t[R 5:2]\tBecause of our faith, Christ has brought us into this place of undeserved privilege where we now stand, and we confidently and joyfully look forward to sharing God's glory.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "a living sacrifice to god"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Enthusiastically do what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 12:11]\tNever be lazy, but work hard and serve the Lord enthusiastically.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"A Living Sacrifice to God\". \nEnthusiastically do what?\n\t[R 12:11]\tNever be lazy, but work hard and serve the Lord enthusiastically.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "About pottery, what did Paul say?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:21]\tWhen a potter makes jars out of clay, doesn't he have a right to use the same lump of clay to make one jar for decoration and another to throw garbage into?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 20 points. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 9. \nAbout pottery, what did Paul say?\n\t[R 9:21]\tWhen a potter makes jars out of clay, doesn't he have a right to use the same lump of clay to make one jar for decoration and another to throw garbage into?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 7
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        },
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Mercy is mentioned in which chapters.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t\tRomans 1, 9, 11, and 15\n\t\tJames 2, 3, and 5\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 30 points. 7-Part answer. From Romans and James. \nMercy is mentioned in which chapters.\n\t\tRomans 1, 9, 11, and 15\n\t\tJames 2, 3, and 5\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            1,
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Two verses speak of God's justice. Give in essence these verses.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:32]\tThey know God's justice requires that those who do these things deserve to die, yet they do them anyway. Worse yet, they encourage others to do them, too.\n\t[R 2:2]\tAnd we know that God, in his justice, will punish anyone who does such things.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 20 points. Statement and essence question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 1 and 2. \nTwo verses speak of God's justice. Give in essence these verses.\n\t[R 1:32]\tThey know God's justice requires that those who do these things deserve to die, yet they do them anyway. Worse yet, they encourage others to do them, too.\n\t[R 2:2]\tAnd we know that God, in his justice, will punish anyone who does such things.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "the danger of criticism"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What is not a matter of what we eat or drink?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:17]\tFor the Kingdom of God is not a matter of what we eat or drink, but of living a life of goodness and peace and joy in the Holy Spirit.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"The Danger of Criticism\". \nWhat is not a matter of what we eat or drink?\n\t[R 14:17]\tFor the Kingdom of God is not a matter of what we eat or drink, but of living a life of goodness and peace and joy in the Holy Spirit.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The 27th verse names which individual?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:27]\tIsaiah\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. Chapter analysis answer. From Romans Chapter 9.\nThe 27th verse names which individual?\n\t[R 9:27]\tIsaiah\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "The unique word finality is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:28]\tFor the LORD will carry out his sentence upon the earth quickly and with finality.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. Statement and 2-Part essence question. \nThe unique word finality is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n\t[R 9:28]\tFor the LORD will carry out his sentence upon the earth quickly and with finality.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence the verse that names David, the verse that names Moses and the verse that names Sarah.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:6]\tDavid also spoke of this when he described the happiness of those who are declared righteous without working for it:\n\t[R 4:16]\tSo the promise is received by faith. It is given as a free gift. And we are all certain to receive it, whether or not we live according to the law of Moses, if we have faith like Abraham's. For Abraham is the father of all who believe.\n\t[R 4:19]\tAnd Abraham's faith did not weaken, even though, at about 100 years of age, he figured his body was as good as dead- and so was Sarah's womb.\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. 3-Part essence question. From separate verses of Romans chapter 4. \nGive in essence the verse that names David, the verse that names Moses and the verse that names Sarah.\n\t[R 4:6]\tDavid also spoke of this when he described the happiness of those who are declared righteous without working for it:\n\t[R 4:16]\tSo the promise is received by faith. It is given as a free gift. And we are all certain to receive it, whether or not we live according to the law of Moses, if we have faith like Abraham's. For Abraham is the father of all who believe.\n\t[R 4:19]\tAnd Abraham's faith did not weaken, even though, at about 100 years of age, he figured his body was as good as dead- and so was Sarah's womb.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The section titled \"Greetings from James\" names which individual and contains which exclamation?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 1:1]\tJames\n\t[J 1:1]\tGreetings!\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 10 points. 2-Part question. Chapter analysis answer. From James. \nThe section titled \"Greetings from James\" names which individual and contains which exclamation?\n\t[J 1:1]\tJames\n\t[J 1:1]\tGreetings!\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            14
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "When won't you be criticized for what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:15]\tAnd if another believer is distressed by what you eat, you are not acting in love if you eat it. Don't let your eating ruin someone for whom Christ died.\n\t[R 14:16]\tThen you will not be criticized for doing something you believe is good.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 14. \nWhen won't you be criticized for what?\n\t[R 14:15]\tAnd if another believer is distressed by what you eat, you are not acting in love if you eat it. Don't let your eating ruin someone for whom Christ died.\n\t[R 14:16]\tThen you will not be criticized for doing something you believe is good.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "In fact, what did Paul say?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 2:27]\tIn fact, uncircumcised Gentiles who keep God's law will condemn you Jews who are circumcised and possess God's law but don't obey it.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 20 points. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 2. \nIn fact, what did Paul say?\n\t[R 2:27]\tIn fact, uncircumcised Gentiles who keep God's law will condemn you Jews who are circumcised and possess God's law but don't obey it.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's mercy on israel"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who were enriched?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:12]\tNow if the Gentiles were enriched because the people of Israel turned down God's offer of salvation, think how much greater a blessing the world will share when they finally accept it.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 10 points. From the section titled, \"God's Mercy on Israel\". \nWho were enriched?\n\t[R 11:12]\tNow if the Gentiles were enriched because the people of Israel turned down God's offer of salvation, think how much greater a blessing the world will share when they finally accept it.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 4
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "israel's unbelief"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "To dear brothers and sisters, what did Paul say?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 10:1]\tDear brothers and sisters, the longing of my heart and my prayer to God is for the people of Israel to be saved.\n\t[R 10:2]\tI know what enthusiasm they have for God, but it is misdirected zeal.\n\t[R 10:3]\tFor they don't understand God's way of making people right with himself. Refusing to accept God's way, they cling to their own way of getting right with God by trying to keep the law.\n\t[R 10:4]\tFor Christ has already accomplished the purpose for which the law was given. As a result, all who believe in him are made right with God.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 30 points. Give a complete answer. From 4 consecutive verses of the section titled, \"Israel's Unbelief\". \nTo dear brothers and sisters, what did Paul say?\n\t[R 10:1]\tDear brothers and sisters, the longing of my heart and my prayer to God is for the people of Israel to be saved.\n\t[R 10:2]\tI know what enthusiasm they have for God, but it is misdirected zeal.\n\t[R 10:3]\tFor they don't understand God's way of making people right with himself. Refusing to accept God's way, they cling to their own way of getting right with God by trying to keep the law.\n\t[R 10:4]\tFor Christ has already accomplished the purpose for which the law was given. As a result, all who believe in him are made right with God.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "israel's unbelief"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "All who believe in whom are made right with whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 10:4]\tFor Christ has already accomplished the purpose for which the law was given. As a result, all who believe in him are made right with God.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 10 points. 2-Part question. From the section titled, \"Israel's Unbelief\". \nAll who believe in whom are made right with whom?\n\t[R 10:4]\tFor Christ has already accomplished the purpose for which the law was given. As a result, all who believe in him are made right with God.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "EssenceCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            15
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish in essence this verse and the one that follows, quote, \"My ambition has always been... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:20]\tMy ambition has always been to preach the Good News where the name of Christ has never been heard, rather than where a church has already been started by someone else.\n\t[R 15:21]\tI have been following the plan spoken of in the Scriptures, where it says, \"Those who have never been told about him will see, and those who have never heard of him will understand.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 20 points. Essence completion question. From Romans chapter 15. \nFinish in essence this verse and the one that follows, quote, \"My ambition has always been... \"\n\t[R 15:20]\tMy ambition has always been to preach the Good News where the name of Christ has never been heard, rather than where a church has already been started by someone else.\n\t[R 15:21]\tI have been following the plan spoken of in the Scriptures, where it says, \"Those who have never been told about him will see, and those who have never heard of him will understand.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            14
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "When are you not, quote, \"acting in love?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:15]\tAnd if another believer is distressed by what you eat, you are not acting in love if you eat it. Don't let your eating ruin someone for whom Christ died.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 14. \nWhen are you not, quote, \"acting in love?\"\n\t[R 14:15]\tAnd if another believer is distressed by what you eat, you are not acting in love if you eat it. Don't let your eating ruin someone for whom Christ died.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "James teaches about the tongue's incendiary quality by giving a two-verse illustration about fire. Give this illustration.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:5]\tIn the same way, the tongue is a small thing that makes grand speeches. But a tiny spark can set a great forest on fire.\n\t[J 3:6]\tAnd among all the parts of the body, the tongue is a flame of fire. It is a whole world of wickedness, corrupting your entire body. It can set your whole life on fire, for it is set on fire by hell itself.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 20 points. Statement and question. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of James chapter 3. \nJames teaches about the tongue's incendiary quality by giving a two-verse illustration about fire. Give this illustration.\n\t[J 3:5]\tIn the same way, the tongue is a small thing that makes grand speeches. But a tiny spark can set a great forest on fire.\n\t[J 3:6]\tAnd among all the parts of the body, the tongue is a flame of fire. It is a whole world of wickedness, corrupting your entire body. It can set your whole life on fire, for it is set on fire by hell itself.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText",
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            11
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote the verses in which Paul talked about branches from a, quote, \"wild olive tree.\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:17]\tBut some of these branches from Abraham's tree- some of the people of Israel- have been broken off. And you Gentiles, who were branches from a wild olive tree, have been grafted in. So now you also receive the blessing God has promised Abraham and his children, sharing in the rich nourishment from the root of God's special olive tree.\n\t[R 11:24]\tYou, by nature, were a branch cut from a wild olive tree. So if God was willing to do something contrary to nature by grafting you into his cultivated tree, he will be far more eager to graft the original branches back into the tree where they belong.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 30 points. Scripture text quotation question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 11. \nQuote the verses in which Paul talked about branches from a, quote, \"wild olive tree.\"\n\t[R 11:17]\tBut some of these branches from Abraham's tree- some of the people of Israel- have been broken off. And you Gentiles, who were branches from a wild olive tree, have been grafted in. So now you also receive the blessing God has promised Abraham and his children, sharing in the rich nourishment from the root of God's special olive tree.\n\t[R 11:24]\tYou, by nature, were a branch cut from a wild olive tree. So if God was willing to do something contrary to nature by grafting you into his cultivated tree, he will be far more eager to graft the original branches back into the tree where they belong.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            9,
            11
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who did Paul describe as, quote, \"an Israelite\"?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:5]\tChrist\n\t[R 11:1]\tI myself (Paul)\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. Scripture text question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 9 and 11. \nWho did Paul describe as, quote, \"an Israelite\"?\n\t[R 9:5]\tChrist\n\t[R 11:1]\tI myself (Paul)\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        },
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            1
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What will happen quickly and what must happen quickly?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:28]\tFor the LORD will carry out his sentence upon the earth quickly and with finality.\"\n\t[J 1:19]\tUnderstand this, my dear brothers and sisters: You must all be quick to listen, slow to speak, and slow to get angry.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 2 separate verses of Romans chapter 9 and James chapter 1. \nWhat will happen quickly and what must happen quickly?\n\t[R 9:28]\tFor the LORD will carry out his sentence upon the earth quickly and with finality.\"\n\t[J 1:19]\tUnderstand this, my dear brothers and sisters: You must all be quick to listen, slow to speak, and slow to get angry.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "paul's travel plans"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Paul took a donation where?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:31]\tJerusalem\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 10 points. Chapter analysis answer. From the section titled, \"Paul's Travel Plans\". \nPaul took a donation where?\n\t[R 15:31]\tJerusalem\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            11
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "7.000 others have never done what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:4]\tAnd do you remember God's reply? He said, \"No, I have 7,000 others who have never bowed down to Baal!\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 11. \n7.000 others have never done what?\n\t[R 11:4]\tAnd do you remember God's reply? He said, \"No, I have 7,000 others who have never bowed down to Baal!\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote verses 1, 2, and 3 from the 15th chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:1]\tWe who are strong must be considerate of those who are sensitive about things like this. We must not just please ourselves.\n\t[R 15:2]\tWe should help others do what is right and build them up in the Lord.\n\t[R 15:3]\tFor even Christ didn't live to please himself. As the Scriptures say, \"The insults of those who insult you, O God, have fallen on me.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 30 points. Quotation question. From 3 consecutive verses of Romans. \nQuote verses 1, 2, and 3 from the 15th chapter.\n\t[R 15:1]\tWe who are strong must be considerate of those who are sensitive about things like this. We must not just please ourselves.\n\t[R 15:2]\tWe should help others do what is right and build them up in the Lord.\n\t[R 15:3]\tFor even Christ didn't live to please himself. As the Scriptures say, \"The insults of those who insult you, O God, have fallen on me.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "the power of prayer"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What sent down rain?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:18]\tThen, when he prayed again, the sky sent down rain and the earth began to yield its crops.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 10 points. From the section titled, \"The Power of Prayer\". \nWhat sent down rain?\n\t[J 5:18]\tThen, when he prayed again, the sky sent down rain and the earth began to yield its crops.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            7
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Referring to Paul, what happened quote, \"in my mind?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 7:25]\tThank God! The answer is in Jesus Christ our Lord. So you see how it is: In my mind I really want to obey God's law, but because of my sinful nature I am a slave to sin.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 20 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 7. \nReferring to Paul, what happened quote, \"in my mind?\"\n\t[R 7:25]\tThank God! The answer is in Jesus Christ our Lord. So you see how it is: In my mind I really want to obey God's law, but because of my sinful nature I am a slave to sin.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "love fulfills god's requirements"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What shines?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 13:12]\tThe night is almost gone; the day of salvation will soon be here. So remove your dark deeds like dirty clothes, and put on the shining armor of right living.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Love Fulfills God's Requirements\". \nWhat shines?\n\t[R 13:12]\tThe night is almost gone; the day of salvation will soon be here. So remove your dark deeds like dirty clothes, and put on the shining armor of right living.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 5
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "Romans chapter 3 contains which exclamations?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:2]\tYes, there are great benefits!\n\t[R 3:4]\tOf course not!\n\t[R 3:6]\tOf course not!\n\t[R 3:8]\tThe more we sin, the better it is!\n\t[R 3:31]\tOf course not!\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 20 points. 5-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses. \nRomans chapter 3 contains which exclamations?\n\t[R 3:2]\tYes, there are great benefits!\n\t[R 3:4]\tOf course not!\n\t[R 3:6]\tOf course not!\n\t[R 3:8]\tThe more we sin, the better it is!\n\t[R 3:31]\tOf course not!\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Suppose you see what, say what, and do what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:15]\tSuppose you see a brother or sister who has no food or clothing,\n\t[J 2:16]\tand you say, \"Good-bye and have a good day; stay warm and eat well\"- but then you don't give that person any food or clothing. What good does that do?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 20 points. 3-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of James chapter 2. \nSuppose you see what, say what, and do what?\n\t[J 2:15]\tSuppose you see a brother or sister who has no food or clothing,\n\t[J 2:16]\tand you say, \"Good-bye and have a good day; stay warm and eat well\"- but then you don't give that person any food or clothing. What good does that do?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god remains faithful"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Some Jews were what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:3]\tTrue, some of them were unfaithful; but just because they were unfaithful, does that mean God will be unfaithful?\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. From the section titled, \"God Remains Faithful\". \nSome Jews were what?\n\t[R 3:3]\tTrue, some of them were unfaithful; but just because they were unfaithful, does that mean God will be unfaithful?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            14
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Paul asked which questions?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:4]\tWho are you to condemn someone else's servants?\n\t[R 14:10]\tSo why do you condemn another believer?\n\t[R 14:10]\tWhy do you look down on another believer?\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. 3-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 14. \nPaul asked which questions?\n\t[R 14:4]\tWho are you to condemn someone else's servants?\n\t[R 14:10]\tSo why do you condemn another believer?\n\t[R 14:10]\tWhy do you look down on another believer?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "QuotationCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            7
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish this verse and the two that follow, quote, \"At one time... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 7:9]\tAt one time I lived without understanding the law. But when I learned the command not to covet, for instance, the power of sin came to life,\n\t[R 7:10]\tand I died. So I discovered that the law's commands, which were supposed to bring life, brought spiritual death instead.\n\t[R 7:11]\tSin took advantage of those commands and deceived me; it used the commands to kill me.\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. Quotation completion question. From Romans chapter 7. \nFinish this verse and the two that follow, quote, \"At one time... \"\n\t[R 7:9]\tAt one time I lived without understanding the law. But when I learned the command not to covet, for instance, the power of sin came to life,\n\t[R 7:10]\tand I died. So I discovered that the law's commands, which were supposed to bring life, brought spiritual death instead.\n\t[R 7:11]\tSin took advantage of those commands and deceived me; it used the commands to kill me.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 6
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "Romans chapter 13 contains which question and which Old Testament Scriptures?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 13:3]\tWould you like to live without fear of the authorities?\n\t[R 13:9]\t\"You must not commit adultery. You must not murder. You must not steal. You must not covet.\"\n\t[R 13:9]\t\"Love your neighbor as yourself\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 20 points. 2-Part question. 6-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses. \nRomans chapter 13 contains which question and which Old Testament Scriptures?\n\t[R 13:3]\tWould you like to live without fear of the authorities?\n\t[R 13:9]\t\"You must not commit adultery. You must not murder. You must not steal. You must not covet.\"\n\t[R 13:9]\t\"Love your neighbor as yourself\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How do verses 18, 19, and 20 describe Abraham?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:18]\tEven when there was no reason for hope, Abraham kept hoping- believing that he would become the father of many nations. For God had said to him, \"That's how many descendants you will have!\"\n\t[R 4:19]\tAnd Abraham's faith did not weaken, even though, at about 100 years of age, he figured his body was as good as dead- and so was Sarah's womb.\n\t[R 4:20]\tAbraham never wavered in believing God's promise. In fact, his faith grew stronger, and in this he brought glory to God.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 30 points. 3-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 3 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 4. \nHow do verses 18, 19, and 20 describe Abraham?\n\t[R 4:18]\tEven when there was no reason for hope, Abraham kept hoping- believing that he would become the father of many nations. For God had said to him, \"That's how many descendants you will have!\"\n\t[R 4:19]\tAnd Abraham's faith did not weaken, even though, at about 100 years of age, he figured his body was as good as dead- and so was Sarah's womb.\n\t[R 4:20]\tAbraham never wavered in believing God's promise. In fact, his faith grew stronger, and in this he brought glory to God.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            15
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Paul planned to go where and stop off where?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:24]\tSpain\n\t[R 15:24]\tRome\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 10 points. 2-Part question. Chapter analysis answer. From Romans chapter 15. \nPaul planned to go where and stop off where?\n\t[R 15:24]\tSpain\n\t[R 15:24]\tRome\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Part",
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            16
          ],
          "Section": null
        },
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "When spending time with others, one might say \"hello\" when arriving and \"good-bye\" when leaving. Quote the verse that contains the word \"hello\" and the verse that contains the word \"Good-bye.\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:23]\tGaius says hello to you. He is my host and also serves as host to the whole church. Erastus, the city treasurer, sends you his greetings, and so does our brother Quartus.\n\t[J 2:16]\tand you say, \"Good-bye and have a good day; stay warm and eat well\"- but then you don't give that person any food or clothing. What good does that do?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 20 points. Statement and 2-Part quotation question. From separate verses of Romans chapter 16 and James chapter 2. \nWhen spending time with others, one might say \"hello\" when arriving and \"good-bye\" when leaving. Quote the verse that contains the word \"hello\" and the verse that contains the word \"Good-bye.\"\n\t[R 16:23]\tGaius says hello to you. He is my host and also serves as host to the whole church. Erastus, the city treasurer, sends you his greetings, and so does our brother Quartus.\n\t[J 2:16]\tand you say, \"Good-bye and have a good day; stay warm and eat well\"- but then you don't give that person any food or clothing. What good does that do?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            16
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The 6th verse names which individual?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:6]\tMary\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 10 points. Chapter analysis answer. From Romans chapter 16. \nThe 6th verse names which individual?\n\t[R 16:6]\tMary\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "About Sodom, what did Paul say?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:29]\tAnd Isaiah said the same thing in another place: \" If the LORD of Heaven's Armies had not spared a few of our children, we would have been wiped out like Sodom, destroyed like Gomorrah.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 20 points. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 9. \nAbout Sodom, what did Paul say?\n\t[R 9:29]\tAnd Isaiah said the same thing in another place: \" If the LORD of Heaven's Armies had not spared a few of our children, we would have been wiped out like Sodom, destroyed like Gomorrah.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "the faith of abraham"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "God is able to do what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:21]\tHe was fully convinced that God is able to do whatever he promises.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"The Faith of Abraham\". \nGod is able to do what?\n\t[R 4:21]\tHe was fully convinced that God is able to do whatever he promises.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 14
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give the references for the verses in which Abraham is named.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t\tRomans 4:1, 3, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 22, and 23\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 30 points. 14-Part answer. From Romans chapter 4. \nGive the references for the verses in which Abraham is named.\n\t\tRomans 4:1, 3, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 22, and 23\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "In two chapters, Paul expressed his desire to visit the Romans. Identify these chapters.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t\tRomans 1 and 15\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 20 points. Statement and question. 2-Part answer. From Romans. \nIn two chapters, Paul expressed his desire to visit the Romans. Identify these chapters.\n\t\tRomans 1 and 15\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "paul greets his friends"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The opening verse names which individual and which geographical location?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:1]\tPhoebe\n\t[R 16:1]\tCenchrea\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 10 points. 2-Part question. Chapter analysis answer. From the section titled, \"Paul Greets His Friends\". \nThe opening verse names which individual and which geographical location?\n\t[R 16:1]\tPhoebe\n\t[R 16:1]\tCenchrea\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            1
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who have something to boast about and why?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 1:9]\tBelievers who are poor have something to boast about, for God has honored them.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From James chapter 1. \nWho have something to boast about and why?\n\t[J 1:9]\tBelievers who are poor have something to boast about, for God has honored them.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's judgment of sin"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who is storing up what for whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 2:5]\tBut because you are stubborn and refuse to turn from your sin, you are storing up terrible punishment for yourself.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 10 points. 3-Part question. From the section titled, \"God's Judgment of Sin\". \nWho is storing up what for whom?\n\t[R 2:5]\tBut because you are stubborn and refuse to turn from your sin, you are storing up terrible punishment for yourself.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            5,
            6
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence the verse that contains the phrase \"gift of forgiveness\", the verse that contains the phrase \"gift of righteousness\", and the verse that contains the phrase \"gift of God.\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 5:15]\tBut there is a great difference between Adam's sin and God's gracious gift. For the sin of this one man, Adam, brought death to many. But even greater is God's wonderful grace and his gift of forgiveness to many through this other man, Jesus Christ.\n\t[R 5:17]\tFor the sin of this one man, Adam, caused death to rule over many. But even greater is God's wonderful grace and his gift of righteousness, for all who receive it will live in triumph over sin and death through this one man, Jesus Christ.\n\t[R 6:23]\tFor the wages of sin is death, but the free gift of God is eternal life through Christ Jesus our Lord.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 30 points. 3-Part essence question. From separate verses of Romans chapters 5 and 6. \nGive in essence the verse that contains the phrase \"gift of forgiveness\", the verse that contains the phrase \"gift of righteousness\", and the verse that contains the phrase \"gift of God.\"\n\t[R 5:15]\tBut there is a great difference between Adam's sin and God's gracious gift. For the sin of this one man, Adam, brought death to many. But even greater is God's wonderful grace and his gift of forgiveness to many through this other man, Jesus Christ.\n\t[R 5:17]\tFor the sin of this one man, Adam, caused death to rule over many. But even greater is God's wonderful grace and his gift of righteousness, for all who receive it will live in triumph over sin and death through this one man, Jesus Christ.\n\t[R 6:23]\tFor the wages of sin is death, but the free gift of God is eternal life through Christ Jesus our Lord.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            11
          ],
          "Section": null
        },
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What is deep?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:8]\tsleep\n\t[J 4:9]\tgrief\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 20 points. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 11 and James chapter 4. \nWhat is deep?\n\t[R 11:8]\tsleep\n\t[J 4:9]\tgrief\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "the danger of criticism"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who might be caused, quote, \"to stumble?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:21]\tIt is better not to eat meat or drink wine or do anything else if it might cause another believer to stumble.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"The Danger of Criticism\". \nWho might be caused, quote, \"to stumble?\"\n\t[R 14:21]\tIt is better not to eat meat or drink wine or do anything else if it might cause another believer to stumble.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's mercy is for everyone"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Once, what happened, and now, what happened?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:30]\tOnce, you Gentiles were rebels against God, but when the people of Israel rebelled against him, God was merciful to you instead.\n\t[R 11:31]\tNow they are the rebels, and God's mercy has come to you so that they, too, will share in God's mercy.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of the section titled, \"God's Mercy Is for Everyone\". \nOnce, what happened, and now, what happened?\n\t[R 11:30]\tOnce, you Gentiles were rebels against God, but when the people of Israel rebelled against him, God was merciful to you instead.\n\t[R 11:31]\tNow they are the rebels, and God's mercy has come to you so that they, too, will share in God's mercy.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "living to please others"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who will rule over the Gentiles?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:12]\tAnd in another place Isaiah said, \"The heir to David's throne will come, and he will rule over the Gentiles. They will place their hope on him.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Living to Please Others\". \nWho will rule over the Gentiles?\n\t[R 15:12]\tAnd in another place Isaiah said, \"The heir to David's throne will come, and he will rule over the Gentiles. They will place their hope on him.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            3,
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Two verses contain the word \"truthfulness.\" Quote these verses.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:7]\t\"But,\" someone might still argue, \"how can God condemn me as a sinner if my dishonesty highlights his truthfulness and brings him more glory?\"\n\t[R 9:1]\tWith Christ as my witness, I speak with utter truthfulness. My conscience and the Holy Spirit confirm it.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 20 points. Statement and quotation question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 3 and 9. \nTwo verses contain the word \"truthfulness.\" Quote these verses.\n\t[R 3:7]\t\"But,\" someone might still argue, \"how can God condemn me as a sinner if my dishonesty highlights his truthfulness and brings him more glory?\"\n\t[R 9:1]\tWith Christ as my witness, I speak with utter truthfulness. My conscience and the Holy Spirit confirm it.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "listening and doing"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "About anger, what did James say?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 1:19]\tUnderstand this, my dear brothers and sisters: You must all be quick to listen, slow to speak, and slow to get angry.\n\t[J 1:20]\tHuman anger does not produce the righteousness God desires.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 20 points. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of the section titled, \"Listening and Doing\". \nAbout anger, what did James say?\n\t[J 1:19]\tUnderstand this, my dear brothers and sisters: You must all be quick to listen, slow to speak, and slow to get angry.\n\t[J 1:20]\tHuman anger does not produce the righteousness God desires.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            11
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What can never be withdrawn?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:29]\tFor God's gifts and his call can never be withdrawn.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 10 points. Give 2 complete answers. From Romans chapter 11. \nWhat can never be withdrawn?\n\t[R 11:29]\tFor God's gifts and his call can never be withdrawn.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "faith and endurance"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What is divided between God and the world?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 1:8]\tTheir loyalty is divided between God and the world, and they are unstable in everything they do.\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Faith and Endurance\". \nWhat is divided between God and the world?\n\t[J 1:8]\tTheir loyalty is divided between God and the world, and they are unstable in everything they do.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote verses 10, 11, and 12.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:10]\tAs the Scriptures say, \"No one is righteous- not even one.\n\t[R 3:11]\tNo one is truly wise; no one is seeking God.\n\t[R 3:12]\tAll have turned away; all have become useless. No one does good, not a single one.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. Quotation question. From 3 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 3. \nQuote verses 10, 11, and 12.\n\t[R 3:10]\tAs the Scriptures say, \"No one is righteous- not even one.\n\t[R 3:11]\tNo one is truly wise; no one is seeking God.\n\t[R 3:12]\tAll have turned away; all have become useless. No one does good, not a single one.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "christ took our punishment"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "God presented Jesus as what and why?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:25]\tFor God presented Jesus as the sacrifice for sin. People are made right with God when they believe that Jesus sacrificed his life, shedding his blood. This sacrifice shows that God was being fair when he held back and did not punish those who sinned in times past,\n\t[R 3:26]\tfor he was looking ahead and including them in what he would do in this present time. God did this to demonstrate his righteousness, for he himself is fair and just, and he makes sinners right in his sight when they believe in Jesus.\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of the section titled, \"Christ Took Our Punishment\". \nGod presented Jesus as what and why?\n\t[R 3:25]\tFor God presented Jesus as the sacrifice for sin. People are made right with God when they believe that Jesus sacrificed his life, shedding his blood. This sacrifice shows that God was being fair when he held back and did not punish those who sinned in times past,\n\t[R 3:26]\tfor he was looking ahead and including them in what he would do in this present time. God did this to demonstrate his righteousness, for he himself is fair and just, and he makes sinners right in his sight when they believe in Jesus.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What is bitter?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:11]\tDoes a spring of water bubble out with both fresh water and bitter water?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 10 points. From James chapter 3. \nWhat is bitter?\n\t[J 3:11]\tDoes a spring of water bubble out with both fresh water and bitter water?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "One chapter contains less than 20 verses. Identify this chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t\tRomans 13\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 20 points. Statement and question. From Romans. \nOne chapter contains less than 20 verses. Identify this chapter.\n\t\tRomans 13\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "life in the spirit"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Referring to Christ, under what condition must we, quote, \"share his suffering?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:17]\tAnd since we are his children, we are his heirs. In fact, together with Christ we are heirs of God's glory. But if we are to share his glory, we must also share his suffering.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Life in the Spirit\". \nReferring to Christ, under what condition must we, quote, \"share his suffering?\"\n\t[R 8:17]\tAnd since we are his children, we are his heirs. In fact, together with Christ we are heirs of God's glory. But if we are to share his glory, we must also share his suffering.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            1,
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The word utter is used to describe what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:22]\tfools\n\t[R 9:1]\ttruthfulness\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 20 points. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 1 and 9. \nThe word utter is used to describe what?\n\t[R 1:22]\tfools\n\t[R 9:1]\ttruthfulness\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            13
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What is almost gone?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 13:12]\tThe night is almost gone; the day of salvation will soon be here. So remove your dark deeds like dirty clothes, and put on the shining armor of right living.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 10 points. From Romans chapter 13. \nWhat is almost gone?\n\t[R 13:12]\tThe night is almost gone; the day of salvation will soon be here. So remove your dark deeds like dirty clothes, and put on the shining armor of right living.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            8,
            10
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Three parenthetical statements mention Christ. Give these parenthetical statements.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:9]\t(And remember that those who do not have the Spirit of Christ living in them do not belong to him at all.)\n\t[R 10:6]\t(to bring Christ down to earth)\n\t[R 10:7]\t(to bring Christ back to life again\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 30 points. Statement and question. 3-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 8 and 10. \nThree parenthetical statements mention Christ. Give these parenthetical statements.\n\t[R 8:9]\t(And remember that those who do not have the Spirit of Christ living in them do not belong to him at all.)\n\t[R 10:6]\t(to bring Christ down to earth)\n\t[R 10:7]\t(to bring Christ back to life again\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            6
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What did Paul say the Romans were, quote, \"now ashamed of... \"?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 6:21]\tAnd what was the result? You are now ashamed of the things you used to do, things that end in eternal doom.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 20 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 6. \nWhat did Paul say the Romans were, quote, \"now ashamed of... \"?\n\t[R 6:21]\tAnd what was the result? You are now ashamed of the things you used to do, things that end in eternal doom.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "paul greets his friends"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Priscilla risked what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:4]\tIn fact, they once risked their lives for me. I am thankful to them, and so are all the Gentile churches.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Paul Greets His Friends\". \nPriscilla risked what?\n\t[R 16:4]\tIn fact, they once risked their lives for me. I am thankful to them, and so are all the Gentile churches.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        },
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Paul was writing to whom and James was writing to whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:7]\tI am writing to all of you in Rome who are loved by God and are called to be his own holy people. May God our Father and the Lord Jesus Christ give you grace and peace.\n\t[J 1:1]\tThis letter is from James, a slave of God and of the Lord Jesus Christ. I am writing to the \"twelve tribes\"- Jewish believers scattered abroad. Greetings!\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 2 separate verses of Romans and James. \nPaul was writing to whom and James was writing to whom?\n\t[R 1:7]\tI am writing to all of you in Rome who are loved by God and are called to be his own holy people. May God our Father and the Lord Jesus Christ give you grace and peace.\n\t[J 1:1]\tThis letter is from James, a slave of God and of the Lord Jesus Christ. I am writing to the \"twelve tribes\"- Jewish believers scattered abroad. Greetings!\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Elders anoint with what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:14]\tAre any of you sick? You should call for the elders of the church to come and pray over you, anointing you with oil in the name of the Lord.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 10 points. From James chapter 5. \nElders anoint with what?\n\t[J 5:14]\tAre any of you sick? You should call for the elders of the church to come and pray over you, anointing you with oil in the name of the Lord.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            3,
            10
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence the verses in which lips are mentioned.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:13]\t\"Their talk is foul, like the stench from an open grave. Their tongues are filled with lies.\" \"Snake venom drips from their lips.\"\n\t[R 10:8]\tIn fact, it says, \"The message is very close at hand; it is on your lips and in your heart.\" And that message is the very message about faith that we preach:\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. Essence question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 3 and 10. \nGive in essence the verses in which lips are mentioned.\n\t[R 3:13]\t\"Their talk is foul, like the stench from an open grave. Their tongues are filled with lies.\" \"Snake venom drips from their lips.\"\n\t[R 10:8]\tIn fact, it says, \"The message is very close at hand; it is on your lips and in your heart.\" And that message is the very message about faith that we preach:\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "EssenceCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish in essence this verse and the three that follow, quote, \"People can tame... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:7]\tPeople can tame all kinds of animals, birds, reptiles, and fish,\n\t[J 3:8]\tbut no one can tame the tongue. It is restless and evil, full of deadly poison.\n\t[J 3:9]\tSometimes it praises our Lord and Father, and sometimes it curses those who have been made in the image of God.\n\t[J 3:10]\tAnd so blessing and cursing come pouring out of the same mouth. Surely, my brothers and sisters, this is not right!\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 30 points. Essence completion question. From James chapter 3. \nFinish in essence this verse and the three that follow, quote, \"People can tame... \"\n\t[J 3:7]\tPeople can tame all kinds of animals, birds, reptiles, and fish,\n\t[J 3:8]\tbut no one can tame the tongue. It is restless and evil, full of deadly poison.\n\t[J 3:9]\tSometimes it praises our Lord and Father, and sometimes it curses those who have been made in the image of God.\n\t[J 3:10]\tAnd so blessing and cursing come pouring out of the same mouth. Surely, my brothers and sisters, this is not right!\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            14
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Decide instead to do what instead of what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:13]\tSo let's stop condemning each other. Decide instead to live in such a way that you will not cause another believer to stumble and fall.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 14. \nDecide instead to do what instead of what?\n\t[R 14:13]\tSo let's stop condemning each other. Decide instead to live in such a way that you will not cause another believer to stumble and fall.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "faith without good deeds is dead"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Unless faith produces good deeds, what is it?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:17]\tSo you see, faith by itself isn't enough. Unless it produces good deeds, it is dead and useless.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 10 points. 2-Part answer. From the section titled, \"Faith without Good Deeds Is Dead\". \nUnless faith produces good deeds, what is it?\n\t[J 2:17]\tSo you see, faith by itself isn't enough. Unless it produces good deeds, it is dead and useless.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The 4th verse contains which exclamation, the 9th verse contains which exclamation, and the 17th verse contains which exclamation,\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:4]\tFor listen!\n\t[J 5:9]\tFor look- the Judge is standing at the door!\n\t[J 5:17]\tElijah was as human as we are, and yet when he prayed earnestly that no rain would fall, none fell for three and a half years!\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 20 points. 3-Part question. Chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of James chapter 5. \nThe 4th verse contains which exclamation, the 9th verse contains which exclamation, and the 17th verse contains which exclamation,\n\t[J 5:4]\tFor listen!\n\t[J 5:9]\tFor look- the Judge is standing at the door!\n\t[J 5:17]\tElijah was as human as we are, and yet when he prayed earnestly that no rain would fall, none fell for three and a half years!\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "warning to the rich"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "With anguish, do what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:1]\tLook here, you rich people: Weep and groan with anguish because of all the terrible troubles ahead of you.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 10 points. 2-Part answer. From the section titled, \"Warning to the Rich\". \nWith anguish, do what?\n\t[J 5:1]\tLook here, you rich people: Weep and groan with anguish because of all the terrible troubles ahead of you.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 4
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            1,
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What drag whom and who drag whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 1:14]\tTemptation comes from our own desires, which entice us and drag us away.\n\t[J 2:6]\tBut you dishonor the poor! Isn't it the rich who oppress you and drag you into court \n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 20 points. 4-Part question. From separate verses of James chapters 1 and 2. \nWhat drag whom and who drag whom?\n\t[J 1:14]\tTemptation comes from our own desires, which entice us and drag us away.\n\t[J 2:6]\tBut you dishonor the poor! Isn't it the rich who oppress you and drag you into court \n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "According to Romans 8:39, James 2:8 and James 3:2, indeed, what is true?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:39]\tNo power in the sky above or in the earth below- indeed, nothing in all creation will ever be able to separate us from the love of God that is revealed in Christ Jesus our Lord.\n\t[J 2:8]\tYes indeed, it is good when you obey the royal law as found in the Scriptures: \"Love your neighbor as yourself.\"\n\t[J 3:2]\tIndeed, we all make many mistakes. For if we could control our tongues, we would be perfect and could also control ourselves in every other way.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 30 points. 3-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 3 separate verses. \nAccording to Romans 8:39, James 2:8 and James 3:2, indeed, what is true?\n\t[R 8:39]\tNo power in the sky above or in the earth below- indeed, nothing in all creation will ever be able to separate us from the love of God that is revealed in Christ Jesus our Lord.\n\t[J 2:8]\tYes indeed, it is good when you obey the royal law as found in the Scriptures: \"Love your neighbor as yourself.\"\n\t[J 3:2]\tIndeed, we all make many mistakes. For if we could control our tongues, we would be perfect and could also control ourselves in every other way.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "the danger of criticism"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who want to honor the Lord and who want to please the Lord?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:6]\tThose who worship the Lord on a special day do it to honor him. Those who eat any kind of food do so to honor the Lord, since they give thanks to God before eating. And those who refuse to eat certain foods also want to please the Lord and give thanks to God.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give 3 complete answers. From the section titled, \"The Danger of Criticism\". \nWho want to honor the Lord and who want to please the Lord?\n\t[R 14:6]\tThose who worship the Lord on a special day do it to honor him. Those who eat any kind of food do so to honor the Lord, since they give thanks to God before eating. And those who refuse to eat certain foods also want to please the Lord and give thanks to God.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The 16th verse contains which question?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:16]\tWhat good does that do?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 10 points. Chapter analysis answer. From James chapter 2. \nThe 16th verse contains which question?\n\t[J 2:16]\tWhat good does that do?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            8
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The possessive word Christ's is used to describe what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:35]\tlove\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. From Romans chapter 8. \nThe possessive word Christ's is used to describe what?\n\t[R 8:35]\tlove\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "One chapter contains three parenthetical statements. Identify this chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t\tRomans 8\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. Statement and question. From Romans. \nOne chapter contains three parenthetical statements. Identify this chapter.\n\t\tRomans 8\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 6
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give the complete references for the verses in which Adam is named.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t\tRomans 5:12, 14, 15, 16, 17, and 18\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. 6-Part answer. From Romans. \nGive the complete references for the verses in which Adam is named.\n\t\tRomans 5:12, 14, 15, 16, 17, and 18\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            8
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The word future is used to describe what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:19]\tday\n\t[R 8:23]\tglory\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 20 points. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 8. \nThe word future is used to describe what?\n\t[R 8:19]\tday\n\t[R 8:23]\tglory\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            3,
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Two questions mention circumcision and one question mentions uncircumcision. Give these questions.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:1]\tIs there any value in the ceremony of circumcision?\n\t[R 4:9]\tNow, is this blessing only for the Jews, or is it also for uncircumcised Gentiles?\n\t[R 4:10]\tWas he counted as righteous only after he was circumcised, or was it before he was circumcised?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 30 points. Statement and question. 3-Part Chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 3 and 4. \nTwo questions mention circumcision and one question mentions uncircumcision. Give these questions.\n\t[R 3:1]\tIs there any value in the ceremony of circumcision?\n\t[R 4:9]\tNow, is this blessing only for the Jews, or is it also for uncircumcised Gentiles?\n\t[R 4:10]\tWas he counted as righteous only after he was circumcised, or was it before he was circumcised?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "life in the spirit"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Your body will die because of what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:10]\tAnd Christ lives within you, so even though your body will die because of sin, the Spirit gives you life because you have been made right with God.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 10 points. From the section titled, \"Life in the Spirit\". \nYour body will die because of what?\n\t[R 8:10]\tAnd Christ lives within you, so even though your body will die because of sin, the Spirit gives you life because you have been made right with God.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "The unique word lust is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:27]\tAnd the men, instead of having normal sexual relations with women, burned with lust for each other. Men did shameful things with other men, and as a result of this sin, they suffered within themselves the penalty they deserved.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 20 points. Statement and 2-Part essence question. \nThe unique word lust is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n\t[R 1:27]\tAnd the men, instead of having normal sexual relations with women, burned with lust for each other. Men did shameful things with other men, and as a result of this sin, they suffered within themselves the penalty they deserved.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "paul's travel plans"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Where did Paul want to, quote, \"take a gift?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:25]\tJerusalem\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Chapter analysis answer. From the section titled, \"Paul's Travel Plans\". \nWhere did Paul want to, quote, \"take a gift?\"\n\t[R 15:25]\tJerusalem\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "nothing can separate us from god's love"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Why did Paul say that no one will, quote, \"condemn us?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:34]\tWho then will condemn us? No one- for Christ Jesus died for us and was raised to life for us, and he is sitting in the place of honor at God's right hand, pleading for us.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 20 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Nothing Can Separate Us from God's Love\". \nWhy did Paul say that no one will, quote, \"condemn us?\"\n\t[R 8:34]\tWho then will condemn us? No one- for Christ Jesus died for us and was raised to life for us, and he is sitting in the place of honor at God's right hand, pleading for us.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "paul's final instructions"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Paul wanted the Romans to be wise in what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:19]\tBut everyone knows that you are obedient to the Lord. This makes me very happy. I want you to be wise in doing right and to stay innocent of any wrong.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Paul's Final Instructions\". \nPaul wanted the Romans to be wise in what?\n\t[R 16:19]\tBut everyone knows that you are obedient to the Lord. This makes me very happy. I want you to be wise in doing right and to stay innocent of any wrong.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote the verses in which selfishness is mentioned.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:14]\tBut if you are bitterly jealous and there is selfish ambition in your heart, don't cover up the truth with boasting and lying.\n\t[J 3:15]\tFor jealousy and selfishness are not God's kind of wisdom. Such things are earthly, unspiritual, and demonic.\n\t[J 3:16]\tFor wherever there is jealousy and selfish ambition, there you will find disorder and evil of every kind.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 30 points. Quotation question. 3-Part answer. From 3 consecutive verses of James chapter 3. \nQuote the verses in which selfishness is mentioned.\n\t[J 3:14]\tBut if you are bitterly jealous and there is selfish ambition in your heart, don't cover up the truth with boasting and lying.\n\t[J 3:15]\tFor jealousy and selfishness are not God's kind of wisdom. Such things are earthly, unspiritual, and demonic.\n\t[J 3:16]\tFor wherever there is jealousy and selfish ambition, there you will find disorder and evil of every kind.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "EssenceCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            8
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish in essence this verse and the two that follow, quote, \"Against its will... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:20]\tAgainst its will, all creation was subjected to God's curse. But with eager hope,\n\t[R 8:21]\tthe creation looks forward to the day when it will join God's children in glorious freedom from death and decay.\n\t[R 8:22]\tFor we know that all creation has been groaning as in the pains of childbirth right up to the present time.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 20 points. Essence completion question. From Romans chapter 8. \nFinish in essence this verse and the two that follow, quote, \"Against its will... \"\n\t[R 8:20]\tAgainst its will, all creation was subjected to God's curse. But with eager hope,\n\t[R 8:21]\tthe creation looks forward to the day when it will join God's children in glorious freedom from death and decay.\n\t[R 8:22]\tFor we know that all creation has been groaning as in the pains of childbirth right up to the present time.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "sin's power is broken"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What were crucified with Christ?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 6:6]\tWe know that our old sinful selves were crucified with Christ so that sin might lose its power in our lives. We are no longer slaves to sin.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Sin's Power Is Broken\". \nWhat were crucified with Christ?\n\t[R 6:6]\tWe know that our old sinful selves were crucified with Christ so that sin might lose its power in our lives. We are no longer slaves to sin.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of God...?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 2:20]\tways\n\t[R 2:24]\tname\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. Scripture text question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 2. \nHow does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of God...?\"\n\t[R 2:20]\tways\n\t[R 2:24]\tname\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's mercy on israel"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "God has shut what and closed what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:8]\tAs the Scriptures say, \"God has put them into a deep sleep. To this day he has shut their eyes so they do not see, and closed their ears so they do not hear.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 10 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"God's Mercy on Israel\". \nGod has shut what and closed what?\n\t[R 11:8]\tAs the Scriptures say, \"God has put them into a deep sleep. To this day he has shut their eyes so they do not see, and closed their ears so they do not hear.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 4
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give the complete references for the verses in which David is named.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:3]\tRomans 1:3\n\t[R 4:6]\tRomans 4:6\n\t[R 11:9]\tRomans 11:9\n\t[R 15:12]\tRomans 15:12\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 30 points. 4-Part answer. \nGive the complete references for the verses in which David is named.\n\t[R 1:3]\tRomans 1:3\n\t[R 4:6]\tRomans 4:6\n\t[R 11:9]\tRomans 11:9\n\t[R 15:12]\tRomans 15:12\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "paul's final instructions"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "About hosting, what did Paul say?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:23]\tGaius says hello to you. He is my host and also serves as host to the whole church. Erastus, the city treasurer, sends you his greetings, and so does our brother Quartus.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 20 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Paul's Final Instructions\". \nAbout hosting, what did Paul say?\n\t[R 16:23]\tGaius says hello to you. He is my host and also serves as host to the whole church. Erastus, the city treasurer, sends you his greetings, and so does our brother Quartus.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "a warning against prejudice"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Evil motives guide what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:4]\tdoesn't this discrimination show that your judgments are guided by evil motives?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"A Warning against Prejudice\". \nEvil motives guide what?\n\t[J 2:4]\tdoesn't this discrimination show that your judgments are guided by evil motives?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "EssenceCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish in essence this verse and the one that follows, quote, \"True, some of them... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:3]\tTrue, some of them were unfaithful; but just because they were unfaithful, does that mean God will be unfaithful?\n\t[R 3:4]\tOf course not! Even if everyone else is a liar, God is true. As the Scriptures say about him, \"You will be proved right in what you say, and you will win your case in court.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 20 points. Essence completion question. From Romans chapter 3. \nFinish in essence this verse and the one that follows, quote, \"True, some of them... \"\n\t[R 3:3]\tTrue, some of them were unfaithful; but just because they were unfaithful, does that mean God will be unfaithful?\n\t[R 3:4]\tOf course not! Even if everyone else is a liar, God is true. As the Scriptures say about him, \"You will be proved right in what you say, and you will win your case in court.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "living to please others"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "All the Gentiles should praise whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:11]\tAnd yet again, \"Praise the LORD, all you Gentiles. Praise him, all you people of the earth.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 10 points. From the section titled, \"Living to Please Others\". \nAll the Gentiles should praise whom?\n\t[R 15:11]\tAnd yet again, \"Praise the LORD, all you Gentiles. Praise him, all you people of the earth.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "faith without good deeds is dead"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "We are shown to be what, how?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:24]\tSo you see, we are shown to be right with God by what we do, not by faith alone.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Faith without Good Deeds Is Dead\". \nWe are shown to be what, how?\n\t[J 2:24]\tSo you see, we are shown to be right with God by what we do, not by faith alone.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            14
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who rose again?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:9]\tChrist died and rose again for this very purpose- to be Lord both of the living and of the dead.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 10 points. From Romans chapter 14. \nWho rose again?\n\t[R 14:9]\tChrist died and rose again for this very purpose- to be Lord both of the living and of the dead.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The possessive word God's is used to describe what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:4]\tadopted children\n\t[R 9:6]\tpeople\n\t[R 9:30]\tstandards\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 20 points. 3-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 9. \nThe possessive word God's is used to describe what?\n\t[R 9:4]\tadopted children\n\t[R 9:6]\tpeople\n\t[R 9:30]\tstandards\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "controlling the tongue"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What can set what on fire?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:5]\tIn the same way, the tongue is a small thing that makes grand speeches. But a tiny spark can set a great forest on fire.\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Controlling the Tongue\". \nWhat can set what on fire?\n\t[J 3:5]\tIn the same way, the tongue is a small thing that makes grand speeches. But a tiny spark can set a great forest on fire.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            7
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Why was the trouble not with the law and why was the trouble with Paul?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 7:14]\tSo the trouble is not with the law, for it is spiritual and good. The trouble is with me, for I am all too human, a slave to sin.\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 7. \nWhy was the trouble not with the law and why was the trouble with Paul?\n\t[R 7:14]\tSo the trouble is not with the law, for it is spiritual and good. The trouble is with me, for I am all too human, a slave to sin.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence verses 13, 14, and 15 from the 10th chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 10:13]\tFor \"Everyone who calls on the name of the LORD will be saved.\"\n\t[R 10:14]\tBut how can they call on him to save them unless they believe in him? And how can they believe in him if they have never heard about him? And how can they hear about him unless someone tells them?\n\t[R 10:15]\tAnd how will anyone go and tell them without being sent? That is why the Scriptures say, \"How beautiful are the feet of messengers who bring good news!\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. Essence question. From 3 consecutive verses of Romans. \nGive in essence verses 13, 14, and 15 from the 10th chapter.\n\t[R 10:13]\tFor \"Everyone who calls on the name of the LORD will be saved.\"\n\t[R 10:14]\tBut how can they call on him to save them unless they believe in him? And how can they believe in him if they have never heard about him? And how can they hear about him unless someone tells them?\n\t[R 10:15]\tAnd how will anyone go and tell them without being sent? That is why the Scriptures say, \"How beautiful are the feet of messengers who bring good news!\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's judgment of sin"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "We think we can avoid what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 2:3]\tSince you judge others for doing these things, why do you think you can avoid God's judgment when you do the same things?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"God's Judgment of Sin\". \nWe think we can avoid what?\n\t[R 2:3]\tSince you judge others for doing these things, why do you think you can avoid God's judgment when you do the same things?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            12
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Instead of copying the behavior of this world, what should you do and why?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 12:2]\tDon't copy the behavior and customs of this world, but let God transform you into a new person by changing the way you think. Then you will learn to know God's will for you, which is good and pleasing and perfect.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 12. \nInstead of copying the behavior of this world, what should you do and why?\n\t[R 12:2]\tDon't copy the behavior and customs of this world, but let God transform you into a new person by changing the way you think. Then you will learn to know God's will for you, which is good and pleasing and perfect.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            14
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote verses 7, 8, and 9.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:7]\tFor we don't live for ourselves or die for ourselves.\n\t[R 14:8]\tIf we live, it's to honor the Lord. And if we die, it's to honor the Lord. So whether we live or die, we belong to the Lord.\n\t[R 14:9]\tChrist died and rose again for this very purpose- to be Lord both of the living and of the dead.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 30 points. Quotation question. From 3 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 14. \nQuote verses 7, 8, and 9.\n\t[R 14:7]\tFor we don't live for ourselves or die for ourselves.\n\t[R 14:8]\tIf we live, it's to honor the Lord. And if we die, it's to honor the Lord. So whether we live or die, we belong to the Lord.\n\t[R 14:9]\tChrist died and rose again for this very purpose- to be Lord both of the living and of the dead.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            1
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How does James begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of God...?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 1:1]\tslave\n\t[J 1:27]\tsight\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 20 points. Scripture text question. 2-Part answer. From James chapter 1. \nHow does James begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of God...?\"\n\t[J 1:1]\tslave\n\t[J 1:27]\tsight\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's selection of israel"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "God does not call people according to what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:12]\the calls people, but not according to their good or bad works.) She was told, \"Your older son will serve your younger son.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"God's Selection of Israel\". \nGod does not call people according to what?\n\t[R 9:12]\the calls people, but not according to their good or bad works.) She was told, \"Your older son will serve your younger son.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "warning to the rich"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Before exclaiming \"For listen!\", what did James say?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:1]\tLook here, you rich people: Weep and groan with anguish because of all the terrible troubles ahead of you.\n\t[J 5:2]\tYour wealth is rotting away, and your fine clothes are moth-eaten rags.\n\t[J 5:3]\tYour gold and silver are corroded. The very wealth you were counting on will eat away your flesh like fire. This corroded treasure you have hoarded will testify against you on the day of judgment.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 30 points. Give a complete answer. From 3 consecutive verses of the section titled, \"Warning to the Rich\". \nBefore exclaiming \"For listen!\", what did James say?\n\t[J 5:1]\tLook here, you rich people: Weep and groan with anguish because of all the terrible troubles ahead of you.\n\t[J 5:2]\tYour wealth is rotting away, and your fine clothes are moth-eaten rags.\n\t[J 5:3]\tYour gold and silver are corroded. The very wealth you were counting on will eat away your flesh like fire. This corroded treasure you have hoarded will testify against you on the day of judgment.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "According to James 1:22 and 4:16, otherwise, what is true?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 1:22]\tBut don't just listen to God's word. You must do what it says. Otherwise, you are only fooling yourselves.\n\t[J 4:16]\tOtherwise you are boasting about your own pretentious plans, and all such boasting is evil.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 2 separate verses of James. \nAccording to James 1:22 and 4:16, otherwise, what is true?\n\t[J 1:22]\tBut don't just listen to God's word. You must do what it says. Otherwise, you are only fooling yourselves.\n\t[J 4:16]\tOtherwise you are boasting about your own pretentious plans, and all such boasting is evil.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's mercy is for everyone"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The one who rescues will come from where?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:26]\tJerusalem\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 10 points. Chapter analysis answer. From the section titled, \"God's Mercy Is for Everyone\". \nThe one who rescues will come from where?\n\t[R 11:26]\tJerusalem\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote verses 24 and 25 from the 7th chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 7:24]\tOh, what a miserable person I am! Who will free me from this life that is dominated by sin and death?\n\t[R 7:25]\tThank God! The answer is in Jesus Christ our Lord. So you see how it is: In my mind I really want to obey God's law, but because of my sinful nature I am a slave to sin.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 20 points. Quotation question. From 2 consecutive verses of Romans. \nQuote verses 24 and 25 from the 7th chapter.\n\t[R 7:24]\tOh, what a miserable person I am! Who will free me from this life that is dominated by sin and death?\n\t[R 7:25]\tThank God! The answer is in Jesus Christ our Lord. So you see how it is: In my mind I really want to obey God's law, but because of my sinful nature I am a slave to sin.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "nothing can separate us from god's love"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "We are threatened with what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:35]\tCan anything ever separate us from Christ's love? Does it mean he no longer loves us if we have trouble or calamity, or are persecuted, or hungry, or destitute, or in danger, or threatened with death?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 10 points. From the section titled, \"Nothing Can Separate Us from God's Love\". \nWe are threatened with what?\n\t[R 8:35]\tCan anything ever separate us from Christ's love? Does it mean he no longer loves us if we have trouble or calamity, or are persecuted, or hungry, or destitute, or in danger, or threatened with death?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "The unique word city is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:23]\tGaius says hello to you. He is my host and also serves as host to the whole church. Erastus, the city treasurer, sends you his greetings, and so does our brother Quartus.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. Statement and 2-Part essence question. \nThe unique word city is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n\t[R 16:23]\tGaius says hello to you. He is my host and also serves as host to the whole church. Erastus, the city treasurer, sends you his greetings, and so does our brother Quartus.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            16
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How do verses 25, 26, and 27 describe God?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:25]\tNow all glory to God, who is able to make you strong, just as my Good News says. This message about Jesus Christ has revealed his plan for you Gentiles, a plan kept secret from the beginning of time.\n\t[R 16:26]\tBut now as the prophets foretold and as the eternal God has commanded, this message is made known to all Gentiles everywhere, so that they too might believe and obey him.\n\t[R 16:27]\tAll glory to the only wise God, through Jesus Christ, forever. Amen.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 30 points. 3-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 3 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 16. \nHow do verses 25, 26, and 27 describe God?\n\t[R 16:25]\tNow all glory to God, who is able to make you strong, just as my Good News says. This message about Jesus Christ has revealed his plan for you Gentiles, a plan kept secret from the beginning of time.\n\t[R 16:26]\tBut now as the prophets foretold and as the eternal God has commanded, this message is made known to all Gentiles everywhere, so that they too might believe and obey him.\n\t[R 16:27]\tAll glory to the only wise God, through Jesus Christ, forever. Amen.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "salvation is for everyone"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Later, who spoke boldly for God?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 10:20]\tIsaiah\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 10 points. Chapter analysis answer. From the section titled, \"Salvation Is for Everyone\". \nLater, who spoke boldly for God?\n\t[R 10:20]\tIsaiah\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "One chapter contains an omitted verse. Identify this chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t\tRomans 16\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 20 points. Statement and question. From Romans. \nOne chapter contains an omitted verse. Identify this chapter.\n\t\tRomans 16\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The word large is used to describe what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:3]\tWe can make a large horse go wherever we want by means of a small bit in its mouth.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 10 points. From James chapter 3. \nThe word large is used to describe what?\n\t[J 3:3]\tWe can make a large horse go wherever we want by means of a small bit in its mouth.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 4
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who would not be willing to do what and who might be willing to do what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 5:7]\tNow, most people would not be willing to die for an upright person, though someone might perhaps be willing to die for a person who is especially good.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 20 points. 4-Part question. From Romans chapter 5. \nWho would not be willing to do what and who might be willing to do what?\n\t[R 5:7]\tNow, most people would not be willing to die for an upright person, though someone might perhaps be willing to die for a person who is especially good.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "What life is lived in the, quote, \"Holy Spirit?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:17]\tFor the Kingdom of God is not a matter of what we eat or drink, but of living a life of goodness and peace and joy in the Holy Spirit.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 10 points. Scripture text question. 3-Part answer. \nWhat life is lived in the, quote, \"Holy Spirit?\"\n\t[R 14:17]\tFor the Kingdom of God is not a matter of what we eat or drink, but of living a life of goodness and peace and joy in the Holy Spirit.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            3,
            13
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How does Paul complete the two-word phrase, quote, \"requirements of... \"?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:21]\tthe law\n\t[R 13:8]\tGod's law\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 20 points. Scripture text question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 3 and 13. \nHow does Paul complete the two-word phrase, quote, \"requirements of... \"?\n\t[R 3:21]\tthe law\n\t[R 13:8]\tGod's law\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "living to please others"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Christ has accepted whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:7]\tTherefore, accept each other just as Christ has accepted you so that God will be given glory.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 10 points. From the section titled, \"Living to Please Others\". \nChrist has accepted whom?\n\t[R 15:7]\tTherefore, accept each other just as Christ has accepted you so that God will be given glory.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "Romans chapter 9 names which geographical locations?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:29]\tSodom\n\t[R 9:29]\tGomorrah\n\t[R 9:33]\tJerusalem\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 20 points. 3-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses. \nRomans chapter 9 names which geographical locations?\n\t[R 9:29]\tSodom\n\t[R 9:29]\tGomorrah\n\t[R 9:33]\tJerusalem\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "true wisdom comes from god"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What is selfish?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:16]\tFor wherever there is jealousy and selfish ambition, there you will find disorder and evil of every kind.\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. From the section titled, \"True Wisdom Comes from God\". \nWhat is selfish?\n\t[J 3:16]\tFor wherever there is jealousy and selfish ambition, there you will find disorder and evil of every kind.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            8
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of God...?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:9]\tSpirit\n\t[R 8:14]\tchildren\n\t[R 8:39]\tlove\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. Scripture text question. 3-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 8. \nHow does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of God...?\"\n\t[R 8:9]\tSpirit\n\t[R 8:14]\tchildren\n\t[R 8:39]\tlove\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence verses 17, 18, and 19.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:17]\tSo you see, faith by itself isn't enough. Unless it produces good deeds, it is dead and useless.\n\t[J 2:18]\tNow someone may argue, \"Some people have faith; others have good deeds.\" But I say, \"How can you show me your faith if you don't have good deeds? I will show you my faith by my good deeds.\"\n\t[J 2:19]\tYou say you have faith, for you believe that there is one God. Good for you! Even the demons believe this, and they tremble in terror.\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. Essence question. From 3 consecutive verses of James chapter 2. \nGive in essence verses 17, 18, and 19.\n\t[J 2:17]\tSo you see, faith by itself isn't enough. Unless it produces good deeds, it is dead and useless.\n\t[J 2:18]\tNow someone may argue, \"Some people have faith; others have good deeds.\" But I say, \"How can you show me your faith if you don't have good deeds? I will show you my faith by my good deeds.\"\n\t[J 2:19]\tYou say you have faith, for you believe that there is one God. Good for you! Even the demons believe this, and they tremble in terror.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Describe Tertius.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:22]\tI, Tertius, the one writing this letter for Paul, send my greetings, too, as one of the Lord's followers.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 20 points. Give a complete answer. From Romans. \nDescribe Tertius.\n\t[R 16:22]\tI, Tertius, the one writing this letter for Paul, send my greetings, too, as one of the Lord's followers.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's mercy on israel"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What will be, quote, \"even more wonderful?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:15]\tFor since their rejection meant that God offered salvation to the rest of the world, their acceptance will be even more wonderful. It will be life for those who were dead!\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"God's Mercy on Israel\". \nWhat will be, quote, \"even more wonderful?\"\n\t[R 11:15]\tFor since their rejection meant that God offered salvation to the rest of the world, their acceptance will be even more wonderful. It will be life for those who were dead!\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            12
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The possessive word God's is used to describe what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 12:2]\twill\n\t[R 12:13]\tpeople\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 20 points. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 12. \nThe possessive word God's is used to describe what?\n\t[R 12:2]\twill\n\t[R 12:13]\tpeople\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "love fulfills god's requirements"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What will you fulfill if you, quote, \"love your neighbor?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 13:8]\tOwe nothing to anyone- except for your obligation to love one another. If you love your neighbor, you will fulfill the requirements of God's law.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Love Fulfills God's Requirements\". \nWhat will you fulfill if you, quote, \"love your neighbor?\"\n\t[R 13:8]\tOwe nothing to anyone- except for your obligation to love one another. If you love your neighbor, you will fulfill the requirements of God's law.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 9
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "nothing can separate us from god's love"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Paul listed nine things that are unable to separate us from God's love. What were they?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:38]\tAnd I am convinced that nothing can ever separate us from God's love. Neither death nor life, neither angels nor demons, neither our fears for today nor our worries about tomorrow- not even the powers of hell can separate us from God's love.\n\t[R 8:39]\tNo power in the sky above or in the earth below- indeed, nothing in all creation will ever be able to separate us from the love of God that is revealed in Christ Jesus our Lord.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 30 points. Statement and question. 9-Part answer. From 2 consecutive verses of the section titled, \"Nothing Can Separate Us from God's Love\". \nPaul listed nine things that are unable to separate us from God's love. What were they?\n\t[R 8:38]\tAnd I am convinced that nothing can ever separate us from God's love. Neither death nor life, neither angels nor demons, neither our fears for today nor our worries about tomorrow- not even the powers of hell can separate us from God's love.\n\t[R 8:39]\tNo power in the sky above or in the earth below- indeed, nothing in all creation will ever be able to separate us from the love of God that is revealed in Christ Jesus our Lord.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence verses 6, 7, and 8 from the 8th chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:6]\tSo letting your sinful nature control your mind leads to death. But letting the Spirit control your mind leads to life and peace.\n\t[R 8:7]\tFor the sinful nature is always hostile to God. It never did obey God's laws, and it never will.\n\t[R 8:8]\tThat's why those who are still under the control of their sinful nature can never please God.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 20 points. Essence question. From 3 consecutive verses of Romans. \nGive in essence verses 6, 7, and 8 from the 8th chapter.\n\t[R 8:6]\tSo letting your sinful nature control your mind leads to death. But letting the Spirit control your mind leads to life and peace.\n\t[R 8:7]\tFor the sinful nature is always hostile to God. It never did obey God's laws, and it never will.\n\t[R 8:8]\tThat's why those who are still under the control of their sinful nature can never please God.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "drawing close to god"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "You only want what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 4:3]\tAnd even when you ask, you don't get it because your motives are all wrong- you want only what will give you pleasure.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Drawing Close to God\". \nYou only want what?\n\t[J 4:3]\tAnd even when you ask, you don't get it because your motives are all wrong- you want only what will give you pleasure.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "James teaches about the danger of loving money by giving a two-verse illustration about wealth. Give this illustration.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:2]\tYour wealth is rotting away, and your fine clothes are moth-eaten rags.\n\t[J 5:3]\tYour gold and silver are corroded. The very wealth you were counting on will eat away your flesh like fire. This corroded treasure you have hoarded will testify against you on the day of judgment.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 20 points. Statement and question. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of James chapter 5. \nJames teaches about the danger of loving money by giving a two-verse illustration about wealth. Give this illustration.\n\t[J 5:2]\tYour wealth is rotting away, and your fine clothes are moth-eaten rags.\n\t[J 5:3]\tYour gold and silver are corroded. The very wealth you were counting on will eat away your flesh like fire. This corroded treasure you have hoarded will testify against you on the day of judgment.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            14
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Christ rose again to be the Lord of whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:9]\tChrist died and rose again for this very purpose- to be Lord both of the living and of the dead.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 10 points. 2-Part answer. From Romans chapter 14. \nChrist rose again to be the Lord of whom?\n\t[R 14:9]\tChrist died and rose again for this very purpose- to be Lord both of the living and of the dead.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 5
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            2,
            4,
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        },
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            1
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The word Jewish is used to describe what and whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 2:25]\tceremony (of circumcision)\n\t[R 2:28]\tparents\n\t[R 4:1]\tnation\n\t[R 9:3]\tbrothers and sisters\n\t[J 1:1]\tbelievers\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 30 points. 2-Part question. 5-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 2, 4,  and 9 and James chapter 1. \nThe word Jewish is used to describe what and whom?\n\t[R 2:25]\tceremony (of circumcision)\n\t[R 2:28]\tparents\n\t[R 4:1]\tnation\n\t[R 9:3]\tbrothers and sisters\n\t[J 1:1]\tbelievers\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "life in the spirit"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "In fact, what did Paul say?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:17]\tAnd since we are his children, we are his heirs. In fact, together with Christ we are heirs of God's glory. But if we are to share his glory, we must also share his suffering.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Life in the Spirit\". \nIn fact, what did Paul say?\n\t[R 8:17]\tAnd since we are his children, we are his heirs. In fact, together with Christ we are heirs of God's glory. But if we are to share his glory, we must also share his suffering.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "living to please others"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Where did the psalmist say, quote, \"I will praise you?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:9]\tHe also came so that the Gentiles might give glory to God for his mercies to them. That is what the psalmist meant when he wrote: \"For this, I will praise you among the Gentiles; I will sing praises to your name.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Living to Please Others\". \nWhere did the psalmist say, quote, \"I will praise you?\"\n\t[R 15:9]\tHe also came so that the Gentiles might give glory to God for his mercies to them. That is what the psalmist meant when he wrote: \"For this, I will praise you among the Gentiles; I will sing praises to your name.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        },
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence the verse in which Paul speaks of sorrow and the verse in which James speaks of sorrow.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:2]\tMy heart is filled with bitter sorrow and unending grief\n\t[J 4:9]\tLet there be tears for what you have done. Let there be sorrow and deep grief. Let there be sadness instead of laughter, and gloom instead of joy.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 20 points. 2-Part essence question. From separate verses of Romans chapter 9 and James chapter 4. \nGive in essence the verse in which Paul speaks of sorrow and the verse in which James speaks of sorrow.\n\t[R 9:2]\tMy heart is filled with bitter sorrow and unending grief\n\t[J 4:9]\tLet there be tears for what you have done. Let there be sorrow and deep grief. Let there be sadness instead of laughter, and gloom instead of joy.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "controlling the tongue"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "We all make what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:2]\tIndeed, we all make many mistakes. For if we could control our tongues, we would be perfect and could also control ourselves in every other way.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Controlling the Tongue\". \nWe all make what?\n\t[J 3:2]\tIndeed, we all make many mistakes. For if we could control our tongues, we would be perfect and could also control ourselves in every other way.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 4
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Which exclamations are contained?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:3]\tcut off from Christ!\n\t[R 9:5]\tAnd he is God, the one who rules over everything and is worthy of eternal praise!\n\t[R 9:6]\tNo, for not all who are born into the nation of Israel are truly members of God's people!\n\t[R 9:14]\tOf course not!\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 30 points. 4-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 9. \nWhich exclamations are contained?\n\t[R 9:3]\tcut off from Christ!\n\t[R 9:5]\tAnd he is God, the one who rules over everything and is worthy of eternal praise!\n\t[R 9:6]\tNo, for not all who are born into the nation of Israel are truly members of God's people!\n\t[R 9:14]\tOf course not!\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            15
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote the verses in which Spain is mentioned.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:24]\tI am planning to go to Spain, and when I do, I will stop off in Rome. And after I have enjoyed your fellowship for a little while, you can provide for my journey.\n\t[R 15:28]\tAs soon as I have delivered this money and completed this good deed of theirs, I will come to see you on my way to Spain.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 20 points. Quotation question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 15. \nQuote the verses in which Spain is mentioned.\n\t[R 15:24]\tI am planning to go to Spain, and when I do, I will stop off in Rome. And after I have enjoyed your fellowship for a little while, you can provide for my journey.\n\t[R 15:28]\tAs soon as I have delivered this money and completed this good deed of theirs, I will come to see you on my way to Spain.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            8
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What is affirmed?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:16]\tFor his Spirit joins with our spirit to affirm that we are God's children.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 8. \nWhat is affirmed?\n\t[R 8:16]\tFor his Spirit joins with our spirit to affirm that we are God's children.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "warning about self-confidence"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "You ought to say what instead of what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 4:13]\tLook here, you who say, \"Today or tomorrow we are going to a certain town and will stay there a year. We will do business there and make a profit.\"\n\t[J 4:15]\tWhat you ought to say is, \"If the Lord wants us to, we will live and do this or that.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 2 separate verses of the section titled, \"Warning about Self-Confidence\". \nYou ought to say what instead of what?\n\t[J 4:13]\tLook here, you who say, \"Today or tomorrow we are going to a certain town and will stay there a year. We will do business there and make a profit.\"\n\t[J 4:15]\tWhat you ought to say is, \"If the Lord wants us to, we will live and do this or that.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who was a man of, quote, \"great endurance?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:11]\tJob\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Chapter analysis answer. From James chapter 5. \nWho was a man of, quote, \"great endurance?\"\n\t[J 5:11]\tJob\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "One chapter contains no questions. Identify this chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t\tJames 1 \n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 20 points. Statement and question. From James. \nOne chapter contains no questions. Identify this chapter.\n\t\tJames 1 \n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "salvation is for everyone"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The message is on what and in what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 10:8]\tIn fact, it says, \"The message is very close at hand; it is on your lips and in your heart.\" And that message is the very message about faith that we preach:\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Salvation Is for Everyone\". \nThe message is on what and in what?\n\t[R 10:8]\tIn fact, it says, \"The message is very close at hand; it is on your lips and in your heart.\" And that message is the very message about faith that we preach:\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "The unique word snare is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:9]\tLikewise, David said, \"Let their bountiful table become a snare, a trap that makes them think all is well. Let their blessings cause them to stumble, and let them get what they deserve.\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. Statement and 2-Part essence question. \nThe unique word snare is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n\t[R 11:9]\tLikewise, David said, \"Let their bountiful table become a snare, a trap that makes them think all is well. Let their blessings cause them to stumble, and let them get what they deserve.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 6
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        },
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Praise is mentioned in which chapters.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t\tRomans 1, 2, 9, and 15\n\t\tJames 3 and 5\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. 2-Part question. 6-Part answer. From Romans and James. \nPraise is mentioned in which chapters.\n\t\tRomans 1, 2, 9, and 15\n\t\tJames 3 and 5\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's mercy on israel"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who have not found the favor they are looking for?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:7]\tSo this is the situation: Most of the people of Israel have not found the favor of God they are looking for so earnestly. A few have- the ones God has chosen- but the hearts of the rest were hardened.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"God's Mercy on Israel\". \nWho have not found the favor they are looking for?\n\t[R 11:7]\tSo this is the situation: Most of the people of Israel have not found the favor of God they are looking for so earnestly. A few have- the ones God has chosen- but the hearts of the rest were hardened.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            14
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of God...?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:10]\tjudgment seat\n\t[R 14:17]\tKingdom\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 20 points. Scripture text question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 14. \nHow does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of God...?\"\n\t[R 14:10]\tjudgment seat\n\t[R 14:17]\tKingdom\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "paul greets his friends"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Greet each other with what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:16]\tGreet each other with a sacred kiss. All the churches of Christ send you their greetings.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Paul Greets His Friends\". \nGreet each other with what?\n\t[R 16:16]\tGreet each other with a sacred kiss. All the churches of Christ send you their greetings.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "The unique word aim is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:19]\tSo then, let us aim for harmony in the church and try to build each other up.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 20 points. Statement and 2-Part essence question. \nThe unique word aim is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n\t[R 14:19]\tSo then, let us aim for harmony in the church and try to build each other up.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "israel's unbelief"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who never succeeded?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:31]\tBut the people of Israel, who tried so hard to get right with God by keeping the law, never succeeded.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Israel's Unbelief\". \nWho never succeeded?\n\t[R 9:31]\tBut the people of Israel, who tried so hard to get right with God by keeping the law, never succeeded.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 6
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "faith without good deeds is dead"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Which questions are contained?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:14]\tWhat good is it, dear brothers and sisters, if you say you have faith but don't show it by your actions?\n\t[J 2:14]\tCan that kind of faith save anyone?\n\t[J 2:16]\tWhat good does that do?\n\t[J 2:18]\t\"How can you show me your faith if you don't have good deeds?\n\t[J 2:20]\tCan't you see that faith without good deeds is useless?\n\t[J 2:21]\tDon't you remember that our ancestor Abraham was shown to be right with God by his actions when he offered his son Isaac on the altar?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 30 points. 6-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of the section titled, \"Faith without Good Deeds Is Dead\". \nWhich questions are contained?\n\t[J 2:14]\tWhat good is it, dear brothers and sisters, if you say you have faith but don't show it by your actions?\n\t[J 2:14]\tCan that kind of faith save anyone?\n\t[J 2:16]\tWhat good does that do?\n\t[J 2:18]\t\"How can you show me your faith if you don't have good deeds?\n\t[J 2:20]\tCan't you see that faith without good deeds is useless?\n\t[J 2:21]\tDon't you remember that our ancestor Abraham was shown to be right with God by his actions when he offered his son Isaac on the altar?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence verses 15, 16, and 17 from the 10th chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 10:15]\tAnd how will anyone go and tell them without being sent? That is why the Scriptures say, \"How beautiful are the feet of messengers who bring good news!\"\n\t[R 10:16]\tBut not everyone welcomes the Good News, for Isaiah the prophet said, \"LORD, who has believed our message?\"\n\t[R 10:17]\tSo faith comes from hearing, that is, hearing the Good News about Christ.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 20 points. Essence question. From 3 consecutive verses of Romans. \nGive in essence verses 15, 16, and 17 from the 10th chapter.\n\t[R 10:15]\tAnd how will anyone go and tell them without being sent? That is why the Scriptures say, \"How beautiful are the feet of messengers who bring good news!\"\n\t[R 10:16]\tBut not everyone welcomes the Good News, for Isaiah the prophet said, \"LORD, who has believed our message?\"\n\t[R 10:17]\tSo faith comes from hearing, that is, hearing the Good News about Christ.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "life in the spirit"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "God gave whom as a sacrifice for what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:3]\tAnd in that body God declared an end to sin's control over us by giving his Son as a sacrifice for our sins.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 10 points. 2-Part question. Give a Complete Answer. From the section titled, \"Life in the Spirit\". \nGod gave whom as a sacrifice for what?\n\t[R 8:3]\tAnd in that body God declared an end to sin's control over us by giving his Son as a sacrifice for our sins.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "QuotationCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            14
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish this verse and the one that follows, quote, \"Don't tear apart the work... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:20]\tDon't tear apart the work of God over what you eat. Remember, all foods are acceptable, but it is wrong to eat something if it makes another person stumble.\n\t[R 14:21]\tIt is better not to eat meat or drink wine or do anything else if it might cause another believer to stumble.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 20 points. Quotation completion question. From Romans chapter 14. \nFinish this verse and the one that follows, quote, \"Don't tear apart the work... \"\n\t[R 14:20]\tDon't tear apart the work of God over what you eat. Remember, all foods are acceptable, but it is wrong to eat something if it makes another person stumble.\n\t[R 14:21]\tIt is better not to eat meat or drink wine or do anything else if it might cause another believer to stumble.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "patience and endurance"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Why take courage?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:8]\tYou, too, must be patient. Take courage, for the coming of the Lord is near.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Patience and Endurance\". \nWhy take courage?\n\t[J 5:8]\tYou, too, must be patient. Take courage, for the coming of the Lord is near.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Which individuals are named?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:11]\tJob\n\t[J 5:17]\tElijah\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. 2-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of James chapter 5. \nWhich individuals are named?\n\t[J 5:11]\tJob\n\t[J 5:17]\tElijah\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            16
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence the verses that contain the phrase \"fellow Jews\" and the verse that contains the phrase \"fellow Jew.\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:7]\tGreet Andronicus and Junia, my fellow Jews, who were in prison with me. They are highly respected among the apostles and became followers of Christ before I did.\n\t[R 16:21]\tTimothy, my fellow worker, sends you his greetings, as do Lucius, Jason, and Sosipater, my fellow Jews.\n\t[R 16:11]\tGreet Herodion, my fellow Jew. Greet the Lord's people from the household of Narcissus.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 30 points. 2-Part essence question. 3-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 16. \nGive in essence the verses that contain the phrase \"fellow Jews\" and the verse that contains the phrase \"fellow Jew.\"\n\t[R 16:7]\tGreet Andronicus and Junia, my fellow Jews, who were in prison with me. They are highly respected among the apostles and became followers of Christ before I did.\n\t[R 16:21]\tTimothy, my fellow worker, sends you his greetings, as do Lucius, Jason, and Sosipater, my fellow Jews.\n\t[R 16:11]\tGreet Herodion, my fellow Jew. Greet the Lord's people from the household of Narcissus.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The possessive word God's is used to describe what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:2]\tway\n\t[R 4:13]\tpromise\n\t[R 4:13]\tlaw\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 20 points. 3-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 4. \nThe possessive word God's is used to describe what?\n\t[R 4:2]\tway\n\t[R 4:13]\tpromise\n\t[R 4:13]\tlaw\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "faith and endurance"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "To the waves, what does wind do?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 1:6]\tBut when you ask him, be sure that your faith is in God alone. Do not waver, for a person with divided loyalty is as unsettled as a wave of the sea that is blown and tossed by the wind.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 10 points. 2-Part answer. From the section titled, \"Faith and Endurance\". \nTo the waves, what does wind do?\n\t[J 1:6]\tBut when you ask him, be sure that your faith is in God alone. Do not waver, for a person with divided loyalty is as unsettled as a wave of the sea that is blown and tossed by the wind.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            15
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "When can you, quote, \"join together with one voice?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:5]\tMay God, who gives this patience and encouragement, help you live in complete harmony with each other, as is fitting for followers of Christ Jesus.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 20 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 15. \nWhen can you, quote, \"join together with one voice?\"\n\t[R 15:5]\tMay God, who gives this patience and encouragement, help you live in complete harmony with each other, as is fitting for followers of Christ Jesus.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "paul greets his friends"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Help Phoebe how?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:2]\tWelcome her in the Lord as one who is worthy of honor among God's people. Help her in whatever she needs, for she has been helpful to many, and especially to me.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Paul Greets His Friends\". \nHelp Phoebe how?\n\t[R 16:2]\tWelcome her in the Lord as one who is worthy of honor among God's people. Help her in whatever she needs, for she has been helpful to many, and especially to me.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "paul greets his friends"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "About Aquila, what did Paul say?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:3]\tGive my greetings to Priscilla and Aquila, my co-workers in the ministry of Christ Jesus.\n\t[R 16:4]\tIn fact, they once risked their lives for me. I am thankful to them, and so are all the Gentile churches.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 20 points. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of the section titled, \"Paul Greets His Friends\". \nAbout Aquila, what did Paul say?\n\t[R 16:3]\tGive my greetings to Priscilla and Aquila, my co-workers in the ministry of Christ Jesus.\n\t[R 16:4]\tIn fact, they once risked their lives for me. I am thankful to them, and so are all the Gentile churches.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        },
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            1
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Giving birth is mentioned in three verses. Give in essence these verses.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:10]\tThis son was our ancestor Isaac. When he married Rebekah, she gave birth to twins.\n\t[J 1:15]\tThese desires give birth to sinful actions. And when sin is allowed to grow, it gives birth to death.\n\t[J 1:18]\tHe chose to give birth to us by giving us his true word. And we, out of all creation, became his prized possession.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 30 points. Statement and essence question. 3-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 9 and James chapter 1. \nGiving birth is mentioned in three verses. Give in essence these verses.\n\t[R 9:10]\tThis son was our ancestor Isaac. When he married Rebekah, she gave birth to twins.\n\t[J 1:15]\tThese desires give birth to sinful actions. And when sin is allowed to grow, it gives birth to death.\n\t[J 1:18]\tHe chose to give birth to us by giving us his true word. And we, out of all creation, became his prized possession.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part",
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            14
          ],
          "Section": null
        },
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote the verse of Romans that mentions a Kingdom and the verse of James that mentions a Kingdom.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:17]\tFor the Kingdom of God is not a matter of what we eat or drink, but of living a life of goodness and peace and joy in the Holy Spirit.\n\t[J 2:5]\tListen to me, dear brothers and sisters. Hasn't God chosen the poor in this world to be rich in faith? Aren't they the ones who will inherit the Kingdom he promised to those who love him?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 20 points. 2-Part quotation question. From separate verses of Romans chapter 14 and James chapter 2. \nQuote the verse of Romans that mentions a Kingdom and the verse of James that mentions a Kingdom.\n\t[R 14:17]\tFor the Kingdom of God is not a matter of what we eat or drink, but of living a life of goodness and peace and joy in the Holy Spirit.\n\t[J 2:5]\tListen to me, dear brothers and sisters. Hasn't God chosen the poor in this world to be rich in faith? Aren't they the ones who will inherit the Kingdom he promised to those who love him?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "life in the spirit"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What has just requirements?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:4]\tHe did this so that the just requirement of the law would be fully satisfied for us, who no longer follow our sinful nature but instead follow the Spirit.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 10 points. From the section titled, \"Life in the Spirit\". \nWhat has just requirements?\n\t[R 8:4]\tHe did this so that the just requirement of the law would be fully satisfied for us, who no longer follow our sinful nature but instead follow the Spirit.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "love fulfills god's requirements"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Clothe whom with what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 13:14]\tInstead, clothe yourself with the presence of the Lord Jesus Christ. And don't let yourself think about ways to indulge your evil desires.\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. 2-Part question. From the section titled, \"Love Fulfills God's Requirements\". \nClothe whom with what?\n\t[R 13:14]\tInstead, clothe yourself with the presence of the Lord Jesus Christ. And don't let yourself think about ways to indulge your evil desires.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote verses 15 and 16 from the 4th chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 4:15]\tWhat you ought to say is, \"If the Lord wants us to, we will live and do this or that.\"\n\t[J 4:16]\tOtherwise you are boasting about your own pretentious plans, and all such boasting is evil.\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. Quotation question. From 2 consecutive verses of James. \nQuote verses 15 and 16 from the 4th chapter.\n\t[J 4:15]\tWhat you ought to say is, \"If the Lord wants us to, we will live and do this or that.\"\n\t[J 4:16]\tOtherwise you are boasting about your own pretentious plans, and all such boasting is evil.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            4,
            9,
            11
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence the verse that mentions the Jewish nation and the verses that mention the nation of Israel.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:1]\tAbraham was, humanly speaking, the founder of our Jewish nation. What did he discover about being made right with God?\n\t[R 9:6]\tWell then, has God failed to fulfill his promise to Israel? No, for not all who are born into the nation of Israel are truly members of God's people!\n\t[R 11:1]\tI ask, then, has God rejected his own people, the nation of Israel? Of course not! I myself am an Israelite, a descendant of Abraham and a member of the tribe of Benjamin.\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. 2-Part essence question. 3-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 4, 9,  and 11. \nGive in essence the verse that mentions the Jewish nation and the verses that mention the nation of Israel.\n\t[R 4:1]\tAbraham was, humanly speaking, the founder of our Jewish nation. What did he discover about being made right with God?\n\t[R 9:6]\tWell then, has God failed to fulfill his promise to Israel? No, for not all who are born into the nation of Israel are truly members of God's people!\n\t[R 11:1]\tI ask, then, has God rejected his own people, the nation of Israel? Of course not! I myself am an Israelite, a descendant of Abraham and a member of the tribe of Benjamin.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "sin's power is broken"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What was the result of what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 6:20]\tWhen you were slaves to sin, you were free from the obligation to do right.\n\t[R 6:21]\tAnd what was the result? You are now ashamed of the things you used to do, things that end in eternal doom.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of the section titled, \"Sin's Power Is Broken\". \nWhat was the result of what?\n\t[R 6:20]\tWhen you were slaves to sin, you were free from the obligation to do right.\n\t[R 6:21]\tAnd what was the result? You are now ashamed of the things you used to do, things that end in eternal doom.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "true wisdom comes from god"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "About jealousy, what did James say?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:14]\tBut if you are bitterly jealous and there is selfish ambition in your heart, don't cover up the truth with boasting and lying.\n\t[J 3:15]\tFor jealousy and selfishness are not God's kind of wisdom. Such things are earthly, unspiritual, and demonic.\n\t[J 3:16]\tFor wherever there is jealousy and selfish ambition, there you will find disorder and evil of every kind.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 30 points. Give a complete answer. From 3 consecutive verses of the section titled, \"True Wisdom Comes from God\". \nAbout jealousy, what did James say?\n\t[J 3:14]\tBut if you are bitterly jealous and there is selfish ambition in your heart, don't cover up the truth with boasting and lying.\n\t[J 3:15]\tFor jealousy and selfishness are not God's kind of wisdom. Such things are earthly, unspiritual, and demonic.\n\t[J 3:16]\tFor wherever there is jealousy and selfish ambition, there you will find disorder and evil of every kind.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The 23rd verse names which individual?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:23]\tAbraham\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 10 points. Chapter analysis answer. From James chapter 2. \nThe 23rd verse names which individual?\n\t[J 2:23]\tAbraham\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "The unique word sentence is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:28]\tFor the LORD will carry out his sentence upon the earth quickly and with finality.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 20 points. Statement and 2-Part essence question. \nThe unique word sentence is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n\t[R 9:28]\tFor the LORD will carry out his sentence upon the earth quickly and with finality.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "warning about self-confidence"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "If the Lord wants us to, what will we do?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 4:15]\tWhat you ought to say is, \"If the Lord wants us to, we will live and do this or that.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 10 points. 2-Part answer. From the section titled, \"Warning about Self-Confidence\". \nIf the Lord wants us to, what will we do?\n\t[J 4:15]\tWhat you ought to say is, \"If the Lord wants us to, we will live and do this or that.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of God...?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:2]\twhole revelation\n\t[R 3:18]\tfear\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 20 points. Scripture text question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 3. \nHow does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of God...?\"\n\t[R 3:2]\twhole revelation\n\t[R 3:18]\tfear\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "a warning against prejudice"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Discrimination shows what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:4]\tdoesn't this discrimination show that your judgments are guided by evil motives?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"A Warning against Prejudice\". \nDiscrimination shows what?\n\t[J 2:4]\tdoesn't this discrimination show that your judgments are guided by evil motives?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            2,
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "In three verses. Paul refers to the Gentiles as uncircumcised. Give in essence these verses.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 2:25]\tThe Jewish ceremony of circumcision has value only if you obey God's law. But if you don't obey God's law, you are no better off than an uncircumcised Gentile.\n\t[R 2:27]\tIn fact, uncircumcised Gentiles who keep God's law will condemn you Jews who are circumcised and possess God's law but don't obey it.\n\t[R 4:9]\tNow, is this blessing only for the Jews, or is it also for uncircumcised Gentiles? Well, we have been saying that Abraham was counted as righteous by God because of his faith.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 30 points. Statement and essence question. 3-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 2 and 4. \nIn three verses. Paul refers to the Gentiles as uncircumcised. Give in essence these verses.\n\t[R 2:25]\tThe Jewish ceremony of circumcision has value only if you obey God's law. But if you don't obey God's law, you are no better off than an uncircumcised Gentile.\n\t[R 2:27]\tIn fact, uncircumcised Gentiles who keep God's law will condemn you Jews who are circumcised and possess God's law but don't obey it.\n\t[R 4:9]\tNow, is this blessing only for the Jews, or is it also for uncircumcised Gentiles? Well, we have been saying that Abraham was counted as righteous by God because of his faith.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 4
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "James chapter 2 contains which Old Testament Scriptures?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:8]\t\"Love your neighbor as yourself.\"\n\t[J 2:11]\t\"You must not commit adultery,\"\n\t[J 2:11]\t\"You must not murder.\"\n\t[J 2:23]\t\"Abraham believed God, and God counted him as righteous because of his faith.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 20 points. 4-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses. \nJames chapter 2 contains which Old Testament Scriptures?\n\t[J 2:8]\t\"Love your neighbor as yourself.\"\n\t[J 2:11]\t\"You must not commit adultery,\"\n\t[J 2:11]\t\"You must not murder.\"\n\t[J 2:23]\t\"Abraham believed God, and God counted him as righteous because of his faith.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "adam and christ contrasted"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What brought, quote, \"death to many\"?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 5:15]\tBut there is a great difference between Adam's sin and God's gracious gift. For the sin of this one man, Adam, brought death to many. But even greater is God's wonderful grace and his gift of forgiveness to many through this other man, Jesus Christ.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 10 points. Scripture Text Question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Adam and Christ Contrasted\". \nWhat brought, quote, \"death to many\"?\n\t[R 5:15]\tBut there is a great difference between Adam's sin and God's gracious gift. For the sin of this one man, Adam, brought death to many. But even greater is God's wonderful grace and his gift of forgiveness to many through this other man, Jesus Christ.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            13
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote verses 9 and 10.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 13:9]\tFor the commandments say, \"You must not commit adultery. You must not murder. You must not steal. You must not covet.\" These- and other such commandments- are summed up in this one commandment: \"Love your neighbor as yourself.\"\n\t[R 13:10]\tLove does no wrong to others, so love fulfills the requirements of God's law.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. Quotation question. From 2 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 13. \nQuote verses 9 and 10.\n\t[R 13:9]\tFor the commandments say, \"You must not commit adultery. You must not murder. You must not steal. You must not covet.\" These- and other such commandments- are summed up in this one commandment: \"Love your neighbor as yourself.\"\n\t[R 13:10]\tLove does no wrong to others, so love fulfills the requirements of God's law.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "paul greets his friends"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Greet whom with what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:16]\tGreet each other with a sacred kiss. All the churches of Christ send you their greetings.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 10 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Paul Greets His Friends\". \nGreet whom with what?\n\t[R 16:16]\tGreet each other with a sacred kiss. All the churches of Christ send you their greetings.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            1,
            6,
            7
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "In three verses. Paul thanked God. Give in essence these verses.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:8]\tLet me say first that I thank my God through Jesus Christ for all of you, because your faith in him is being talked about all over the world.\n\t[R 6:17]\tThank God! Once you were slaves of sin, but now you wholeheartedly obey this teaching we have given you.\n\t[R 7:25]\tThank God! The answer is in Jesus Christ our Lord. So you see how it is: In my mind I really want to obey God's law, but because of my sinful nature I am a slave to sin.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 30 points. Statement and essence question. 3-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 1, 6,  and 7. \nIn three verses. Paul thanked God. Give in essence these verses.\n\t[R 1:8]\tLet me say first that I thank my God through Jesus Christ for all of you, because your faith in him is being talked about all over the world.\n\t[R 6:17]\tThank God! Once you were slaves of sin, but now you wholeheartedly obey this teaching we have given you.\n\t[R 7:25]\tThank God! The answer is in Jesus Christ our Lord. So you see how it is: In my mind I really want to obey God's law, but because of my sinful nature I am a slave to sin.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "EssenceCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            12
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish in essence this verse and the two that follow, quote, \"Rejoice in our confident... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 12:12]\tRejoice in our confident hope. Be patient in trouble, and keep on praying.\n\t[R 12:13]\tWhen God's people are in need, be ready to help them. Always be eager to practice hospitality.\n\t[R 12:14]\tBless those who persecute you. Don't curse them; pray that God will bless them.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 20 points. Essence completion question. From Romans chapter 12. \nFinish in essence this verse and the two that follow, quote, \"Rejoice in our confident... \"\n\t[R 12:12]\tRejoice in our confident hope. Be patient in trouble, and keep on praying.\n\t[R 12:13]\tWhen God's people are in need, be ready to help them. Always be eager to practice hospitality.\n\t[R 12:14]\tBless those who persecute you. Don't curse them; pray that God will bless them.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "sin's power is broken"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Eternal life is through whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 6:23]\tFor the wages of sin is death, but the free gift of God is eternal life through Christ Jesus our Lord.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Sin's Power Is Broken\". \nEternal life is through whom?\n\t[R 6:23]\tFor the wages of sin is death, but the free gift of God is eternal life through Christ Jesus our Lord.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "About Gomorrah, what did Paul say?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:29]\tAnd Isaiah said the same thing in another place: \" If the LORD of Heaven's Armies had not spared a few of our children, we would have been wiped out like Sodom, destroyed like Gomorrah.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 20 points. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 9. \nAbout Gomorrah, what did Paul say?\n\t[R 9:29]\tAnd Isaiah said the same thing in another place: \" If the LORD of Heaven's Armies had not spared a few of our children, we would have been wiped out like Sodom, destroyed like Gomorrah.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            12
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What are heaped, where?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 12:20]\tInstead, \"If your enemies are hungry, feed them. If they are thirsty, give them something to drink. In doing this, you will heap burning coals of shame on their heads.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 10 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 12. \nWhat are heaped, where?\n\t[R 12:20]\tInstead, \"If your enemies are hungry, feed them. If they are thirsty, give them something to drink. In doing this, you will heap burning coals of shame on their heads.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "Romans chapter 12 contains which exclamation and which Old Testament Scriptures?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 12:16]\tAnd don't think you know it all!\n\t[R 12:19]\t\"I will take revenge; I will pay them back,\"\n\t[R 12:20]\t\"If your enemies are hungry, feed them. If they are thirsty, give them something to drink. In doing this, you will heap burning coals of shame on their heads.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 20 points. 2-Part question. 3-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses. \nRomans chapter 12 contains which exclamation and which Old Testament Scriptures?\n\t[R 12:16]\tAnd don't think you know it all!\n\t[R 12:19]\t\"I will take revenge; I will pay them back,\"\n\t[R 12:20]\t\"If your enemies are hungry, feed them. If they are thirsty, give them something to drink. In doing this, you will heap burning coals of shame on their heads.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            1
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How did God choose to, quote, \"give birth to us?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 1:18]\tHe chose to give birth to us by giving us his true word. And we, out of all creation, became his prized possession.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From James chapter 1. \nHow did God choose to, quote, \"give birth to us?\"\n\t[J 1:18]\tHe chose to give birth to us by giving us his true word. And we, out of all creation, became his prized possession.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "When the Gentiles sin, what happens?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 2:12]\tWhen the Gentiles sin, they will be destroyed, even though they never had God's written law. And the Jews, who do have God's law, will be judged by that law when they fail to obey it.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 20 points. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 2. \nWhen the Gentiles sin, what happens?\n\t[R 2:12]\tWhen the Gentiles sin, they will be destroyed, even though they never had God's written law. And the Jews, who do have God's law, will be judged by that law when they fail to obey it.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "living to please others"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "We wait patiently for what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:4]\tSuch things were written in the Scriptures long ago to teach us. And the Scriptures give us hope and encouragement as we wait patiently for God's promises to be fulfilled.\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Living to Please Others\". \nWe wait patiently for what?\n\t[R 15:4]\tSuch things were written in the Scriptures long ago to teach us. And the Scriptures give us hope and encouragement as we wait patiently for God's promises to be fulfilled.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Even when there was no hope, what did Abraham do and why?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:18]\tEven when there was no reason for hope, Abraham kept hoping- believing that he would become the father of many nations. For God had said to him, \"That's how many descendants you will have!\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 4. \nEven when there was no hope, what did Abraham do and why?\n\t[R 4:18]\tEven when there was no reason for hope, Abraham kept hoping- believing that he would become the father of many nations. For God had said to him, \"That's how many descendants you will have!\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            11
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Two consecutive verses name Abraham. Quote these verses.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:16]\tAnd since Abraham and the other patriarchs were holy, their descendants will also be holy- just as the entire batch of dough is holy because the portion given as an offering is holy. For if the roots of the tree are holy, the branches will be, too.\n\t[R 11:17]\tBut some of these branches from Abraham's tree- some of the people of Israel- have been broken off. And you Gentiles, who were branches from a wild olive tree, have been grafted in. So now you also receive the blessing God has promised Abraham and his children, sharing in the rich nourishment from the root of God's special olive tree.\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. Statement and quotation question. 2-Part answer. From consecutive verses of Romans chapter 11. \nTwo consecutive verses name Abraham. Quote these verses.\n\t[R 11:16]\tAnd since Abraham and the other patriarchs were holy, their descendants will also be holy- just as the entire batch of dough is holy because the portion given as an offering is holy. For if the roots of the tree are holy, the branches will be, too.\n\t[R 11:17]\tBut some of these branches from Abraham's tree- some of the people of Israel- have been broken off. And you Gentiles, who were branches from a wild olive tree, have been grafted in. So now you also receive the blessing God has promised Abraham and his children, sharing in the rich nourishment from the root of God's special olive tree.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            10
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How does Paul complete the two-word phrase, quote, \"time of...?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 10:19]\tMoses\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Chapter analysis answer. From Romans chapter 10. \nHow does Paul complete the two-word phrase, quote, \"time of...?\"\n\t[R 10:19]\tMoses\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            10
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote the verses in which Isaiah is named.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 10:16]\tBut not everyone welcomes the Good News, for Isaiah the prophet said, \"LORD, who has believed our message?\"\n\t[R 10:20]\tAnd later Isaiah spoke boldly for God, saying, \"I was found by people who were not looking for me. I showed myself to those who were not asking for me.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 20 points. Quotation question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 10. \nQuote the verses in which Isaiah is named.\n\t[R 10:16]\tBut not everyone welcomes the Good News, for Isaiah the prophet said, \"LORD, who has believed our message?\"\n\t[R 10:20]\tAnd later Isaiah spoke boldly for God, saying, \"I was found by people who were not looking for me. I showed myself to those who were not asking for me.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            3,
            13
          ],
          "Section": null
        },
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Three Old Testament Scriptures mention murder. Give these Old Testament Scriptures.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:15-17]\t\"They rush to commit murder. Destruction and misery always follow them. They don't know where to find peace.\"\n\t[R 13:9]\tYou must not murder.\n\t[J 2:11]\t\"You must not murder.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 30 points. Statement and question. 3-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 3 and 13 and James chapter 2. \nThree Old Testament Scriptures mention murder. Give these Old Testament Scriptures.\n\t[R 3:15-17]\t\"They rush to commit murder. Destruction and misery always follow them. They don't know where to find peace.\"\n\t[R 13:9]\tYou must not murder.\n\t[J 2:11]\t\"You must not murder.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part",
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            11
          ],
          "Section": null
        },
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote the verse that contains the phrase entire batch and the verse that contains the phrase entire body.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:16]\tAnd since Abraham and the other patriarchs were holy, their descendants will also be holy- just as the entire batch of dough is holy because the portion given as an offering is holy. For if the roots of the tree are holy, the branches will be, too.\n\t[J 3:6]\tAnd among all the parts of the body, the tongue is a flame of fire. It is a whole world of wickedness, corrupting your entire body. It can set your whole life on fire, for it is set on fire by hell itself.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 20 points. 2-Part quotation question. From separate verses of Romans chapter 11 and James chapter 3. \nQuote the verse that contains the phrase entire batch and the verse that contains the phrase entire body.\n\t[R 11:16]\tAnd since Abraham and the other patriarchs were holy, their descendants will also be holy- just as the entire batch of dough is holy because the portion given as an offering is holy. For if the roots of the tree are holy, the branches will be, too.\n\t[J 3:6]\tAnd among all the parts of the body, the tongue is a flame of fire. It is a whole world of wickedness, corrupting your entire body. It can set your whole life on fire, for it is set on fire by hell itself.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's judgment of sin"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Merely listening to the law doesn't make us right with whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 2:13]\tFor merely listening to the law doesn't make us right with God. It is obeying the law that makes us right in his sight.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 10 points. From the section titled, \"God's Judgment of Sin\". \nMerely listening to the law doesn't make us right with whom?\n\t[R 2:13]\tFor merely listening to the law doesn't make us right with God. It is obeying the law that makes us right in his sight.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 4
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence verses 2, 3, 4, and 5 from the opening chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 1:2]\tDear brothers and sisters, when troubles of any kind come your way, consider it an opportunity for great joy.\n\t[J 1:3]\tFor you know that when your faith is tested, your endurance has a chance to grow.\n\t[J 1:4]\tSo let it grow, for when your endurance is fully developed, you will be perfect and complete, needing nothing.\n\t[J 1:5]\tIf you need wisdom, ask our generous God, and he will give it to you. He will not rebuke you for asking.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 30 points. Essence question. From 4 consecutive verses of James. \nGive in essence verses 2, 3, 4, and 5 from the opening chapter.\n\t[J 1:2]\tDear brothers and sisters, when troubles of any kind come your way, consider it an opportunity for great joy.\n\t[J 1:3]\tFor you know that when your faith is tested, your endurance has a chance to grow.\n\t[J 1:4]\tSo let it grow, for when your endurance is fully developed, you will be perfect and complete, needing nothing.\n\t[J 1:5]\tIf you need wisdom, ask our generous God, and he will give it to you. He will not rebuke you for asking.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "EssenceCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's law reveals our sin"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish in essence this verse and the two that follow, quote, \"At one time I lived... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 7:9]\tAt one time I lived without understanding the law. But when I learned the command not to covet, for instance, the power of sin came to life,\n\t[R 7:10]\tand I died. So I discovered that the law's commands, which were supposed to bring life, brought spiritual death instead.\n\t[R 7:11]\tSin took advantage of those commands and deceived me; it used the commands to kill me.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 20 points. Essence completion question. From the section titled, \"God's Law Reveals Our Sin\". \nFinish in essence this verse and the two that follow, quote, \"At one time I lived... \"\n\t[R 7:9]\tAt one time I lived without understanding the law. But when I learned the command not to covet, for instance, the power of sin came to life,\n\t[R 7:10]\tand I died. So I discovered that the law's commands, which were supposed to bring life, brought spiritual death instead.\n\t[R 7:11]\tSin took advantage of those commands and deceived me; it used the commands to kill me.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "salvation is for everyone"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Openly declare what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 10:10]\tFor it is by believing in your heart that you are made right with God, and it is by openly declaring your faith that you are saved.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 10 points. Give a Complete Answer. From the section titled, \"Salvation Is for Everyone\". \nOpenly declare what?\n\t[R 10:10]\tFor it is by believing in your heart that you are made right with God, and it is by openly declaring your faith that you are saved.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "true wisdom comes from god"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote the closing two verses.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:17]\tBut the wisdom from above is first of all pure. It is also peace loving, gentle at all times, and willing to yield to others. It is full of mercy and the fruit of good deeds. It shows no favoritism and is always sincere.\n\t[J 3:18]\tAnd those who are peacemakers will plant seeds of peace and reap a harvest of righteousness.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 20 points. Quotation question. From 2 consecutive verses of the section titled, \"True Wisdom Comes from God\". \nQuote the closing two verses.\n\t[J 3:17]\tBut the wisdom from above is first of all pure. It is also peace loving, gentle at all times, and willing to yield to others. It is full of mercy and the fruit of good deeds. It shows no favoritism and is always sincere.\n\t[J 3:18]\tAnd those who are peacemakers will plant seeds of peace and reap a harvest of righteousness.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "respect for authority"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What should you pay to, quote, \"those who collect them?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 13:7]\tGive to everyone what you owe them: Pay your taxes and government fees to those who collect them, and give respect and honor to those who are in authority.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 10 points. Scripture Text question. Give 2 complete answers. From the section titled, \"Respect for Authority\". \nWhat should you pay to, quote, \"those who collect them?\"\n\t[R 13:7]\tGive to everyone what you owe them: Pay your taxes and government fees to those who collect them, and give respect and honor to those who are in authority.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part",
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote the verse in which Sarah is named and the verse in which Rebekah is named.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:9]\tFor God had promised, \"I will return about this time next year, and Sarah will have a son.\"\n\t[R 9:10]\tThis son was our ancestor Isaac. When he married Rebekah, she gave birth to twins.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. 2-Part quotation question. From 2 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 9. \nQuote the verse in which Sarah is named and the verse in which Rebekah is named.\n\t[R 9:9]\tFor God had promised, \"I will return about this time next year, and Sarah will have a son.\"\n\t[R 9:10]\tThis son was our ancestor Isaac. When he married Rebekah, she gave birth to twins.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "sin's power is broken"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence the three verses that say we died, quote, \"with Christ.\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 6:4]\tFor we died and were buried with Christ by baptism. And just as Christ was raised from the dead by the glorious power of the Father, now we also may live new lives.\n\t[R 6:7]\tFor when we died with Christ we were set free from the power of sin.\n\t[R 6:8]\tAnd since we died with Christ, we know we will also live with him.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 30 points. Scripture text essence question. 3-Part answer. From separate verses of the section titled, \"Sin's Power Is Broken\". \nGive in essence the three verses that say we died, quote, \"with Christ.\"\n\t[R 6:4]\tFor we died and were buried with Christ by baptism. And just as Christ was raised from the dead by the glorious power of the Father, now we also may live new lives.\n\t[R 6:7]\tFor when we died with Christ we were set free from the power of sin.\n\t[R 6:8]\tAnd since we died with Christ, we know we will also live with him.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "controlling the tongue"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "A huge ship turns where?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:4]\tAnd a small rudder makes a huge ship turn wherever the pilot chooses to go, even though the winds are strong.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Controlling the Tongue\". \nA huge ship turns where?\n\t[J 3:4]\tAnd a small rudder makes a huge ship turn wherever the pilot chooses to go, even though the winds are strong.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "salvation is for everyone"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Later, Isaiah did what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 10:20]\tAnd later Isaiah spoke boldly for God, saying, \"I was found by people who were not looking for me. I showed myself to those who were not asking for me.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 20 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Salvation Is for Everyone\". \nLater, Isaiah did what?\n\t[R 10:20]\tAnd later Isaiah spoke boldly for God, saying, \"I was found by people who were not looking for me. I showed myself to those who were not asking for me.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "a living sacrifice to god"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Don't think you are better than what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 12:3]\tBecause of the privilege and authority God has given me, I give each of you this warning: Don't think you are better than you really are. Be honest in your evaluation of yourselves, measuring yourselves by the faith God has given us.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"A Living Sacrifice to God\". \nDon't think you are better than what?\n\t[R 12:3]\tBecause of the privilege and authority God has given me, I give each of you this warning: Don't think you are better than you really are. Be honest in your evaluation of yourselves, measuring yourselves by the faith God has given us.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "QuotationCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            11
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish this verse and the one that follows, quote, \"\"LORD, they have killed... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:3]\t\"LORD, they have killed your prophets and torn down your altars. I am the only one left, and now they are trying to kill me, too.\"\n\t[R 11:4]\tAnd do you remember God's reply? He said, \"No, I have 7,000 others who have never bowed down to Baal!\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 20 points. Quotation completion question. From Romans chapter 11. \nFinish this verse and the one that follows, quote, \"\"LORD, they have killed... \"\n\t[R 11:3]\t\"LORD, they have killed your prophets and torn down your altars. I am the only one left, and now they are trying to kill me, too.\"\n\t[R 11:4]\tAnd do you remember God's reply? He said, \"No, I have 7,000 others who have never bowed down to Baal!\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "sin's power is broken"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What end in eternal doom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 6:21]\tAnd what was the result? You are now ashamed of the things you used to do, things that end in eternal doom.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Sin's Power Is Broken\". \nWhat end in eternal doom?\n\t[R 6:21]\tAnd what was the result? You are now ashamed of the things you used to do, things that end in eternal doom.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            8
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "To which questions did Paul answer, quote, \"No one\"?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:33]\tWho dares accuse us whom God has chosen for his own?\n\t[R 8:34]\tWho then will condemn us?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 20 points. Scripture text question. 2-Part chapter analysis answer. From consecutive verses of Romans chapter 8. \nTo which questions did Paul answer, quote, \"No one\"?\n\t[R 8:33]\tWho dares accuse us whom God has chosen for his own?\n\t[R 8:34]\tWho then will condemn us?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's mercy is for everyone"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Why has God imprisoned, quote, \"everyone in disobedience?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:32]\tFor God has imprisoned everyone in disobedience so he could have mercy on everyone.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"God's Mercy Is for Everyone\". \nWhy has God imprisoned, quote, \"everyone in disobedience?\"\n\t[R 11:32]\tFor God has imprisoned everyone in disobedience so he could have mercy on everyone.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            6
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "To which questions did Paul exclaim, quote, \"Of Course not!\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 6:1]\tWell then, should we keep on sinning so that God can show us more and more of his wonderful grace?\n\t[R 6:15]\tWell then, since God's grace has set us free from the law, does that mean we can go on sinning?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 20 points. Scripture text question. 2-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 6. \nTo which questions did Paul exclaim, quote, \"Of Course not!\"\n\t[R 6:1]\tWell then, should we keep on sinning so that God can show us more and more of his wonderful grace?\n\t[R 6:15]\tWell then, since God's grace has set us free from the law, does that mean we can go on sinning?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "In the 10th verse, how does James address his readers?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:10]\tAnd so blessing and cursing come pouring out of the same mouth. Surely, my brothers and sisters, this is not right!\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. Give a complete answer. From James chapter 3. \nIn the 10th verse, how does James address his readers?\n\t[J 3:10]\tAnd so blessing and cursing come pouring out of the same mouth. Surely, my brothers and sisters, this is not right!\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "The unique word money is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:28]\tAs soon as I have delivered this money and completed this good deed of theirs, I will come to see you on my way to Spain.\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. Statement and 2-Part essence question. \nThe unique word money is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n\t[R 15:28]\tAs soon as I have delivered this money and completed this good deed of theirs, I will come to see you on my way to Spain.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            3,
            14
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give the Old Testament Scriptures in which tongues are mentioned.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:13]\t\"Their talk is foul, like the stench from an open grave. Their tongues are filled with lies.\"\n\t[R 14:11]\t\"'As surely as I live,' says the LORD, 'every knee will bend to me, and every tongue will declare allegiance to God.'\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. 2-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 3 and 14. \nGive the Old Testament Scriptures in which tongues are mentioned.\n\t[R 3:13]\t\"Their talk is foul, like the stench from an open grave. Their tongues are filled with lies.\"\n\t[R 14:11]\t\"'As surely as I live,' says the LORD, 'every knee will bend to me, and every tongue will declare allegiance to God.'\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of Christ?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 5:9]\tblood\n\t[R 5:14]\trepresentation\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 20 points. Scripture text question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 5. \nHow does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of Christ?\"\n\t[R 5:9]\tblood\n\t[R 5:14]\trepresentation\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            12
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "In the 19th verse, how does Paul address his readers?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 12:19]\tDear friends \n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 12. \nIn the 19th verse, how does Paul address his readers?\n\t[R 12:19]\tDear friends \n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "David said what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:7]\t\"Oh, what joy for those whose disobedience is forgiven, whose sins are put out of sight.\n\t[R 4:8]\tYes, what joy for those whose record the LORD has cleared of sin.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 20 points. Chapter analysis answer. From consecutive verses of Romans chapter 4. \nDavid said what?\n\t[R 4:7]\t\"Oh, what joy for those whose disobedience is forgiven, whose sins are put out of sight.\n\t[R 4:8]\tYes, what joy for those whose record the LORD has cleared of sin.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "paul's travel plans"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Christ will richly bless what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:29]\tAnd I am sure that when I come, Christ will richly bless our time together.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Paul's Travel Plans\". \nChrist will richly bless what?\n\t[R 15:29]\tAnd I am sure that when I come, Christ will richly bless our time together.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 6
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "sin's power is broken"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Which questions are contained?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 6:1]\tWell then, should we keep on sinning so that God can show us more and more of his wonderful grace?\n\t[R 6:2]\tSince we have died to sin, how can we continue to live in it?\n\t[R 6:3]\tOr have you forgotten that when we were joined with Christ Jesus in baptism, we joined him in his death?\n\t[R 6:15]\tWell then, since God's grace has set us free from the law, does that mean we can go on sinning?\n\t[R 6:16]\tDon't you realize that you become the slave of whatever you choose to obey?\n\t[R 6:21]\tAnd what was the result?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 30 points. 6-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of the section titled, \"Sin's Power Is Broken\". \nWhich questions are contained?\n\t[R 6:1]\tWell then, should we keep on sinning so that God can show us more and more of his wonderful grace?\n\t[R 6:2]\tSince we have died to sin, how can we continue to live in it?\n\t[R 6:3]\tOr have you forgotten that when we were joined with Christ Jesus in baptism, we joined him in his death?\n\t[R 6:15]\tWell then, since God's grace has set us free from the law, does that mean we can go on sinning?\n\t[R 6:16]\tDon't you realize that you become the slave of whatever you choose to obey?\n\t[R 6:21]\tAnd what was the result?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote verses 22 and 23 from the 6th chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 6:22]\tBut now you are free from the power of sin and have become slaves of God. Now you do those things that lead to holiness and result in eternal life.\n\t[R 6:23]\tFor the wages of sin is death, but the free gift of God is eternal life through Christ Jesus our Lord.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 20 points. Quotation question. From 2 consecutive verses of Romans. \nQuote verses 22 and 23 from the 6th chapter.\n\t[R 6:22]\tBut now you are free from the power of sin and have become slaves of God. Now you do those things that lead to holiness and result in eternal life.\n\t[R 6:23]\tFor the wages of sin is death, but the free gift of God is eternal life through Christ Jesus our Lord.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Concerning cutting, which exclamation is contained?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:3]\tcut off from Christ!\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 10 points. Chapter analysis answer. From Romans chapter 9. \nConcerning cutting, which exclamation is contained?\n\t[R 9:3]\tcut off from Christ!\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part",
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "greetings from paul"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "May who give whom, quote, \"grace and peace?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:7]\tI am writing to all of you in Rome who are loved by God and are called to be his own holy people. May God our Father and the Lord Jesus Christ give you grace and peace.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 20 points. 2-Part scripture text question. Give 3 complete answers. From the section titled, \"Greetings from Paul\". \nMay who give whom, quote, \"grace and peace?\"\n\t[R 1:7]\tI am writing to all of you in Rome who are loved by God and are called to be his own holy people. May God our Father and the Lord Jesus Christ give you grace and peace.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "According to the 11th verse, no one is what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:11]\tNo one is truly wise; no one is seeking God.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 10 points. Give 2 complete answers. From Romans chapter 3. \nAccording to the 11th verse, no one is what?\n\t[R 3:11]\tNo one is truly wise; no one is seeking God.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 6
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Which questions are contained?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 4:1]\tWhat is causing the quarrels and fights among you?\n\t[J 4:1]\tDon't they come from the evil desires at war within you?\n\t[J 4:4]\tDon't you realize that friendship with the world makes you an enemy of God?\n\t[J 4:5]\tDo you think the Scriptures have no meaning?\n\t[J 4:12]\tSo what right do you have to judge your neighbor?\n\t[J 4:14]\tHow do you know what your life will be like tomorrow?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 30 points. 6-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of James chapter 4. \nWhich questions are contained?\n\t[J 4:1]\tWhat is causing the quarrels and fights among you?\n\t[J 4:1]\tDon't they come from the evil desires at war within you?\n\t[J 4:4]\tDon't you realize that friendship with the world makes you an enemy of God?\n\t[J 4:5]\tDo you think the Scriptures have no meaning?\n\t[J 4:12]\tSo what right do you have to judge your neighbor?\n\t[J 4:14]\tHow do you know what your life will be like tomorrow?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's anger at sin"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Why did Paul say that sinful people had no excuse for, quote, \"not knowing God?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:19]\tThey know the truth about God because he has made it obvious to them.\n\t[R 1:20]\tFor ever since the world was created, people have seen the earth and sky. Through everything God made, they can clearly see his invisible qualities- his eternal power and divine nature. So they have no excuse for not knowing God.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of the section titled, \"God's Anger at Sin\". \nWhy did Paul say that sinful people had no excuse for, quote, \"not knowing God?\"\n\t[R 1:19]\tThey know the truth about God because he has made it obvious to them.\n\t[R 1:20]\tFor ever since the world was created, people have seen the earth and sky. Through everything God made, they can clearly see his invisible qualities- his eternal power and divine nature. So they have no excuse for not knowing God.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "What did James say to do if you are quote, \"suffering hardships?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:13]\tAre any of you suffering hardships? You should pray. Are any of you happy? You should sing praises.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. \nWhat did James say to do if you are quote, \"suffering hardships?\"\n\t[J 5:13]\tAre any of you suffering hardships? You should pray. Are any of you happy? You should sing praises.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            12
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Leave what to what and why?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 12:19]\tDear friends, never take revenge. Leave that to the righteous anger of God. For the Scriptures say, \"I will take revenge; I will pay them back,\" says the LORD.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 20 points. 3-Part question. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 12. \nLeave what to what and why?\n\t[R 12:19]\tDear friends, never take revenge. Leave that to the righteous anger of God. For the Scriptures say, \"I will take revenge; I will pay them back,\" says the LORD.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "sin's power is broken"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "We have been united with whom in what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 6:5]\tSince we have been united with him in his death, we will also be raised to life as he was.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 10 points. 2-Part question. From the section titled, \"Sin's Power Is Broken\". \nWe have been united with whom in what?\n\t[R 6:5]\tSince we have been united with him in his death, we will also be raised to life as he was.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How do verses 16 and 17 describe Abraham?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:16]\tSo the promise is received by faith. It is given as a free gift. And we are all certain to receive it, whether or not we live according to the law of Moses, if we have faith like Abraham's. For Abraham is the father of all who believe.\n\t[R 4:17]\tThat is what the Scriptures mean when God told him, \"I have made you the father of many nations.\" This happened because Abraham believed in the God who brings the dead back to life and who creates new things out of nothing.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 30 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 4. \nHow do verses 16 and 17 describe Abraham?\n\t[R 4:16]\tSo the promise is received by faith. It is given as a free gift. And we are all certain to receive it, whether or not we live according to the law of Moses, if we have faith like Abraham's. For Abraham is the father of all who believe.\n\t[R 4:17]\tThat is what the Scriptures mean when God told him, \"I have made you the father of many nations.\" This happened because Abraham believed in the God who brings the dead back to life and who creates new things out of nothing.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            15
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The possessive word God's is used to describe what and whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:4]\tpromises\n\t[R 15:15]\tgrace\n\t[R 15:19]\tSpirit\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 20 points. 2-Part question. 3-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 15. \nThe possessive word God's is used to describe what and whom?\n\t[R 15:4]\tpromises\n\t[R 15:15]\tgrace\n\t[R 15:19]\tSpirit\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            15
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who gives patience and encouragement?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:5]\tMay God, who gives this patience and encouragement, help you live in complete harmony with each other, as is fitting for followers of Christ Jesus.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 10 points. From Romans chapter 15. \nWho gives patience and encouragement?\n\t[R 15:5]\tMay God, who gives this patience and encouragement, help you live in complete harmony with each other, as is fitting for followers of Christ Jesus.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "According to Romans 12:14 and James 1:25, God will bless whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 12:14]\tBless those who persecute you. Don't curse them; pray that God will bless them.\n\t[J 1:25]\tBut if you look carefully into the perfect law that sets you free, and if you do what it says and don't forget what you heard, then God will bless you for doing it.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 20 points. 2-Part question. From separate verses. \nAccording to Romans 12:14 and James 1:25, God will bless whom?\n\t[R 12:14]\tBless those who persecute you. Don't curse them; pray that God will bless them.\n\t[J 1:25]\tBut if you look carefully into the perfect law that sets you free, and if you do what it says and don't forget what you heard, then God will bless you for doing it.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            12
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who takes revenge?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 12:19]\tDear friends, never take revenge. Leave that to the righteous anger of God. For the Scriptures say, \"I will take revenge; I will pay them back,\" says the LORD.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 10 points. From Romans chapter 12. \nWho takes revenge?\n\t[R 12:19]\tDear friends, never take revenge. Leave that to the righteous anger of God. For the Scriptures say, \"I will take revenge; I will pay them back,\" says the LORD.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            16
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How do verses 1 and 2 describe Phoebe?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:1]\tI commend to you our sister Phoebe, who is a deacon in the church in Cenchrea.\n\t[R 16:2]\tWelcome her in the Lord as one who is worthy of honor among God's people. Help her in whatever she needs, for she has been helpful to many, and especially to me.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 16. \nHow do verses 1 and 2 describe Phoebe?\n\t[R 16:1]\tI commend to you our sister Phoebe, who is a deacon in the church in Cenchrea.\n\t[R 16:2]\tWelcome her in the Lord as one who is worthy of honor among God's people. Help her in whatever she needs, for she has been helpful to many, and especially to me.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "life in the spirit"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Put to death what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:13]\tFor if you live by its dictates, you will die. But if through the power of the Spirit you put to death the deeds of your sinful nature, you will live.\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Life in the Spirit\". \nPut to death what?\n\t[R 8:13]\tFor if you live by its dictates, you will die. But if through the power of the Spirit you put to death the deeds of your sinful nature, you will live.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "QuotationCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            1
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish this verse and the two that follow, quote, \"Temptation comes from... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 1:14]\tTemptation comes from our own desires, which entice us and drag us away.\n\t[J 1:15]\tThese desires give birth to sinful actions. And when sin is allowed to grow, it gives birth to death.\n\t[J 1:16]\tSo don't be misled, my dear brothers and sisters.\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. Quotation completion question. From James chapter 1. \nFinish this verse and the two that follow, quote, \"Temptation comes from... \"\n\t[J 1:14]\tTemptation comes from our own desires, which entice us and drag us away.\n\t[J 1:15]\tThese desires give birth to sinful actions. And when sin is allowed to grow, it gives birth to death.\n\t[J 1:16]\tSo don't be misled, my dear brothers and sisters.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            15
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How do verses 7, 8, and 9 describe Christ?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:7]\tTherefore, accept each other just as Christ has accepted you so that God will be given glory.\n\t[R 15:8]\tRemember that Christ came as a servant to the Jews to show that God is true to the promises he made to their ancestors.\n\t[R 15:9]\tHe also came so that the Gentiles might give glory to God for his mercies to them. That is what the psalmist meant when he wrote: \"For this, I will praise you among the Gentiles; I will sing praises to your name.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. 3-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 3 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 15. \nHow do verses 7, 8, and 9 describe Christ?\n\t[R 15:7]\tTherefore, accept each other just as Christ has accepted you so that God will be given glory.\n\t[R 15:8]\tRemember that Christ came as a servant to the Jews to show that God is true to the promises he made to their ancestors.\n\t[R 15:9]\tHe also came so that the Gentiles might give glory to God for his mercies to them. That is what the psalmist meant when he wrote: \"For this, I will praise you among the Gentiles; I will sing praises to your name.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "QuotationCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish this Old Testament Scripture, quote, \"\"Oh, what joy... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:7]\t\"Oh, what joy for those whose disobedience is forgiven, whose sins are put out of sight.\n\t[R 4:8]\tYes, what joy for those whose record the LORD has cleared of sin.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 20 points. Quotation completion question. From Romans chapter 4. \nFinish this Old Testament Scripture, quote, \"\"Oh, what joy... \"\n\t[R 4:7]\t\"Oh, what joy for those whose disobedience is forgiven, whose sins are put out of sight.\n\t[R 4:8]\tYes, what joy for those whose record the LORD has cleared of sin.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            6
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How did Paul answer his question, quote, \" And what was the result?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 6:21]\tAnd what was the result? You are now ashamed of the things you used to do, things that end in eternal doom.\n\t[R 6:22]\tBut now you are free from the power of sin and have become slaves of God. Now you do those things that lead to holiness and result in eternal life.\n\t[R 6:23]\tFor the wages of sin is death, but the free gift of God is eternal life through Christ Jesus our Lord.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 30 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From 3 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 6. \nHow did Paul answer his question, quote, \" And what was the result?\"\n\t[R 6:21]\tAnd what was the result? You are now ashamed of the things you used to do, things that end in eternal doom.\n\t[R 6:22]\tBut now you are free from the power of sin and have become slaves of God. Now you do those things that lead to holiness and result in eternal life.\n\t[R 6:23]\tFor the wages of sin is death, but the free gift of God is eternal life through Christ Jesus our Lord.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's law reveals our sin"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What brought spiritual death?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 7:10]\tand I died. So I discovered that the law's commands, which were supposed to bring life, brought spiritual death instead.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"God's Law Reveals Our Sin\". \nWhat brought spiritual death?\n\t[R 7:10]\tand I died. So I discovered that the law's commands, which were supposed to bring life, brought spiritual death instead.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The law applies to whom and why?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:19]\tObviously, the law applies to those to whom it was given, for its purpose is to keep people from having excuses, and to show that the entire world is guilty before God.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give 3 complete answers. From Romans chapter 3. \nThe law applies to whom and why?\n\t[R 3:19]\tObviously, the law applies to those to whom it was given, for its purpose is to keep people from having excuses, and to show that the entire world is guilty before God.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "struggling with sin"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Paul inevitably did what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 7:21]\tI have discovered this principle of life- that when I want to do what is right, I inevitably do what is wrong.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Struggling with Sin\". \nPaul inevitably did what?\n\t[R 7:21]\tI have discovered this principle of life- that when I want to do what is right, I inevitably do what is wrong.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Prove what by what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 3:13]\tIf you are wise and understand God's ways, prove it by living an honorable life, doing good works with the humility that comes from wisdom.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From James chapter 3. \nProve what by what?\n\t[J 3:13]\tIf you are wise and understand God's ways, prove it by living an honorable life, doing good works with the humility that comes from wisdom.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's anger at sin"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who did shameful things with whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:27]\tAnd the men, instead of having normal sexual relations with women, burned with lust for each other. Men did shameful things with other men, and as a result of this sin, they suffered within themselves the penalty they deserved.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 10 points. 2-Part question. From the section titled, \"God's Anger at Sin\". \nWho did shameful things with whom?\n\t[R 1:27]\tAnd the men, instead of having normal sexual relations with women, burned with lust for each other. Men did shameful things with other men, and as a result of this sin, they suffered within themselves the penalty they deserved.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            7
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How do verses 18, 19, and 20 describe Paul?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 7:18]\tAnd I know that nothing good lives in me, that is, in my sinful nature. I want to do what is right, but I can't.\n\t[R 7:19]\tI want to do what is good, but I don't. I don't want to do what is wrong, but I do it anyway.\n\t[R 7:20]\tBut if I do what I don't want to do, I am not really the one doing wrong; it is sin living in me that does it.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 30 points. 3-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 3 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 7. \nHow do verses 18, 19, and 20 describe Paul?\n\t[R 7:18]\tAnd I know that nothing good lives in me, that is, in my sinful nature. I want to do what is right, but I can't.\n\t[R 7:19]\tI want to do what is good, but I don't. I don't want to do what is wrong, but I do it anyway.\n\t[R 7:20]\tBut if I do what I don't want to do, I am not really the one doing wrong; it is sin living in me that does it.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "The unique word royal is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:8]\tYes indeed, it is good when you obey the royal law as found in the Scriptures: \"Love your neighbor as yourself.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 20 points. Statement and 2-Part essence question. \nThe unique word royal is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n\t[J 2:8]\tYes indeed, it is good when you obey the royal law as found in the Scriptures: \"Love your neighbor as yourself.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "God raised whom from what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:24]\tfor our benefit, too, assuring us that God will also count us as righteous if we believe in him, the one who raised Jesus our Lord from the dead.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 10 points. 2-Part question. From Romans chapter 4. \nGod raised whom from what?\n\t[R 4:24]\tfor our benefit, too, assuring us that God will also count us as righteous if we believe in him, the one who raised Jesus our Lord from the dead.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give the complete references for the verses in which Paul is named.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:1]\tRomans 1:1\n\t[R 16:22]\tRomans 16:22\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. 2-Part answer. \nGive the complete references for the verses in which Paul is named.\n\t[R 1:1]\tRomans 1:1\n\t[R 16:22]\tRomans 16:22\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "the future glory"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "In advance, who did God know?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:29]\tFor God knew his people in advance, and he chose them to become like his Son, so that his Son would be the firstborn among many brothers and sisters.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"The Future Glory\". \nIn advance, who did God know?\n\t[R 8:29]\tFor God knew his people in advance, and he chose them to become like his Son, so that his Son would be the firstborn among many brothers and sisters.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "QuotationCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish this two-verse section, quote, \"My dear brothers and sisters... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:19]\tMy dear brothers and sisters, if someone among you wanders away from the truth and is brought back,\n\t[J 5:20]\tyou can be sure that whoever brings the sinner back from wandering will save that person from death and bring about the forgiveness of many sins.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 30 points. Quotation completion question. From James chapter 5. \nFinish this two-verse section, quote, \"My dear brothers and sisters... \"\n\t[J 5:19]\tMy dear brothers and sisters, if someone among you wanders away from the truth and is brought back,\n\t[J 5:20]\tyou can be sure that whoever brings the sinner back from wandering will save that person from death and bring about the forgiveness of many sins.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Circumcision was a sign of what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:11]\tCircumcision was a sign that Abraham already had faith and that God had already accepted him and declared him to be righteous- even before he was circumcised. So Abraham is the spiritual father of those who have faith but have not been circumcised. They are counted as righteous because of their faith.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 20 points. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 4. \nCircumcision was a sign of what?\n\t[R 4:11]\tCircumcision was a sign that Abraham already had faith and that God had already accepted him and declared him to be righteous- even before he was circumcised. So Abraham is the spiritual father of those who have faith but have not been circumcised. They are counted as righteous because of their faith.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "QuotationCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            1
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish this verse, quote, \"Claiming to be wise... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:22]\tClaiming to be wise, they instead became utter fools.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 10 points. Quotation completion question. From Romans chapter 1. \nFinish this verse, quote, \"Claiming to be wise... \"\n\t[R 1:22]\tClaiming to be wise, they instead became utter fools.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            12
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Instead of copying the customs of this world, what should you do and why?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 12:2]\tDon't copy the behavior and customs of this world, but let God transform you into a new person by changing the way you think. Then you will learn to know God's will for you, which is good and pleasing and perfect.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From Romans chapter 12. \nInstead of copying the customs of this world, what should you do and why?\n\t[R 12:2]\tDon't copy the behavior and customs of this world, but let God transform you into a new person by changing the way you think. Then you will learn to know God's will for you, which is good and pleasing and perfect.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "sin's power is broken"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "We were joined with Christ Jesus in what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 6:3]\tOr have you forgotten that when we were joined with Christ Jesus in baptism, we joined him in his death?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 10 points. 2-Part answer. From the section titled, \"Sin's Power Is Broken\". \nWe were joined with Christ Jesus in what?\n\t[R 6:3]\tOr have you forgotten that when we were joined with Christ Jesus in baptism, we joined him in his death?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 11
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's anger at sin"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Sinful people are what and do what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:30]\tThey are backstabbers, haters of God, insolent, proud, and boastful. They invent new ways of sinning, and they disobey their parents.\n\t[R 1:31]\tThey refuse to understand, break their promises, are heartless, and have no mercy.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 20 points. 2-Part question. 11-Part answer. From consecutive verses of the section titled, \"God's Anger at Sin\". \nSinful people are what and do what?\n\t[R 1:30]\tThey are backstabbers, haters of God, insolent, proud, and boastful. They invent new ways of sinning, and they disobey their parents.\n\t[R 1:31]\tThey refuse to understand, break their promises, are heartless, and have no mercy.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who are uncircumcised?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 2:25]\tGentile\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 10 points. From Romans chapter 2. \nWho are uncircumcised?\n\t[R 2:25]\tGentile\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            6
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of God...?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 6:13]\tglory\n\t[R 6:22]\tslaves\n\t[R 6:23]\tfree gift\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 20 points. Scripture text question. 3-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 6. \nHow does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of God...?\"\n\t[R 6:13]\tglory\n\t[R 6:22]\tslaves\n\t[R 6:23]\tfree gift\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's mercy is for everyone"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Everything exists by what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:36]\tFor everything comes from him and exists by his power and is intended for his glory. All glory to him forever! Amen.\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"God's Mercy Is for Everyone\". \nEverything exists by what?\n\t[R 11:36]\tFor everything comes from him and exists by his power and is intended for his glory. All glory to him forever! Amen.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            6
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "According to the 11th verse, consider yourselves to be what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 6:11]\tSo you also should consider yourselves to be dead to the power of sin and alive to God through Christ Jesus.\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. Give 2 complete answers. From Romans chapter 6. \nAccording to the 11th verse, consider yourselves to be what?\n\t[R 6:11]\tSo you also should consider yourselves to be dead to the power of sin and alive to God through Christ Jesus.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence verses 26 and 27 from the opening chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:26]\tThat is why God abandoned them to their shameful desires. Even the women turned against the natural way to have sex and instead indulged in sex with each other.\n\t[R 1:27]\tAnd the men, instead of having normal sexual relations with women, burned with lust for each other. Men did shameful things with other men, and as a result of this sin, they suffered within themselves the penalty they deserved.\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. Essence question. From 2 consecutive verses of Romans. \nGive in essence verses 26 and 27 from the opening chapter.\n\t[R 1:26]\tThat is why God abandoned them to their shameful desires. Even the women turned against the natural way to have sex and instead indulged in sex with each other.\n\t[R 1:27]\tAnd the men, instead of having normal sexual relations with women, burned with lust for each other. Men did shameful things with other men, and as a result of this sin, they suffered within themselves the penalty they deserved.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            14
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote the 7th verse.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 14:7]\tFor we don't live for ourselves or die for ourselves.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 10 points. Quotation question. From Romans chapter 14. \nQuote the 7th verse.\n\t[R 14:7]\tFor we don't live for ourselves or die for ourselves.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            15
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of Christ?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:5]\tfollowers\n\t[R 15:19]\tGood News\n\t[R 15:20]\tname\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 20 points. Scripture text question. 3-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 15. \nHow does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of Christ?\"\n\t[R 15:5]\tfollowers\n\t[R 15:19]\tGood News\n\t[R 15:20]\tname\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence the verses in which rain is mentioned.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 5:7]\tDear brothers and sisters, be patient as you wait for the Lord's return. Consider the farmers who patiently wait for the rains in the fall and in the spring. They eagerly look for the valuable harvest to ripen.\n\t[J 5:17]\tElijah was as human as we are, and yet when he prayed earnestly that no rain would fall, none fell for three and a half years!\n\t[J 5:18]\tThen, when he prayed again, the sky sent down rain and the earth began to yield its crops.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 30 points. Essence question. 3-Part Answer. From separate verses of James chapter 5. \nGive in essence the verses in which rain is mentioned.\n\t[J 5:7]\tDear brothers and sisters, be patient as you wait for the Lord's return. Consider the farmers who patiently wait for the rains in the fall and in the spring. They eagerly look for the valuable harvest to ripen.\n\t[J 5:17]\tElijah was as human as we are, and yet when he prayed earnestly that no rain would fall, none fell for three and a half years!\n\t[J 5:18]\tThen, when he prayed again, the sky sent down rain and the earth began to yield its crops.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "The unique word familiar is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 7:1]\tNow, dear brothers and sisters- you who are familiar with the law- don't you know that the law applies only while a person is living?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 20 points. Statement and 2-Part essence question. \nThe unique word familiar is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n\t[R 7:1]\tNow, dear brothers and sisters- you who are familiar with the law- don't you know that the law applies only while a person is living?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's anger at sin"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The Creator is worthy of what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:25]\tThey traded the truth about God for a lie. So they worshiped and served the things God created instead of the Creator himself, who is worthy of eternal praise! Amen.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"God's Anger at Sin\". \nThe Creator is worthy of what?\n\t[R 1:25]\tThey traded the truth about God for a lie. So they worshiped and served the things God created instead of the Creator himself, who is worthy of eternal praise! Amen.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            4
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How do verses 21, 22, and 23 describe Abraham?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:21]\tHe was fully convinced that God is able to do whatever he promises.\n\t[R 4:22]\tAnd because of Abraham's faith, God counted him as righteous.\n\t[R 4:23]\tAnd when God counted him as righteous, it wasn't just for Abraham's benefit. It was recorded\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 30 points. 3-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 3 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 4. \nHow do verses 21, 22, and 23 describe Abraham?\n\t[R 4:21]\tHe was fully convinced that God is able to do whatever he promises.\n\t[R 4:22]\tAnd because of Abraham's faith, God counted him as righteous.\n\t[R 4:23]\tAnd when God counted him as righteous, it wasn't just for Abraham's benefit. It was recorded\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part",
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "greetings from paul"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote the verse in which Paul is named and the verse in which David is named.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:1]\tThis letter is from Paul, a slave of Christ Jesus, chosen by God to be an apostle and sent out to preach his Good News.\n\t[R 1:3]\tThe Good News is about his Son. In his earthly life he was born into King David's family line,\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 20 points. 2-Part quotation question. From separate verses of the section titled, \"Greetings from Paul\". \nQuote the verse in which Paul is named and the verse in which David is named.\n\t[R 1:1]\tThis letter is from Paul, a slave of Christ Jesus, chosen by God to be an apostle and sent out to preach his Good News.\n\t[R 1:3]\tThe Good News is about his Son. In his earthly life he was born into King David's family line,\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "nothing can separate us from god's love"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Overwhelming victory is ours through whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:37]\tNo, despite all these things, overwhelming victory is ours through Christ, who loved us.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Nothing Can Separate Us from God's Love\". \nOverwhelming victory is ours through whom?\n\t[R 8:37]\tNo, despite all these things, overwhelming victory is ours through Christ, who loved us.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "israel's unbelief"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "The Israelites cling to what, how?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 10:3]\tFor they don't understand God's way of making people right with himself. Refusing to accept God's way, they cling to their own way of getting right with God by trying to keep the law.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Israel's Unbelief\". \nThe Israelites cling to what, how?\n\t[R 10:3]\tFor they don't understand God's way of making people right with himself. Refusing to accept God's way, they cling to their own way of getting right with God by trying to keep the law.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's mercy is for everyone"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Some of the people of Israel have what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:25]\tI want you to understand this mystery, dear brothers and sisters, so that you will not feel proud about yourselves. Some of the people of Israel have hard hearts, but this will last only until the full number of Gentiles comes to Christ.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"God's Mercy Is for Everyone\". \nSome of the people of Israel have what?\n\t[R 11:25]\tI want you to understand this mystery, dear brothers and sisters, so that you will not feel proud about yourselves. Some of the people of Israel have hard hearts, but this will last only until the full number of Gentiles comes to Christ.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote verses 8 and 9 from the 5th chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 5:8]\tBut God showed his great love for us by sending Christ to die for us while we were still sinners.\n\t[R 5:9]\tAnd since we have been made right in God's sight by the blood of Christ, he will certainly save us from God's condemnation.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. Quotation question. From 2 consecutive verses of Romans. \nQuote verses 8 and 9 from the 5th chapter.\n\t[R 5:8]\tBut God showed his great love for us by sending Christ to die for us while we were still sinners.\n\t[R 5:9]\tAnd since we have been made right in God's sight by the blood of Christ, he will certainly save us from God's condemnation.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            1
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "About temptation, what did James say?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 1:12]\tGod blesses those who patiently endure testing and temptation. Afterward they will receive the crown of life that God has promised to those who love him.\n\t[J 1:13]\tAnd remember, when you are being tempted, do not say, \"God is tempting me.\" God is never tempted to do wrong, and he never tempts anyone else.\n\t[J 1:14]\tTemptation comes from our own desires, which entice us and drag us away.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 30 points. Give a complete answer. From 3 consecutive verses of James chapter 1. \nAbout temptation, what did James say?\n\t[J 1:12]\tGod blesses those who patiently endure testing and temptation. Afterward they will receive the crown of life that God has promised to those who love him.\n\t[J 1:13]\tAnd remember, when you are being tempted, do not say, \"God is tempting me.\" God is never tempted to do wrong, and he never tempts anyone else.\n\t[J 1:14]\tTemptation comes from our own desires, which entice us and drag us away.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "struggling with sin"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What did Paul want to obey, quote, \"in my mind?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 7:25]\tThank God! The answer is in Jesus Christ our Lord. So you see how it is: In my mind I really want to obey God's law, but because of my sinful nature I am a slave to sin.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Struggling with Sin\". \nWhat did Paul want to obey, quote, \"in my mind?\"\n\t[R 7:25]\tThank God! The answer is in Jesus Christ our Lord. So you see how it is: In my mind I really want to obey God's law, but because of my sinful nature I am a slave to sin.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "Romans chapter 6 contains which exclamations?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 6:2]\tOf course not!\n\t[R 6:15]\tOf course not!\n\t[R 6:17]\tThank God!\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 20 points. 3-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses. \nRomans chapter 6 contains which exclamations?\n\t[R 6:2]\tOf course not!\n\t[R 6:15]\tOf course not!\n\t[R 6:17]\tThank God!\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How does Paul complete the two-word phrase, quote, \"friends of...?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 5:11]\tGod\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 10 points. Scripture text question. From Romans chapter 5. \nHow does Paul complete the two-word phrase, quote, \"friends of...?\"\n\t[R 5:11]\tGod\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence verses 11, 12, and 13 from the 2nd chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 2:11]\tFor God does not show favoritism.\n\t[R 2:12]\tWhen the Gentiles sin, they will be destroyed, even though they never had God's written law. And the Jews, who do have God's law, will be judged by that law when they fail to obey it.\n\t[R 2:13]\tFor merely listening to the law doesn't make us right with God. It is obeying the law that makes us right in his sight.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 20 points. Essence question. From 3 consecutive verses of Romans. \nGive in essence verses 11, 12, and 13 from the 2nd chapter.\n\t[R 2:11]\tFor God does not show favoritism.\n\t[R 2:12]\tWhen the Gentiles sin, they will be destroyed, even though they never had God's written law. And the Jews, who do have God's law, will be judged by that law when they fail to obey it.\n\t[R 2:13]\tFor merely listening to the law doesn't make us right with God. It is obeying the law that makes us right in his sight.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "israel's unbelief"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who will never be disgraced?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:33]\tGod warned them of this in the Scriptures when he said, \"I am placing a stone in Jerusalem that makes people stumble, a rock that makes them fall. But anyone who trusts in him will never be disgraced.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Israel's Unbelief\". \nWho will never be disgraced?\n\t[R 9:33]\tGod warned them of this in the Scriptures when he said, \"I am placing a stone in Jerusalem that makes people stumble, a rock that makes them fall. But anyone who trusts in him will never be disgraced.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote the closing two verses.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:26]\tBut now as the prophets foretold and as the eternal God has commanded, this message is made known to all Gentiles everywhere, so that they too might believe and obey him.\n\t[R 16:27]\tAll glory to the only wise God, through Jesus Christ, forever. Amen.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 20 points. Quotation question. From 2 consecutive verses of Romans. \nQuote the closing two verses.\n\t[R 16:26]\tBut now as the prophets foretold and as the eternal God has commanded, this message is made known to all Gentiles everywhere, so that they too might believe and obey him.\n\t[R 16:27]\tAll glory to the only wise God, through Jesus Christ, forever. Amen.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            3
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How does Paul complete the two-word phrase, quote, \"writings of...?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:21]\tMoses\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Chapter analysis answer. From Romans chapter 3. \nHow does Paul complete the two-word phrase, quote, \"writings of...?\"\n\t[R 3:21]\tMoses\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            11
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "One verse is comprised entirely of exclamations. Quote this verse.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 11:33]\tOh, how great are God's riches and wisdom and knowledge! How impossible it is for us to understand his decisions and his ways!\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 20 points. Statement and quotation question. From Romans chapter 11. \nOne verse is comprised entirely of exclamations. Quote this verse.\n\t[R 11:33]\tOh, how great are God's riches and wisdom and knowledge! How impossible it is for us to understand his decisions and his ways!\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "greetings from paul"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How does Paul complete the two-word phrase, quote, \"son of...?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:4]\tGod\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. Scripture text question. From the section titled, \"Greetings from Paul\". \nHow does Paul complete the two-word phrase, quote, \"son of...?\"\n\t[R 1:4]\tGod\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence verses 22, 23, and 24 from the 1st chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 1:22]\tBut don't just listen to God's word. You must do what it says. Otherwise, you are only fooling yourselves.\n\t[J 1:23]\tFor if you listen to the word and don't obey, it is like glancing at your face in a mirror.\n\t[J 1:24]\tYou see yourself, walk away, and forget what you look like.\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. Essence question. From 3 consecutive verses of James. \nGive in essence verses 22, 23, and 24 from the 1st chapter.\n\t[J 1:22]\tBut don't just listen to God's word. You must do what it says. Otherwise, you are only fooling yourselves.\n\t[J 1:23]\tFor if you listen to the word and don't obey, it is like glancing at your face in a mirror.\n\t[J 1:24]\tYou see yourself, walk away, and forget what you look like.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Quote verses 4 and 5 from the 3rd chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:4]\tOf course not! Even if everyone else is a liar, God is true. As the Scriptures say about him, \"You will be proved right in what you say, and you will win your case in court.\"\n\t[R 3:5]\t\"But,\" some might say, \"our sinfulness serves a good purpose, for it helps people see how righteous God is. Isn't it unfair, then, for him to punish us?\" (This is merely a human point of view.)\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. Quotation question. From 2 consecutive verses of Romans. \nQuote verses 4 and 5 from the 3rd chapter.\n\t[R 3:4]\tOf course not! Even if everyone else is a liar, God is true. As the Scriptures say about him, \"You will be proved right in what you say, and you will win your case in court.\"\n\t[R 3:5]\t\"But,\" some might say, \"our sinfulness serves a good purpose, for it helps people see how righteous God is. Isn't it unfair, then, for him to punish us?\" (This is merely a human point of view.)\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "no longer bound to the law"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What example did Paul give?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 7:2]\tFor example, when a woman marries, the law binds her to her husband as long as he is alive. But if he dies, the laws of marriage no longer apply to her.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 1 for 20 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"No Longer Bound to the Law\". \nWhat example did Paul give?\n\t[R 7:2]\tFor example, when a woman marries, the law binds her to her husband as long as he is alive. But if he dies, the laws of marriage no longer apply to her.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "faith and endurance"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What are patiently endured?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 1:12]\tGod blesses those who patiently endure testing and temptation. Afterward they will receive the crown of life that God has promised to those who love him.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 2 for 10 points. 2-Part answer. From the section titled, \"Faith and Endurance\". \nWhat are patiently endured?\n\t[J 1:12]\tGod blesses those who patiently endure testing and temptation. Afterward they will receive the crown of life that God has promised to those who love him.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "QuotationCompletion"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Finish this verse and the one that follows, quote, \"No wonder the Scriptures... \"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 2:24]\tNo wonder the Scriptures say, \"The Gentiles blaspheme the name of God because of you.\"\n\t[R 2:25]\tThe Jewish ceremony of circumcision has value only if you obey God's law. But if you don't obey God's law, you are no better off than an uncircumcised Gentile.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 3 for 20 points. Quotation completion question. From Romans chapter 2. \nFinish this verse and the one that follows, quote, \"No wonder the Scriptures... \"\n\t[R 2:24]\tNo wonder the Scriptures say, \"The Gentiles blaspheme the name of God because of you.\"\n\t[R 2:25]\tThe Jewish ceremony of circumcision has value only if you obey God's law. But if you don't obey God's law, you are no better off than an uncircumcised Gentile.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's anger at sin"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "People began to think up what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:21]\tYes, they knew God, but they wouldn't worship him as God or even give him thanks. And they began to think up foolish ideas of what God was like. As a result, their minds became dark and confused.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 4 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"God's Anger at Sin\". \nPeople began to think up what?\n\t[R 1:21]\tYes, they knew God, but they wouldn't worship him as God or even give him thanks. And they began to think up foolish ideas of what God was like. As a result, their minds became dark and confused.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's anger at sin"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence the verses in which worship is mentioned.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:21]\tYes, they knew God, but they wouldn't worship him as God or even give him thanks. And they began to think up foolish ideas of what God was like. As a result, their minds became dark and confused.\n\t[R 1:23]\tAnd instead of worshiping the glorious, ever-living God, they worshiped idols made to look like mere people and birds and animals and reptiles.\n\t[R 1:25]\tThey traded the truth about God for a lie. So they worshiped and served the things God created instead of the Creator himself, who is worthy of eternal praise! Amen.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 5 for 30 points. Essence question. 3-Part answer. From separate verses of the section titled, \"God's Anger at Sin\". \nGive in essence the verses in which worship is mentioned.\n\t[R 1:21]\tYes, they knew God, but they wouldn't worship him as God or even give him thanks. And they began to think up foolish ideas of what God was like. As a result, their minds became dark and confused.\n\t[R 1:23]\tAnd instead of worshiping the glorious, ever-living God, they worshiped idols made to look like mere people and birds and animals and reptiles.\n\t[R 1:25]\tThey traded the truth about God for a lie. So they worshiped and served the things God created instead of the Creator himself, who is worthy of eternal praise! Amen.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Quotation"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            2,
            8
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Calamity is mentioned in two verses. Quote these verses.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 2:9]\tThere will be trouble and calamity for everyone who keeps on doing what is evil- for the Jew first and also for the Gentile.\n\t[R 8:35]\tCan anything ever separate us from Christ's love? Does it mean he no longer loves us if we have trouble or calamity, or are persecuted, or hungry, or destitute, or in danger, or threatened with death?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 6 for 20 points. Statement and quotation question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapters 2 and 8. \nCalamity is mentioned in two verses. Quote these verses.\n\t[R 2:9]\tThere will be trouble and calamity for everyone who keeps on doing what is evil- for the Jew first and also for the Gentile.\n\t[R 8:35]\tCan anything ever separate us from Christ's love? Does it mean he no longer loves us if we have trouble or calamity, or are persecuted, or hungry, or destitute, or in danger, or threatened with death?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "the faith of abraham"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "What faith counts people, quote, as righteous?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 4:5]\tBut people are counted as righteous, not because of their work, but because of their faith in God who forgives sinners.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 7 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"The Faith of Abraham\". \nWhat faith counts people, quote, as righteous?\"\n\t[R 4:5]\tBut people are counted as righteous, not because of their work, but because of their faith in God who forgives sinners.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence verses 29, 30, and 31 from the opening chapter.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 1:29]\tTheir lives became full of every kind of wickedness, sin, greed, hate, envy, murder, quarreling, deception, malicious behavior, and gossip.\n\t[R 1:30]\tThey are backstabbers, haters of God, insolent, proud, and boastful. They invent new ways of sinning, and they disobey their parents.\n\t[R 1:31]\tThey refuse to understand, break their promises, are heartless, and have no mercy.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 8 for 20 points. Essence question. From 3 consecutive verses of Romans. \nGive in essence verses 29, 30, and 31 from the opening chapter.\n\t[R 1:29]\tTheir lives became full of every kind of wickedness, sin, greed, hate, envy, murder, quarreling, deception, malicious behavior, and gossip.\n\t[R 1:30]\tThey are backstabbers, haters of God, insolent, proud, and boastful. They invent new ways of sinning, and they disobey their parents.\n\t[R 1:31]\tThey refuse to understand, break their promises, are heartless, and have no mercy.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "nothing can separate us from god's love"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Christ is sitting where?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 8:34]\tWho then will condemn us? No one- for Christ Jesus died for us and was raised to life for us, and he is sitting in the place of honor at God's right hand, pleading for us.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 9 for 10 points. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Nothing Can Separate Us from God's Love\". \nChrist is sitting where?\n\t[R 8:34]\tWho then will condemn us? No one- for Christ Jesus died for us and was raised to life for us, and he is sitting in the place of honor at God's right hand, pleading for us.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 5
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        },
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Five chapters refer to either Heaven or the heavens. Identify these chapters.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t\tRomans 1, 9 and 10\n\t\tJames 1 and 5\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 10 for 30 points. Statement and 2-Part question. 5-Part answer. From Romans and James. \nFive chapters refer to either Heaven or the heavens. Identify these chapters.\n\t\tRomans 1, 9 and 10\n\t\tJames 1 and 5\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part",
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            16
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Paul named which geographical locations?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:1]\tCenchrea\n\t[R 16:5]\tAsia\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 11 for 20 points. 2-Part chapter analysis answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 16. \nPaul named which geographical locations?\n\t[R 16:1]\tCenchrea\n\t[R 16:5]\tAsia\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "salvation is for everyone"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Don't say what, quote, \"in your heart?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 10:6]\t'Who will go up to heaven?'\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 12 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Chapter analysis answer. From the section titled, \"Salvation Is for Everyone\". \nDon't say what, quote, \"in your heart?\"\n\t[R 10:6]\t'Who will go up to heaven?'\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence the verses in which Jacob is named.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:5]\tAbraham, Isaac, and Jacob are their ancestors, and Christ himself was an Israelite as far as his human nature is concerned. And he is God, the one who rules over everything and is worthy of eternal praise! Amen.\n\t[R 9:13]\tIn the words of the Scriptures, \"I loved Jacob, but I rejected Esau.\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 13 for 20 points. Essence question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 9. \nGive in essence the verses in which Jacob is named.\n\t[R 9:5]\tAbraham, Isaac, and Jacob are their ancestors, and Christ himself was an Israelite as far as his human nature is concerned. And he is God, the one who rules over everything and is worthy of eternal praise! Amen.\n\t[R 9:13]\tIn the words of the Scriptures, \"I loved Jacob, but I rejected Esau.\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "faith brings joy"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Through what will we, quote, \"certainly be saved?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 5:10]\tFor since our friendship with God was restored by the death of his Son while we were still his enemies, we will certainly be saved through the life of his Son.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 14 for 10 points. Scripture text question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Faith Brings Joy\". \nThrough what will we, quote, \"certainly be saved?\"\n\t[R 5:10]\tFor since our friendship with God was restored by the death of his Son while we were still his enemies, we will certainly be saved through the life of his Son.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 3
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "james",
          "Chapters": [
            2
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "According to three separate verses, suppose what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 2:2]\tFor example, suppose someone comes into your meeting dressed in fancy clothes and expensive jewelry, and another comes in who is poor and dressed in dirty clothes.\n\t[J 2:15]\tSuppose you see a brother or sister who has no food or clothing,\n\t[J 2:16]\tand you say, \"Good-bye and have a good day; stay warm and eat well\"- but then you don't give that person any food or clothing. What good does that do?\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 15 for 30 points. Give a complete answer. From 3 separate verses of James chapter 2. \nAccording to three separate verses, suppose what?\n\t[J 2:2]\tFor example, suppose someone comes into your meeting dressed in fancy clothes and expensive jewelry, and another comes in who is poor and dressed in dirty clothes.\n\t[J 2:15]\tSuppose you see a brother or sister who has no food or clothing,\n\t[J 2:16]\tand you say, \"Good-bye and have a good day; stay warm and eat well\"- but then you don't give that person any food or clothing. What good does that do?\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "love fulfills god's requirements"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Instead, do what and don't do what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 13:14]\tInstead, clothe yourself with the presence of the Lord Jesus Christ. And don't let yourself think about ways to indulge your evil desires.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 16 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From the section titled, \"Love Fulfills God's Requirements\". \nInstead, do what and don't do what?\n\t[R 13:14]\tInstead, clothe yourself with the presence of the Lord Jesus Christ. And don't let yourself think about ways to indulge your evil desires.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            9
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Isaac married whom?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:10]\tRebekah\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 17 for 10 points. Chapter analysis answer. From Romans chapter 9. \nIsaac married whom?\n\t[R 9:10]\tRebekah\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "ScriptureText"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Separate"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            5
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "How does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of God...?\"\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 5:11]\tfriends\n\t[R 5:14]\tcommandment\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 18 for 20 points. Scripture text question. 2-Part answer. From separate verses of Romans chapter 5. \nHow does Paul begin the two-word phrase, quote, \"of God...?\"\n\t[R 5:11]\tfriends\n\t[R 5:14]\tcommandment\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": null,
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Analysis"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god remains faithful"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Slanderers claim that we say what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 3:8]\t\"The more we sin, the better it is!\"\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 19 for 10 points. Chapter analysis answer. From the section titled, \"God Remains Faithful\". \nSlanderers claim that we say what?\n\t[R 3:8]\t\"The more we sin, the better it is!\"\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Complete"
        ],
        "Parts": 1
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 2
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": "romans",
          "Chapters": [
            15
          ],
          "Section": null
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Why did Christ come to the Jews and why did Christ come to the Gentiles?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 15:8]\tRemember that Christ came as a servant to the Jews to show that God is true to the promises he made to their ancestors.\n\t[R 15:9]\tHe also came so that the Gentiles might give glory to God for his mercies to them.\n",
    "OriginalText": "Question number 20 for 20 points. 2-Part question. Give a complete answer. From 2 consecutive verses of Romans chapter 15. \nWhy did Christ come to the Jews and why did Christ come to the Gentiles?\n\t[R 15:8]\tRemember that Christ came as a servant to the Jews to show that God is true to the promises he made to their ancestors.\n\t[R 15:9]\tHe also came so that the Gentiles might give glory to God for his mercies to them.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 10
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "god's selection of israel"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Who rules over what?\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 9:5]\tAbraham, Isaac, and Jacob are their ancestors, and Christ himself was an Israelite as far as his human nature is concerned. And he is God, the one who rules over everything and is worthy of eternal praise! Amen.\n",
    "OriginalText": "10 points. 2-Part question. From the section titled, \"God's Selection of Israel\". \nWho rules over what?\n\t[R 9:5]\tAbraham, Isaac, and Jacob are their ancestors, and Christ himself was an Israelite as far as his human nature is concerned. And he is God, the one who rules over everything and is worthy of eternal praise! Amen.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 20
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Statement",
          "Part",
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 2
      },
      "AnswerRemark": null,
      "LocationRemark": null,
      "ScriptureRemark": null
    },
    "QuestionText": "The unique word hot is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[J 1:11]\tThe hot sun rises and the grass withers; the little flower droops and falls, and its beauty fades away. In the same way, the rich will fade away with all of their achievements.\n",
    "OriginalText": "20 points. Statement and 2-Part essence question. \nThe unique word hot is found in one verse. Give in essence this verse and its complete reference.\n\t[J 1:11]\tThe hot sun rises and the grass withers; the little flower droops and falls, and its beauty fades away. In the same way, the rich will fade away with all of their achievements.\n"
  },
  {
    "OpeningRemarks": {
      "PointsRemark": {
        "Points": 30
      },
      "QuestionRemark": {
        "QuestionType": [
          "Essence"
        ],
        "Parts": 0
      },
      "AnswerRemark": {
        "AnswerType": [
          "Part"
        ],
        "Parts": 3
      },
      "LocationRemark": {
        "LocationType": [
          "Consecutive"
        ],
        "VerseCount": 0
      },
      "ScriptureRemark": [
        {
          "Book": null,
          "Chapters": null,
          "Section": "paul's final instructions"
        }
      ]
    },
    "QuestionText": "Give in essence the opening three verses.\n",
    "AnswerText": "\t[R 16:17]\tAnd now I make one more appeal, my dear brothers and sisters. Watch out for people who cause divisions and upset people's faith by teaching things contrary to what you have been taught. Stay away from them.\n\t[R 16:18]\tSuch people are not serving Christ our Lord; they are serving their own personal interests. By smooth talk and glowing words they deceive innocent people.\n\t[R 16:19]\tBut everyone knows that you are obedient to the Lord. This makes me very happy. I want you to be wise in doing right and to stay innocent of any wrong.\n",
    "OriginalText": "30 points. Essence question. 3-Part answer. From consecutive verses of the section titled, \"Paul's Final Instructions\". \nGive in essence the opening three verses.\n\t[R 16:17]\tAnd now I make one more appeal, my dear brothers and sisters. Watch out for people who cause divisions and upset people's faith by teaching things contrary to what you have been taught. Stay away from them.\n\t[R 16:18]\tSuch people are not serving Christ our Lord; they are serving their own personal interests. By smooth talk and glowing words they deceive innocent people.\n\t[R 16:19]\tBut everyone knows that you are obedient to the Lord. This makes me very happy. I want you to be wise in doing right and to stay innocent of any wrong.\n"
  }
]